[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": " Trapezius upper Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c2::C3, C4::2}} ",
    "answer": "Spinal accessory | Context:  Muscle Test - Initial Position Patient sitting, and shrugs and retracts the shoulders. Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner forcefully depresses the shoulders. SCI pt's can Nod! ...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": " Trapezius upper Nerve: {{c1::Spinal accessory}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "C3, C4 | Context:  Muscle Test - Initial Position Patient sitting, and shrugs and retracts the shoulders. Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner forcefully depresses the shoulders. SCI pt's can Nod! ...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": " Rhomboid Major and minor Nerve: [BLANK] Root: {{c2::C5::1}} ",
    "answer": "Dorsal scapular | Context:  Muscle Test - Initial Position Patient prone, lifts hand away from buttocks. (off butt toward celing) Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner forces arm into an anterior direction. (humerus down toward...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": " Rhomboid Major and minor Nerve: {{c1::Dorsal scapular}} Root: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "C5 | Context:  Muscle Test - Initial Position Patient prone, lifts hand away from buttocks. (off butt toward celing) Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner forces arm into an anterior direction. (humerus down toward...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": " Serratus anterior Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c2::C5, C6, C7::3}} ",
    "answer": "Long thoracic",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 6
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": " Serratus anterior Nerve: {{c1::Long thoracic}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "C5, C6, C7",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 6
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": " Pectoralis major and minor Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c2:: C5 , C6 , C7, C8 , T1:: }} ",
    "answer": "Lateral pectoral;&nbsp;Medial pectoral | Context:  Muscle Test - Initial Position Patient sitting or supine, and flexes arm. Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner forces the flexed arm into horizontal abduction. (pull it backwards) Trunks: Upper, Mid...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 14
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": " Pectoralis major and minor Nerve: {{c1::Lateral pectoral; Medial pectoral::2}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"blue\"\">C5</font>,&nbsp;<u><font color=\"\"red\"\">C6</font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"red\"\">C7,&nbsp;</font><font color=\"\"red\"\">C8</font></u>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"blue\"\">T1 | Context:  Muscle Test - Initial Position Patient sitting or supine, and flexes arm. Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner forces the flexed arm into horizontal abduction. (pull it backwards) Trunks: Upper, Mid...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 14
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": " Latissimus dorsi Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c2:: C6 , C7 , C8::3 }} ",
    "answer": "Thoracodorsal | Context:  Muscle Test - Initial Position Patient extends arm Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner forces arm in an anterior direction. Trunks: Upper, Middle, & Lower Divisions: Posterior Cords: Posterior ...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 31
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": " Latissimus dorsi Nerve: {{c1::Thoracodorsal}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"blue\"\">C6</font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"red\"\"><u>C7</u></font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"blue\"\">C8 | Context:  Muscle Test - Initial Position Patient extends arm Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner forces arm in an anterior direction. Trunks: Upper, Middle, & Lower Divisions: Posterior Cords: Posterior ...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 31
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": " Supra-spinatus & infra-spinatus & teres minor Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c2:: C5 , C6::2 }} ",
    "answer": "Suprascapular, Suprascapular, Axillary | Context:  Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner forces arm into internal rotation by holding the elbow at the side with one hand and pushing in on the wrist with the other. Trunks: Upper ...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 32
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": " Supra-spinatus & infra-spinatus & teres minor Nerve: {{c1::Suprascapular, Suprascapular, Axillary::3}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"red\"\"><u>C5</u></font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"blue\"\">C6 | Context:  Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner forces arm into internal rotation by holding the elbow at the side with one hand and pushing in on the wrist with the other. Trunks: Upper ...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 32
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": " Deltoid Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c2:: C5 , C6::2 }} ",
    "answer": "Axillary | Context:  Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner pushes arm out of abduction with elbow flexed. Trunks: Upper Divisions: Posterior Cords: Posterior ...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 33
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": " Deltoid Nerve: {{c1::Axillary}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"red\"\"><u>C5</u></font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"blue\"\">C6 | Context:  Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner pushes arm out of abduction with elbow flexed. Trunks: Upper Divisions: Posterior Cords: Posterior ...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 33
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": " Biceps & Brachialis Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c2:: C5 , C6::2 }} ",
    "answer": "Musculocutaneous. \"\"70% have dual radial n. (brachialis)\"\" | Context:  Trunks: Upper Divisions: Anterior Cords: Lateral ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 34
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": " Biceps & Brachialis Nerve: {{c1::Musculocutaneous. \"\"70% have dual radial n. (brachialis)\"\"}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"red\"\"><u>C5</u></font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"blue\"\">C6 | Context:  Trunks: Upper Divisions: Anterior Cords: Lateral ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 34
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": " Brachioradialis Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c2:: C5 , C6 ::2 }} ",
    "answer": "Radial | Context:  Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner forces the forearm into extension. The examiner judges force of BR contraction by comparing the right to the left muscle bulk and tone. Trunks: Upper Divisions: ...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 35
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": " Brachioradialis Nerve: {{c1::Radial}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"blue\"\">C5</font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"red\"\"><u>C6</u> | Context:  Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner forces the forearm into extension. The examiner judges force of BR contraction by comparing the right to the left muscle bulk and tone. Trunks: Upper Divisions: ...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 35
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": " Extensor carpi radialis Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c2:: C6 , C7::2 }} ",
    "answer": "Radial | Context:  Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner forces wrist into flexion and ulnar deviation supporting forearm just above wrist Trunks: Upper and Middle Divisions: Posterior Cords: Posterior ...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 36
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": " Extensor carpi radialis Nerve: {{c1::Radial}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"red\"\"><u>C6</u></font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"blue\"\">C7 | Context:  Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner forces wrist into flexion and ulnar deviation supporting forearm just above wrist Trunks: Upper and Middle Divisions: Posterior Cords: Posterior ...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 36
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": " Triceps Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c2:: C6 , C7 , C8::3 }} ",
    "answer": "Radial | Context:  Trunks: Upper, middle, and lower Divisions: Posterior Cords: Posterior ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 37
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": " Triceps Nerve: {{c1::Radial}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"blue\"\">C6</font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"red\"\"><u>C7</u></font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"blue\"\">C8 | Context:  Trunks: Upper, middle, and lower Divisions: Posterior Cords: Posterior ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 37
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": " Pronator teres Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c2:: C6 , C7::2 }} ",
    "answer": "Median | Context:  Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner grasps distal forearm at wrist and forces forearm into supination. Trunks: Upper & Middle Divisions: Anterior Cords: Lateral ...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 38
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": " Pronator teres Nerve: {{c1::Median}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"red\"\"><u>C6</u></font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"blue\"\">C7 | Context:  Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner grasps distal forearm at wrist and forces forearm into supination. Trunks: Upper & Middle Divisions: Anterior Cords: Lateral ...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 38
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": " Flexor carpi radialis Nerve: [BLANK] Nerve Roots: {{c2:: C6 , C7 ::2 }} ",
    "answer": "Median | Context:  Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner forces wrist into extension and ulnar deviation supporting forearm just above wrist with one hand Trunks: Upper & Middle Divisions: Anterior Cords: Lateral ...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 39
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": " Flexor carpi radialis Nerve: {{c1::Median}} Nerve Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"blue\"\">C6</font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"red\"\"><u>C7</u> | Context:  Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner forces wrist into extension and ulnar deviation supporting forearm just above wrist with one hand Trunks: Upper & Middle Divisions: Anterior Cords: Lateral ...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 39
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "question": " Extensor digitorum longus / Indicis / digit minimi Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c2:: C7 , C8::2 }} ",
    "answer": "Radial (Posterior interosseous branch) | Context:  Muscle Test - Initial Position Patient extends proximal phalanx. Examiner forces proximal phalanx into flexion. Trunks: Middle & Lower Divisions: Posterior Cords: Posterior ...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 40
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "question": " Extensor digitorum longus / Indicis / digit minimi Nerve: {{c1::Radial (Posterior interosseous branch)}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"red\"\"><u>C7</u></font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"blue\"\">C8 | Context:  Muscle Test - Initial Position Patient extends proximal phalanx. Examiner forces proximal phalanx into flexion. Trunks: Middle & Lower Divisions: Posterior Cords: Posterior ...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 40
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "question": " Flexor digitorum profundus Nerve: Digits 2 & 3 [BLANK] Digits 4 & 5 [BLANK] Roots: {{c2:: C7 , C8 , T1::3 }} ",
    "answer": "Ant. interosseous branch of median / Ulnar | Context:  Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner holds proximal and middle phalanx with the index and long fingers and thumb of one hand and forces distal phalanx of the index finger into extension with the thu...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 41
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "question": " Flexor digitorum profundus Nerve: Digits 2 & 3 {{c1::Ant. interosseous branch of median}} Digits 4 & 5 {{c1::Ulnar}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"#0548ff\"\" style=\"\"\"\">C7</font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"red\"\" style=\"\"\"\">C8</font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"blue\"\">T1 | Context:  Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner holds proximal and middle phalanx with the index and long fingers and thumb of one hand and forces distal phalanx of the index finger into extension with the thu...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 41
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "question": " [BLANK] Nerve: {{c1::Median}} Roots: {{c2:: C7 , C8 , T1::3 }} ",
    "answer": "Flexor digitorum superficialis | Context:  Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner holds all the fingers, except for the finger being tested, in firm extension (at the MP, PIP and DIP joints). Pt unable to flex the DIP joint. Examiner forces th...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 42
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "question": " {{c3::Flexor digitorum superficialis}} Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c2:: C7 , C8 , T1::3 }} ",
    "answer": "Median | Context:  Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner holds all the fingers, except for the finger being tested, in firm extension (at the MP, PIP and DIP joints). Pt unable to flex the DIP joint. Examiner forces th...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 42
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "question": " {{c3::Flexor digitorum superficialis}} Nerve: {{c1::Median}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"blue\"\">C7</font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"red\"\"><u>C8</u></font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"blue\"\">T1 | Context:  Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner holds all the fingers, except for the finger being tested, in firm extension (at the MP, PIP and DIP joints). Pt unable to flex the DIP joint. Examiner forces th...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 42
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "question": " [BLANK] Nerve: {{c1::Ant. interosseous of median nerve.}} Roots: {{c2:: C8 , T1::2 }} ",
    "answer": "<b>Flexor pollicis longus</b> | Context:  Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner holds proximal phalanx with the index and thumb of one hand and forces distal phalanx of the thumb into extension with the other hand. Patient flexes 1st distal ...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 43
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "question": " {{c3:: Flexor pollicis longus }} Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c2:: C8 , T1::2 }} ",
    "answer": "Ant. interosseous of median nerve. | Context:  Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner holds proximal phalanx with the index and thumb of one hand and forces distal phalanx of the thumb into extension with the other hand. Patient flexes 1st distal ...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 43
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "question": " {{c3:: Flexor pollicis longus }} Nerve: {{c1::Ant. interosseous of median nerve.}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"red\"\"><u>C8</u></font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"blue\"\">T1 | Context:  Muscle Test - Final Position Examiner holds proximal phalanx with the index and thumb of one hand and forces distal phalanx of the thumb into extension with the other hand. Patient flexes 1st distal ...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 43
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "question": " Abductor pollicis brevis Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c1:: C8 , T1 ::2 }} ",
    "answer": "Median nerve | Context:  Trunks: Lower Divisions: Anterior Cords: Medial ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 44
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "question": " Abductor pollicis brevis Nerve: {{c2::Median nerve}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"blue\"\">C8</font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"red\"\"><u>T1</u> | Context:  Trunks: Lower Divisions: Anterior Cords: Medial ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 44
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "question": " Opponens pollicis Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c2:: C8 , T1 ::2 }} ",
    "answer": "Median nerve | Context:  Trunks: Lower Divisions: Anterior Cords: Medial ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 45
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "question": " Opponens pollicis Nerve: {{c1::Median nerve}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"blue\"\">C8</font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"red\"\"><u>T1</u> | Context:  Trunks: Lower Divisions: Anterior Cords: Medial ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 45
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "question": " [BLANK] Nerve: {{c1::Ulnar nerve}} Roots: {{c2:: C8 , T1 ::2 }} ",
    "answer": "Adductor pollicis | Context:  Trunks: Lower Divisions: Anterior Cords: Medial ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 46
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "question": " {{c3::Adductor pollicis}} Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c2:: C8 , T1 ::2 }} ",
    "answer": "Ulnar nerve | Context:  Trunks: Lower Divisions: Anterior Cords: Medial ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 46
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "question": " {{c3::Adductor pollicis}} Nerve: {{c1::Ulnar nerve}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"blue\"\">C8</font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"red\"\"><u>T1</u> | Context:  Trunks: Lower Divisions: Anterior Cords: Medial ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 46
  },
  {
    "id": 44,
    "question": " [BLANK] Nerve: {{c1::Ulnar nerve}} Roots: {{c2:: C8 , T1 ::2 }} ",
    "answer": "First dorsal &amp; abd dig minimi, dorsal interosseus | Context: force fingers into adduction Trunks: Lower Divisions: Anterior Cords: Medial ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 47
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "question": " {{c3::First dorsal & abd dig minimi, dorsal interosseus}} Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c2:: C8 , T1 ::2 }} ",
    "answer": "Ulnar nerve | Context: force fingers into adduction Trunks: Lower Divisions: Anterior Cords: Medial ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 47
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "question": " {{c3::First dorsal & abd dig minimi, dorsal interosseus}} Nerve: {{c1::Ulnar nerve}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"blue\"\">C8</font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"red\"\"><u>T1</u> | Context: force fingers into adduction Trunks: Lower Divisions: Anterior Cords: Medial ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 47
  },
  {
    "id": 47,
    "question": "and L3}} no major ",
    "answer": " Division: posterior ",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Standard",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 82
  },
  {
    "id": 48,
    "question": " [BLANK] Nerve: {{c2::Superior gluteal}} Roots: {{c3:: L4 , L5 , S1::3 }} ",
    "answer": "<b>Gluteus medius/min &amp; tensor fascia</b> | Context:  Division: Posterior ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 83
  },
  {
    "id": 49,
    "question": " {{c1:: Gluteus medius/min & tensor fascia ::3}} Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c3:: L4 , L5 , S1::3 }} ",
    "answer": "Superior gluteal | Context:  Division: Posterior ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 83
  },
  {
    "id": 50,
    "question": " {{c1:: Gluteus medius/min & tensor fascia ::3}} Nerve: {{c2::Superior gluteal}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"blue\"\">L4</font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"red\"\">L5</font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"blue\"\">S1 | Context:  Division: Posterior ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 83
  },
  {
    "id": 51,
    "question": " [BLANK] Nerve: {{c1::Inferior gluteal}} Roots: {{c2:: L5 , S1 , S2 }} ",
    "answer": "Gluteus maximus | Context:  Division: Posterior ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 84
  },
  {
    "id": 52,
    "question": " {{c3::Gluteus maximus}} Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c2:: L5 , S1 , S2 }} ",
    "answer": "Inferior gluteal | Context:  Division: Posterior ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 84
  },
  {
    "id": 53,
    "question": " {{c3::Gluteus maximus}} Nerve: {{c1::Inferior gluteal}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"blue\"\">L5</font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"red\"\">S1</font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"blue\"\">S2</font> | Context:  Division: Posterior ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 84
  },
  {
    "id": 54,
    "question": " Quadriceps Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c2:: L2, L3 , L4::3 }} ",
    "answer": "Femoral | Context:  Division: Posterior ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 85
  },
  {
    "id": 55,
    "question": " Quadriceps Nerve: {{c1::Femoral}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"#033bff\"\">L2,&nbsp;L3</font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"red\"\">L4 | Context:  Division: Posterior ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 85
  },
  {
    "id": 56,
    "question": " [BLANK] Nerve: {{c1::Deep peroneal}} Roots: {{c2:: L4 , L5::2 }} ",
    "answer": "Tibialis anterior | Context:  Division: Posterior ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 86
  },
  {
    "id": 57,
    "question": " {{c3::Tibialis anterior::m.}} Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c2:: L4 , L5::2 }} ",
    "answer": "Deep peroneal | Context:  Division: Posterior ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 86
  },
  {
    "id": 58,
    "question": " {{c3::Tibialis anterior::m.}} Nerve: {{c1::Deep peroneal}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"blue\"\">L4</font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"red\"\">L5 | Context:  Division: Posterior ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 86
  },
  {
    "id": 59,
    "question": " Extensor hallucis longus Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c2:: L5 , S1::2 }} ",
    "answer": "Deep peroneal | Context:  Division: Posterior ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 87
  },
  {
    "id": 60,
    "question": " Extensor hallucis longus Nerve: {{c1::Deep peroneal}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"red\"\">L5</font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"blue\"\">S1 | Context:  Division: Posterior ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 87
  },
  {
    "id": 61,
    "question": " Flexor hallucis longus Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c2:: L5 , S1 , S2::3 }} ",
    "answer": "Tibial | Context:  Division: Anterior (no conflict, diagram is wrong) ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 88
  },
  {
    "id": 62,
    "question": " Flexor hallucis longus Nerve: {{c1::Tibial}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"red\"\">L5</font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"red\"\">S1</font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"blue\"\">S2 | Context:  Division: Anterior (no conflict, diagram is wrong) ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 88
  },
  {
    "id": 63,
    "question": " [BLANK] Nerve: {{c2::Tibial}} Roots: {{c3:: L5 , S1::2 }} ",
    "answer": "Tibialis posterior | Context: Patient plantar flexes and inverts foot. Division: Anterior (conflict easy emg sates L4,5,S1 ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 89
  },
  {
    "id": 64,
    "question": " {{c1::Tibialis posterior}} Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c3:: L5 , S1::2 }} ",
    "answer": "Tibial | Context: Patient plantar flexes and inverts foot. Division: Anterior (conflict easy emg sates L4,5,S1 ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 89
  },
  {
    "id": 65,
    "question": " {{c1::Tibialis posterior}} Nerve: {{c2::Tibial}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"#fc0006\"\">L5</font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"#033bff\"\">S1 | Context: Patient plantar flexes and inverts foot. Division: Anterior (conflict easy emg sates L4,5,S1 ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 89
  },
  {
    "id": 66,
    "question": " [BLANK] Nerve: {{c2::Superficial peroneal}} Roots: {{c3:: L5 , S1::2 }} ",
    "answer": "<b>Peroneus longus &amp; brevis</b> | Context:  Patient plantar flexes and everts foot. Division: Posterior ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 90
  },
  {
    "id": 67,
    "question": " {{c1:: Peroneus longus & brevis ::2}} Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c3:: L5 , S1::2 }} ",
    "answer": "Superficial peroneal | Context:  Patient plantar flexes and everts foot. Division: Posterior ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 90
  },
  {
    "id": 68,
    "question": " {{c1:: Peroneus longus & brevis ::2}} Nerve: {{c2::Superficial peroneal}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"red\"\">L5</font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"blue\"\">S1 | Context:  Patient plantar flexes and everts foot. Division: Posterior ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 90
  },
  {
    "id": 69,
    "question": " Gastrocnemius & soleus : Nerve: [BLANK] Roots: {{c2:: S1 , S2 ::2 }} ",
    "answer": "Tibial",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 91
  },
  {
    "id": 70,
    "question": " Gastrocnemius & soleus : Nerve: {{c1::Tibial}} Roots: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "<font color=\"\"red\"\">S1</font>,&nbsp;<font color=\"\"#033bff\"\">S2</font><font color=\"\"red\"\">",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 91
  },
  {
    "id": 71,
    "question": "{{c1:: de myelination }} is an injury to sheath of the nerve (but the axon remains intact.) translates to slower signal conduction (onset/peak latency +/- duration) along the axon. ",
    "answer": "may present as decrease in amplitude if a conduction block is present ",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Standard",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 112
  },
  {
    "id": 72,
    "question": " Failure of an AP to propagate past an area of demyelination (along healthy axons) is known as [BLANK] It can present as a {{c2::>20% - >50%::%range2#'s}} drop in {{c3::CMAP amplitude}} with stim. {{c4::across the area of injury or L/R comparison::location 2}} ",
    "answer": "<strong>conduction block</strong>. | Context: ex. a type of severe focal demyelination (ulnar tunnel, saturday night palsy)...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 113
  },
  {
    "id": 73,
    "question": " Failure of an AP to propagate past an area of demyelination (along healthy axons) is known as {{c1:: conduction block .}} It can present as a [BLANK] drop in {{c3::CMAP amplitude}} with stim. {{c4::across the area of injury or L/R comparison::location 2}} ",
    "answer": "&gt;20% - &gt;50% | Context: ex. a type of severe focal demyelination (ulnar tunnel, saturday night palsy)...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 113
  },
  {
    "id": 74,
    "question": " Failure of an AP to propagate past an area of demyelination (along healthy axons) is known as {{c1:: conduction block .}} It can present as a {{c2::>20% - >50%::%range2#'s}} drop in [BLANK] with stim. {{c4::across the area of injury or L/R comparison::location 2}} ",
    "answer": "CMAP&nbsp;amplitude | Context: ex. a type of severe focal demyelination (ulnar tunnel, saturday night palsy)...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 113
  },
  {
    "id": 75,
    "question": " Failure of an AP to propagate past an area of demyelination (along healthy axons) is known as {{c1:: conduction block .}} It can present as a {{c2::>20% - >50%::%range2#'s}} drop in {{c3::CMAP amplitude}} with stim. [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "across the area of injury or L/R comparison | Context: ex. a type of severe focal demyelination (ulnar tunnel, saturday night palsy)...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 113
  },
  {
    "id": 76,
    "question": " demyelination affects the speed of signal conduction along a nerve thus NCS's (CMAP and SNAP) parameters effected include : {{c1::o/p latency }} [BLANK] [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "CV / duration (temporal dispersion)",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 116
  },
  {
    "id": 77,
    "question": "[BLANK] injuries affect the amplitude on nerve conduction waveform ",
    "answer": "Axonal",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 117
  },
  {
    "id": 78,
    "question": "[BLANK]: A nerve injury that begins in a “ dying back ” fashion and affects the nerve distally and ascends proximally [BLANK]: A nerve injury that degenerates distally. The nerve segment proximal to the injury site is essentially intact ",
    "answer": "Axonal Degeneration / Wallerian Degeneration",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 118
  },
  {
    "id": 79,
    "question": " [BLANK] is repair in which a neurite sends off axons of an intact motor unit and innervates muscle fibers of an injured motor unit results in MUAP changes (evidnece of chronic injury): {{c2::polyphasic waveforms}} {{c2::increased duration}} {{c2::increased amplitude}} ",
    "answer": "Collateral sprouting | Context:  - sprouts connect with smaller terminal branches, thinner myelin, and weaker NMJs - increasing size of MU territory - motor units fire with poor synchronicity ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 119
  },
  {
    "id": 80,
    "question": " {{c1::Collateral sprouting}} is repair in which a neurite sends off axons of an intact motor unit and innervates muscle fibers of an injured motor unit results in MUAP changes (evidnece of chronic injury): [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "polyphasic waveforms / increased duration / increased amplitude | Context:  - sprouts connect with smaller terminal branches, thinner myelin, and weaker NMJs - increasing size of MU territory - motor units fire with poor synchronicity ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 119
  },
  {
    "id": 81,
    "question": "[BLANK] is a process of repair in which the nerve regrows down its original path It will travel approximately {{c2::1 mm}}/d or {{c3::1 in./}} mo if the supporting connective tissue remains intact. ",
    "answer": "Axonal regrowth | Context:  With reinnervation, low-amplitude, long-duration, and polyphasic potentials known as nascent potentials are formed. ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 120
  },
  {
    "id": 82,
    "question": "{{c1::Axonal regrowth}} is a process of repair in which the nerve regrows down its original path It will travel approximately [BLANK]/d or {{c3::1 in./}} mo if the supporting connective tissue remains intact. ",
    "answer": "1 mm | Context:  With reinnervation, low-amplitude, long-duration, and polyphasic potentials known as nascent potentials are formed. ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 120
  },
  {
    "id": 83,
    "question": "{{c1::Axonal regrowth}} is a process of repair in which the nerve regrows down its original path It will travel approximately {{c2::1 mm}}/d or [BLANK] mo if the supporting connective tissue remains intact. ",
    "answer": "1 in./ | Context:  With reinnervation, low-amplitude, long-duration, and polyphasic potentials known as nascent potentials are formed. ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 120
  },
  {
    "id": 84,
    "question": " Sunderland Classification TYPE 1 [BLANK] TYPE 2 {{c2::Axonal injury ( axonotmesis )::2}} TYPE 3 Type 2 + {{c3::Endoneurium}} injury TYPE 4 Type 3 + {{c4::Perineurium}} injury TYPE 5 Type 4 + {{c5::Epineurium injury ( neurotmesis )::2}} ",
    "answer": "Conduction block (<u>neuropraxia</u>)",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 121
  },
  {
    "id": 85,
    "question": " Sunderland Classification TYPE 1 {{c1::Conduction block ( neuropraxia )::2}} TYPE 2 [BLANK] TYPE 3 Type 2 + {{c3::Endoneurium}} injury TYPE 4 Type 3 + {{c4::Perineurium}} injury TYPE 5 Type 4 + {{c5::Epineurium injury ( neurotmesis )::2}} ",
    "answer": "Axonal injury (<u>axonotmesis</u>)",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 121
  },
  {
    "id": 86,
    "question": " Sunderland Classification TYPE 1 {{c1::Conduction block ( neuropraxia )::2}} TYPE 2 {{c2::Axonal injury ( axonotmesis )::2}} TYPE 3 Type 2 + [BLANK] injury TYPE 4 Type 3 + {{c4::Perineurium}} injury TYPE 5 Type 4 + {{c5::Epineurium injury ( neurotmesis )::2}} ",
    "answer": "Endoneurium",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 121
  },
  {
    "id": 87,
    "question": " Sunderland Classification TYPE 1 {{c1::Conduction block ( neuropraxia )::2}} TYPE 2 {{c2::Axonal injury ( axonotmesis )::2}} TYPE 3 Type 2 + {{c3::Endoneurium}} injury TYPE 4 Type 3 + [BLANK] injury TYPE 5 Type 4 + {{c5::Epineurium injury ( neurotmesis )::2}} ",
    "answer": "Perineurium",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 121
  },
  {
    "id": 88,
    "question": " Sunderland Classification TYPE 1 {{c1::Conduction block ( neuropraxia )::2}} TYPE 2 {{c2::Axonal injury ( axonotmesis )::2}} TYPE 3 Type 2 + {{c3::Endoneurium}} injury TYPE 4 Type 3 + {{c4::Perineurium}} injury TYPE 5 Type 4 + [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "Epineurium injury (<u>neurotmesis</u>)",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 121
  },
  {
    "id": 89,
    "question": "[BLANK] is A theoretical local block that occurs when reversing the stimulator’s cathode and anode. This hyperpolarizes the nerve, thus inhibiting the production of an action potential ",
    "answer": "Anodal Block",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 122
  },
  {
    "id": 90,
    "question": "[BLANK] stim. intensity 20% above the max stimulus to generate an AP (typically used for NCS ) stimulus intensity set too {{c2::high}} - {{c4::Altered waveforms (spreads through tissues beyond surface electrodes)}} - Amplitudes {{c4::remain unchanged}} stimulus intensity set too {{c2::low}} - falsely {{c3::lower amplitude}} - falsely {{c3::prolonged latency}} ",
    "answer": "Supramaximal stimulus",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 123
  },
  {
    "id": 91,
    "question": "{{c1::Supramaximal stimulus}} stim. intensity 20% above the max stimulus to generate an AP (typically used for NCS ) stimulus intensity set too [BLANK] - {{c4::Altered waveforms (spreads through tissues beyond surface electrodes)}} - Amplitudes {{c4::remain unchanged}} stimulus intensity set too [BLANK] - falsely {{c3::lower amplitude}} - falsely {{c3::prolonged latency}} ",
    "answer": "high / low",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 123
  },
  {
    "id": 92,
    "question": "{{c1::Supramaximal stimulus}} stim. intensity 20% above the max stimulus to generate an AP (typically used for NCS ) stimulus intensity set too {{c2::high}} - [BLANK] - Amplitudes [BLANK] stimulus intensity set too {{c2::low}} - falsely {{c3::lower amplitude}} - falsely {{c3::prolonged latency}} ",
    "answer": "Altered waveforms (spreads through tissues beyond surface electrodes) / remain unchanged",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 123
  },
  {
    "id": 93,
    "question": "{{c1::Supramaximal stimulus}} stim. intensity 20% above the max stimulus to generate an AP (typically used for NCS ) stimulus intensity set too {{c2::high}} - {{c4::Altered waveforms (spreads through tissues beyond surface electrodes)}} - Amplitudes {{c4::remain unchanged}} stimulus intensity set too {{c2::low}} - falsely [BLANK] - falsely [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "lower amplitude / prolonged latency",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 123
  },
  {
    "id": 94,
    "question": " process of averaging improves the {{c1::Signal to Noise Ratio (S:N)}} by a factor that is the square root of the number of averages performed. ",
    "answer": " This averaging process extracts the desired neurophysiologic signal from larger noise and interference signals S:N= { Signal amplitude × √# of averages performed} / Noise amplitude Interference = unwanted signals occurring from outside the system being studied Noise = unwanted signals occurring from within the system (eg. electrical outlets, fluorescent lights) ",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Standard",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 124
  },
  {
    "id": 95,
    "question": "Stimulus Artifact This is a defect seen at the time the stimulus is applied to the skin and represents current spread to the electrode. It can be minimized by Appropriate: [BLANK] placement {{c1::Cleansing the skin from dirt, perspiration, and lotions::pt factor}}",
    "answer": "ground and stimulator (anode and cathode)",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 125
  },
  {
    "id": 96,
    "question": "Stimulus Artifact This is a defect seen at the time the stimulus is applied to the skin and represents current spread to the electrode. It can be minimized by Appropriate: {{c2::ground and stimulator (anode and cathode)::equipment factor 2}} placement [BLANK]",
    "answer": "Cleansing the skin from dirt, perspiration, and lotions",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 125
  },
  {
    "id": 97,
    "question": " A grid is projected on the screen with the horizontal axis representing [BLANK] and the vertical axis representing {{c2::sensitivity ( mV )::name, unit}} or gain each cube is a {{c3::division}} ",
    "answer": "sweep speed (<i>msec</i>)",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 126
  },
  {
    "id": 98,
    "question": " A grid is projected on the screen with the horizontal axis representing {{c1::sweep speed ( msec )::name, unit}} and the vertical axis representing [BLANK] or gain each cube is a {{c3::division}} ",
    "answer": "sensitivity (<i>mV</i>)",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 126
  },
  {
    "id": 99,
    "question": " A grid is projected on the screen with the horizontal axis representing {{c1::sweep speed ( msec )::name, unit}} and the vertical axis representing {{c2::sensitivity ( mV )::name, unit}} or gain each cube is a [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "division",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 126
  },
  {
    "id": 100,
    "question": "[BLANK] is the time required for an electrical stimulus to initiate an evoked potential (fastest axon) [BLANK] is the time for the majority of the axons ",
    "answer": "Onset/distal latency (CMAP) / Peak latency (SNAP)",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 127
  },
  {
    "id": 101,
    "question": "[BLANK] is the speed an impulse travels along a nerve primarily dependent on the integrity of the {{c2::myelin}} Normal values are generally >{{c3::50}} m/sec in the upper limbs and >{{c3::40}} m/sec in the lower limbs ",
    "answer": "conduction velocity | Context:  It can be decreased with nerve injury and from technical factors. It should remain normal even in severe axonal injuries, as NCSs record the velocity of fastest surviving nerve fibers ...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 128
  },
  {
    "id": 102,
    "question": "{{c1::conduction velocity}} is the speed an impulse travels along a nerve primarily dependent on the integrity of the [BLANK] Normal values are generally >{{c3::50}} m/sec in the upper limbs and >{{c3::40}} m/sec in the lower limbs ",
    "answer": "myelin | Context:  It can be decreased with nerve injury and from technical factors. It should remain normal even in severe axonal injuries, as NCSs record the velocity of fastest surviving nerve fibers ...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 128
  },
  {
    "id": 103,
    "question": "{{c1::conduction velocity}} is the speed an impulse travels along a nerve primarily dependent on the integrity of the {{c2::myelin}} Normal values are generally >[BLANK] m/sec in the upper limbs and >[BLANK] m/sec in the lower limbs ",
    "answer": "50 / 40 | Context:  It can be decreased with nerve injury and from technical factors. It should remain normal even in severe axonal injuries, as NCSs record the velocity of fastest surviving nerve fibers ...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 128
  },
  {
    "id": 104,
    "question": "[BLANK] reflects the number of activated muscle fibers or sensory nerve fibers CMAP (or SNAP) [BLANK] reductions are due to injury to {{c2::axons}} ",
    "answer": "Amplitude / amplitude | Context:  (typical axonal neuropathy), other causes include conduction block, NMJ disorders, and myopathies ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 130
  },
  {
    "id": 105,
    "question": "{{c1::Amplitude}} reflects the number of activated muscle fibers or sensory nerve fibers CMAP (or SNAP) {{c1::amplitude::same}} reductions are due to injury to [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "axons | Context:  (typical axonal neuropathy), other causes include conduction block, NMJ disorders, and myopathies ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 130
  },
  {
    "id": 106,
    "question": "[BLANK] is measured from the initial deflection from baseline to the first baseline crossing. it is a measure of {{c2::synchrony}} of the sensory nerve fibers and individual muscle fibers firing ",
    "answer": "duration",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 131
  },
  {
    "id": 107,
    "question": "{{c1::duration::NCS parameter}} is measured from the initial deflection from baseline to the first baseline crossing. it is a measure of [BLANK] of the sensory nerve fibers and individual muscle fibers firing ",
    "answer": "synchrony",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 131
  },
  {
    "id": 108,
    "question": "[BLANK] reflects the range of conduction velocities of the fastest and slowest nerve fibers. ",
    "answer": "Temporal dispersion | Context:  ex. segmental demeylination 2/2 GBS, CIDP ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 132
  },
  {
    "id": 109,
    "question": " [BLANK] = when stimulated, the APs of one axon may be out of sync with neighboring ones when comparing a {{c4::proximal to distal}} stimulation , a drop in amplitude and increase in duration occurs (nl.) amplitude drop of {{c2::50%::%}} is considered normal when recording a proximal SNAP amplitude drop of {{c3::15%::%}} is considered normal when recording a proximal CMAP ",
    "answer": "Phase Cancellation | Context:  Caveat: DROP only in MOTOR NCS \"\"sensory to small to count\"\" Sensory— SNAP phase cancellation. Open arrows indicate stimulation of the nerve distally; the phases from the individual SNAPs summate. Cl...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 133
  },
  {
    "id": 110,
    "question": " {{c1::Phase Cancellation}} = when stimulated, the APs of one axon may be out of sync with neighboring ones when comparing a [BLANK] stimulation , a drop in amplitude and increase in duration occurs (nl.) amplitude drop of {{c2::50%::%}} is considered normal when recording a proximal SNAP amplitude drop of {{c3::15%::%}} is considered normal when recording a proximal CMAP ",
    "answer": "proximal to distal | Context:  Caveat: DROP only in MOTOR NCS \"\"sensory to small to count\"\" Sensory— SNAP phase cancellation. Open arrows indicate stimulation of the nerve distally; the phases from the individual SNAPs summate. Cl...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 133
  },
  {
    "id": 111,
    "question": " {{c1::Phase Cancellation}} = when stimulated, the APs of one axon may be out of sync with neighboring ones when comparing a {{c4::proximal to distal}} stimulation , a drop in amplitude and increase in duration occurs (nl.) amplitude drop of [BLANK] is considered normal when recording a proximal SNAP amplitude drop of {{c3::15%::%}} is considered normal when recording a proximal CMAP ",
    "answer": "50% | Context:  Caveat: DROP only in MOTOR NCS \"\"sensory to small to count\"\" Sensory— SNAP phase cancellation. Open arrows indicate stimulation of the nerve distally; the phases from the individual SNAPs summate. Cl...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 133
  },
  {
    "id": 112,
    "question": " {{c1::Phase Cancellation}} = when stimulated, the APs of one axon may be out of sync with neighboring ones when comparing a {{c4::proximal to distal}} stimulation , a drop in amplitude and increase in duration occurs (nl.) amplitude drop of {{c2::50%::%}} is considered normal when recording a proximal SNAP amplitude drop of [BLANK] is considered normal when recording a proximal CMAP ",
    "answer": "15% | Context:  Caveat: DROP only in MOTOR NCS \"\"sensory to small to count\"\" Sensory— SNAP phase cancellation. Open arrows indicate stimulation of the nerve distally; the phases from the individual SNAPs summate. Cl...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 133
  },
  {
    "id": 113,
    "question": "SNAPs are normal in [BLANK] injury ",
    "answer": "Pre-ganglionic | Context:  Postganglionic injury: results in Wallerian degeneration of both motor and sensory axons. CMAP and SNAP responses are diminished or absent. peripheral neuropathy Preganglionic injury: allows the peri...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 134
  },
  {
    "id": 114,
    "question": " active and reference pickup should be [BLANK] cm apart. Less than this distance will alter the waveform parameters by {{c2::decreasing::inceasing/decreasing}} them all Save for {{c3::onset latency}} which will still be normal ",
    "answer": "&gt; 4 | Context:  PARAMETERS CHANGE Peak latency Decreased Amplitude Decreased Duration Decreased Rise time Decreased ...",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 135
  },
  {
    "id": 115,
    "question": " active and reference pickup should be {{c1::> 4:: >/</#}} cm apart. Less than this distance will alter the waveform parameters by [BLANK] them all Save for {{c3::onset latency}} which will still be normal ",
    "answer": "decreasing | Context:  PARAMETERS CHANGE Peak latency Decreased Amplitude Decreased Duration Decreased Rise time Decreased ...",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 135
  },
  {
    "id": 116,
    "question": " active and reference pickup should be {{c1::> 4:: >/</#}} cm apart. Less than this distance will alter the waveform parameters by {{c2::decreasing::inceasing/decreasing}} them all Save for [BLANK] which will still be normal ",
    "answer": "onset latency | Context:  PARAMETERS CHANGE Peak latency Decreased Amplitude Decreased Duration Decreased Rise time Decreased ...",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 135
  },
  {
    "id": 117,
    "question": " CMAP potential should be [BLANK] with an initial {{c2::negative (upward)}} deflection ",
    "answer": "biphasic",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 136
  },
  {
    "id": 118,
    "question": " CMAP potential should be {{c1::biphasic::morphology}} with an initial [BLANK] deflection ",
    "answer": "negative (upward)",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 136
  },
  {
    "id": 119,
    "question": "CMAP: if an initial positive deflection exists, it may be due to... 1.) [BLANK] 2.) {{c2::conduction from other muscles (stim^)}} 3.) {{c3::Anomalous innervations (M. gruber)}}",
    "answer": "Inappropriate placement of active electrode (from MP) | Context:  Motor points (MP) = point with the highest excitability (AP by the minimum intensity/duration of stim.) anatomically the area where motor endplates (terminal area of the motor nerve enters the muscle...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 137
  },
  {
    "id": 120,
    "question": "CMAP: if an initial positive deflection exists, it may be due to... 1.) {{c1::Inappropriate placement of active electrode (from MP)}} 2.) [BLANK] 3.) {{c3::Anomalous innervations (M. gruber)}}",
    "answer": "conduction from other muscles (stim^) | Context:  Motor points (MP) = point with the highest excitability (AP by the minimum intensity/duration of stim.) anatomically the area where motor endplates (terminal area of the motor nerve enters the muscle...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 137
  },
  {
    "id": 121,
    "question": "CMAP: if an initial positive deflection exists, it may be due to... 1.) {{c1::Inappropriate placement of active electrode (from MP)}} 2.) {{c2::conduction from other muscles (stim^)}} 3.) [BLANK]",
    "answer": "Anomalous innervations (M. gruber) | Context:  Motor points (MP) = point with the highest excitability (AP by the minimum intensity/duration of stim.) anatomically the area where motor endplates (terminal area of the motor nerve enters the muscle...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 137
  },
  {
    "id": 122,
    "question": " Recording electrode falsely decreased amplitude can be due to... [BLANK] {{c2::position off from motor point}} {{c3::submaximal stimulation}} ",
    "answer": "active and reference electrodes too close together",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 138
  },
  {
    "id": 123,
    "question": " Recording electrode falsely decreased amplitude can be due to... {{c1::active and reference electrodes too close together}} [BLANK] {{c3::submaximal stimulation}} ",
    "answer": "position off from motor point",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 138
  },
  {
    "id": 124,
    "question": " Recording electrode falsely decreased amplitude can be due to... {{c1::active and reference electrodes too close together}} {{c2::position off from motor point}} [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "submaximal stimulation",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 138
  },
  {
    "id": 125,
    "question": "[BLANK] is an NCS analogue to a monosynaptic reflex ",
    "answer": "H-reflex",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 139
  },
  {
    "id": 126,
    "question": " H-reflex is initiated with a [BLANK] at a [BLANK] duration (1.0 msec). causing an {{c1::orthodromic:: ortho/anti }} {{c1::sensory:: motor/sensory }} response to the spinal cord, and then an {{c1::orthodromic:: ortho/anti }} {{c1::motor:: motor/sensory }} response back to the electrode ",
    "answer": "submaximal stimulus / long | Context:  A rudimentary M response is produced when a few motor axons are directly stimulated Low stim to go up the sensory (bock) ...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 140
  },
  {
    "id": 127,
    "question": " H-reflex is initiated with a {{c2::submaximal stimulus}} at a {{c2::long}} duration (1.0 msec). causing an [BLANK] [BLANK] response to the spinal cord, and then an [BLANK] [BLANK] response back to the electrode ",
    "answer": "orthodromic / sensory / orthodromic / motor | Context:  A rudimentary M response is produced when a few motor axons are directly stimulated Low stim to go up the sensory (bock) ...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 140
  },
  {
    "id": 128,
    "question": " H-reflex limitations 1) [BLANK] 2) {{c2::cannot distinguish between acute and chronic}} 3) {{c3::NOT a specific finding to S1 radiculopathy }} ",
    "answer": "can not localize lesion | Context:  evaluates a long neural pathway, which can dilute focal lesions and hinder specificity of injury location Once it is abnormal, it is always abnormal can be seen in multiple other conditions, includin...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 141
  },
  {
    "id": 129,
    "question": " H-reflex limitations 1) {{c1::can not localize lesion}} 2) [BLANK] 3) {{c3::NOT a specific finding to S1 radiculopathy }} ",
    "answer": "cannot distinguish between acute and chronic | Context:  evaluates a long neural pathway, which can dilute focal lesions and hinder specificity of injury location Once it is abnormal, it is always abnormal can be seen in multiple other conditions, includin...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 141
  },
  {
    "id": 130,
    "question": "[BLANK] is a small late motor response occurring after the CMAP . It is produced using a {{c2::short}} duration, {{c2::supramaximal}} stimulation ",
    "answer": "F-wave | Context:  It represents a late response from approximately 1% to 5% of the CMAP amplitude. ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 142
  },
  {
    "id": 131,
    "question": "{{c1::F-wave}} is a small late motor response occurring after the CMAP . It is produced using a [BLANK] duration, [BLANK] stimulation ",
    "answer": "short / supramaximal | Context:  It represents a late response from approximately 1% to 5% of the CMAP amplitude. ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 142
  },
  {
    "id": 132,
    "question": " In [BLANK] morphology and latency remain constant with each stimulation at the appropriate intensity ",
    "answer": "H-reflex | Context:  Note that a mean of 10 F-waves can be used as a surrogate for one H-reflex F-wave: The configuration and latency change with each stimulation due to activation of different groups of anterior horn ce...",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 144
  },
  {
    "id": 133,
    "question": " EMG increased insertional activity may be seen in both [BLANK] and [BLANK] conditions ",
    "answer": "neuropathic / myopathic",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 145
  },
  {
    "id": 134,
    "question": " EMG rare conditions, where [BLANK] has occurred, insertional activity may be decreased ",
    "answer": "muscle atrophy | Context:  acute ischemia of muscle due to vascular occlusion or compartment syndrome may also produce decreased Insertional activity. (A) Normal. (B) Increased. CHARACTERISTIC NORMAL INCREASED DECREASED Durati...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 173
  },
  {
    "id": 135,
    "question": " a needle inserted into muscle should be silent at rest if placed near the NMJ (motor endplate), two waveforms can occur: 1.) {{c1:: MEPPs (EP noise) }} which sound like a [BLANK] 2.) {{c1:: EPPs (EP spikes)}} which sound like a [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "sea-shell murmur / sputtering fat | Context:  (A) MEPP —Monophasic negative potentials primarily present as baseline irregularities because of their small amplitude. - excocytosis of ACh quanta traversing NMJ (B) EPP —Biphasic, usually negative ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 174
  },
  {
    "id": 136,
    "question": " a needle inserted into muscle should be silent at rest if placed near the NMJ (motor endplate), two waveforms can occur: 1.) {{c1:: MEPPs (EP noise) }} which sound like a {{c2::sea-shell murmur}} 2.) [BLANK] which sound like a {{c2::sputtering fat}} ",
    "answer": "<strong>EPPs </strong>(EP spikes) | Context:  (A) MEPP —Monophasic negative potentials primarily present as baseline irregularities because of their small amplitude. - excocytosis of ACh quanta traversing NMJ (B) EPP —Biphasic, usually negative ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 174
  },
  {
    "id": 137,
    "question": "EMG , hallmarks are sounding like (Fib): [BLANK] and (Psw): {{c2:: \"\" dull thuds\"\" }} and their [BLANK] of firing ",
    "answer": "\"\"rain on a tin roof” / regularity | Context:  Spontaneously firing APs originating from denervated single muscle fibers secondary to uncontrolled ACh release Although they are typically associated with neuropathies, they can also be seen in myop...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 200
  },
  {
    "id": 138,
    "question": " [BLANK] sound like a {{c2::motor boat}} spontaneous, polyphasic APs originating from a group muscle fibers fire in near synchrony by {{c3::ephaptic transmission}} 2/2 {{c4::collateral sprouting}} ",
    "answer": "complex repetetive discharges",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 221
  },
  {
    "id": 139,
    "question": " {{c1::complex repetetive discharges}} sound like a [BLANK] spontaneous, polyphasic APs originating from a group muscle fibers fire in near synchrony by {{c3::ephaptic transmission}} 2/2 {{c4::collateral sprouting}} ",
    "answer": "motor boat",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 221
  },
  {
    "id": 140,
    "question": " {{c1::complex repetetive discharges}} sound like a {{c2::motor boat}} spontaneous, polyphasic APs originating from a group muscle fibers fire in near synchrony by [BLANK] 2/2 {{c4::collateral sprouting}} ",
    "answer": "ephaptic transmission",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 221
  },
  {
    "id": 141,
    "question": " {{c1::complex repetetive discharges}} sound like a {{c2::motor boat}} spontaneous, polyphasic APs originating from a group muscle fibers fire in near synchrony by {{c3::ephaptic transmission}} 2/2 [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "collateral sprouting",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 221
  },
  {
    "id": 142,
    "question": " [BLANK] are classicly associated w/ {{c3::myopathies::disease category}} {{c4::biphasic::waveform}} single muscle fiber AP's arise after mechanical irritation hallmark sign: smooth change in rate and amplitude with a {{c1::“dive bomber”}} sound ",
    "answer": "myotonic discharges | Context:  ETIOLOGY Nerve disorders : Chronic radiculopathy, peripheral neuropathy Muscle disorders : Myotonic dystrophy, myotonia congenita, paramyotonia, polymyositis, dermatomyositis, acid-maltase deficiency...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 223
  },
  {
    "id": 143,
    "question": " {{c2::myotonic discharges}} are classicly associated w/ [BLANK] {{c4::biphasic::waveform}} single muscle fiber AP's arise after mechanical irritation hallmark sign: smooth change in rate and amplitude with a {{c1::“dive bomber”}} sound ",
    "answer": "myopathies | Context:  ETIOLOGY Nerve disorders : Chronic radiculopathy, peripheral neuropathy Muscle disorders : Myotonic dystrophy, myotonia congenita, paramyotonia, polymyositis, dermatomyositis, acid-maltase deficiency...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 223
  },
  {
    "id": 144,
    "question": " {{c2::myotonic discharges}} are classicly associated w/ {{c3::myopathies::disease category}} [BLANK] single muscle fiber AP's arise after mechanical irritation hallmark sign: smooth change in rate and amplitude with a {{c1::“dive bomber”}} sound ",
    "answer": "biphasic | Context:  ETIOLOGY Nerve disorders : Chronic radiculopathy, peripheral neuropathy Muscle disorders : Myotonic dystrophy, myotonia congenita, paramyotonia, polymyositis, dermatomyositis, acid-maltase deficiency...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 223
  },
  {
    "id": 145,
    "question": " {{c2::myotonic discharges}} are classicly associated w/ {{c3::myopathies::disease category}} {{c4::biphasic::waveform}} single muscle fiber AP's arise after mechanical irritation hallmark sign: smooth change in rate and amplitude with a [BLANK] sound ",
    "answer": "“dive bomber” | Context:  ETIOLOGY Nerve disorders : Chronic radiculopathy, peripheral neuropathy Muscle disorders : Myotonic dystrophy, myotonia congenita, paramyotonia, polymyositis, dermatomyositis, acid-maltase deficiency...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 223
  },
  {
    "id": 146,
    "question": "[BLANK] has the appearance of a MUAP with an {{c1::irregular}} firing pattern Its hallmark sign is a much {{c2::slower}} frequency with a {{c1::“corn popping”}} sound ",
    "answer": "fasciculation | Context:  ETIOLOGY: Normal variant ... or Nerve disorders : Anterior horn cell disease, tetany, Creutzfeldt–Jakob syndrome, radiculopathy, mononeuropathy Metabolic disorders : Thyrotoxicosis, tetany or ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 224
  },
  {
    "id": 147,
    "question": "{{c3::fasciculation}} has the appearance of a MUAP with an [BLANK] firing pattern Its hallmark sign is a much {{c2::slower}} frequency with a [BLANK] sound ",
    "answer": "irregular / “corn popping” | Context:  ETIOLOGY: Normal variant ... or Nerve disorders : Anterior horn cell disease, tetany, Creutzfeldt–Jakob syndrome, radiculopathy, mononeuropathy Metabolic disorders : Thyrotoxicosis, tetany or ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 224
  },
  {
    "id": 148,
    "question": "{{c3::fasciculation}} has the appearance of a MUAP with an {{c1::irregular}} firing pattern Its hallmark sign is a much [BLANK] frequency with a {{c1::“corn popping”}} sound ",
    "answer": "slower | Context:  ETIOLOGY: Normal variant ... or Nerve disorders : Anterior horn cell disease, tetany, Creutzfeldt–Jakob syndrome, radiculopathy, mononeuropathy Metabolic disorders : Thyrotoxicosis, tetany or ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 224
  },
  {
    "id": 149,
    "question": " Myokymic discharges are most commonly seen in [BLANK]",
    "answer": "radiated-induced neuropathy | Context:  ETIOLOGY Facial myokymia : MS , brainstem neoplasm, polyradiculopathy, Bell’s palsy Extremity myokymia : Radiation plexopathy (most common), compression neuropathy , rattlesnake venom ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 232
  },
  {
    "id": 150,
    "question": "[BLANK] : high-frequency, repetitive discharges with progressively decremental amplitudes Hallmark signs on EMG include characteristic {{c2::“pinging”}} sound and {{c3::Tornado-like}} appearance ",
    "answer": "Neuromyotonic discharges | Context:  originating from damaged peripheral motor axons. progressive decrement of waveforms is due to individual muscle fiber fatigue and drop off ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 233
  },
  {
    "id": 151,
    "question": "{{c1::Neuromyotonic discharges}} : high-frequency, repetitive discharges with progressively decremental amplitudes Hallmark signs on EMG include characteristic [BLANK] sound and {{c3::Tornado-like}} appearance ",
    "answer": "“pinging” | Context:  originating from damaged peripheral motor axons. progressive decrement of waveforms is due to individual muscle fiber fatigue and drop off ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 233
  },
  {
    "id": 152,
    "question": "{{c1::Neuromyotonic discharges}} : high-frequency, repetitive discharges with progressively decremental amplitudes Hallmark signs on EMG include characteristic {{c2::“pinging”}} sound and [BLANK] appearance ",
    "answer": "Tornado-like | Context:  originating from damaged peripheral motor axons. progressive decrement of waveforms is due to individual muscle fiber fatigue and drop off ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 233
  },
  {
    "id": 153,
    "question": " Neuromyotonic discharges classically seen in [BLANK] . ",
    "answer": "neuromyotonia (Isaac’s syndrome) | Context:  d/o assocwith continuous muscle fiber activity resulting in the appearance of muscle rippling and stiffness secondary to irritable nerves. ETIOLOGY Nerve disorder : Neuromyotonia, chronic neuropathic...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 234
  },
  {
    "id": 154,
    "question": " exertinal muscle fiber activity can be electrically recorded and summated as a [BLANK] unlike CMAP initial deflection is {{c2::- or +}}. can consist of up to {{c2::4}} phases ",
    "answer": "MUAP",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 235
  },
  {
    "id": 155,
    "question": " exertinal muscle fiber activity can be electrically recorded and summated as a {{c1::MUAP}} unlike CMAP initial deflection is [BLANK]. can consist of up to [BLANK] phases ",
    "answer": "- or + / 4",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 235
  },
  {
    "id": 156,
    "question": "MUAP amplitude: represents the muscle fiber density, measured from the most positive to the most negative peak It can be increased from [BLANK] , A sign that inury is becoming [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "reinnervation / chronic",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 236
  },
  {
    "id": 157,
    "question": "MUAP Rise Time: represents the time it takes the MUAP to go from trough to the peak of the negative wave. It represents [BLANK] to the motor unit. ",
    "answer": "needle position",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 237
  },
  {
    "id": 158,
    "question": "MUAP Duration increases (>15 msec) as the motor unit territory increases 2/2 [BLANK]",
    "answer": "collateral sprouting/reinervation",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 238
  },
  {
    "id": 159,
    "question": " polyphasicity (5 phases) results from [BLANK] and is [BLANK] in timing however, this can occur normally 15% {{c1::(concentric needle)}} or 30% {{c1::( monopolar needle )}} or in the elderly ",
    "answer": "reinnervation/collateral sprouting / chronic",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 239
  },
  {
    "id": 160,
    "question": " polyphasicity (5 phases) results from {{c2::reinnervation/collateral sprouting::patho-phys}} and is {{c2::chronic}} in timing however, this can occur normally 15% [BLANK] or 30% [BLANK] or in the elderly ",
    "answer": "(concentric needle) / (<font color=\"\"#0548ff\"\">monopolar needle</font>)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 239
  },
  {
    "id": 161,
    "question": "[BLANK]: time-locked potentials that trail the MUAP . 2/2 early {{c2::re-inervation}} → very slowly conducting ",
    "answer": "satellite potentitals | Context:  new neural sprouting small, unmyelinated or thinly myelinated Over time, as the sprout matures and the CV increases, the satellite potential will become an additional phase or serration within the MU...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 240
  },
  {
    "id": 162,
    "question": "{{c1::satellite potentitals}}: time-locked potentials that trail the MUAP . 2/2 early [BLANK] → very slowly conducting ",
    "answer": "re-inervation | Context:  new neural sprouting small, unmyelinated or thinly myelinated Over time, as the sprout matures and the CV increases, the satellite potential will become an additional phase or serration within the MU...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 240
  },
  {
    "id": 163,
    "question": "[BLANK] spontaneous repetitive firing of MUAPs assoc w/ {{c2:: metabolic disturbances }} (broad dz category) and pregnancy / strenuous exercise ",
    "answer": "cramp discharge | Context:  Electrolyte abnl, uremia, myxedema prolonged muscle contraction, liver cirrhosis, myotonia congenita, myotonic dystrophy, stiff-man’s syndrome ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 241
  },
  {
    "id": 164,
    "question": "{{c1::cramp discharge}} spontaneous repetitive firing of MUAPs assoc w/ [BLANK] (broad dz category) and pregnancy / strenuous exercise ",
    "answer": "<u>metabolic disturbances</u> | Context:  Electrolyte abnl, uremia, myxedema prolonged muscle contraction, liver cirrhosis, myotonia congenita, myotonic dystrophy, stiff-man’s syndrome ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 241
  },
  {
    "id": 165,
    "question": "[BLANK] refers to addition successive MU's to increase force of contraction. can help decide bewtween {{c2::neruopathic}} and {{c2::myopathic}} diseases ",
    "answer": "Recruitment | Context:  With normal minimal contraction, a single MUAP fires before a second MUAP is recruited...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 242
  },
  {
    "id": 166,
    "question": "{{c1::Recruitment}} refers to addition successive MU's to increase force of contraction. can help decide bewtween [BLANK] and [BLANK] diseases ",
    "answer": "neruopathic / myopathic | Context:  With normal minimal contraction, a single MUAP fires before a second MUAP is recruited...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 242
  },
  {
    "id": 167,
    "question": " EMG MUAP recruitment pattern follows: \"\"The rule of [BLANK] \"\" ",
    "answer": "5's | Context:  The onset frequency of the first MUAP begins at approximately 5 Hz . To generate more force, the FR and recruitment of more motor units must be increased. When the FR reaches approximately 10 Hz , a ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 260
  },
  {
    "id": 168,
    "question": "[BLANK] most commonly seen in myopathic conditions that result in a loss of muscle fibers . ",
    "answer": "Early recruitment | Context:  This loss causes less force to be generated per motor unit. Thus, more motor units must now be called upon abnormally early firing of many MUAPs with a mild contraction ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 261
  },
  {
    "id": 169,
    "question": "[BLANK] most commonly seen in neuropathic conditions ",
    "answer": "Reduced recruitment | Context:  Refers to the firing of fewer than expected MUAPs with even a maximal contraction fire at Higher frequency (30hz) \"\"fewere motor units to recruit\"\" ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 262
  },
  {
    "id": 170,
    "question": " this is a [BLANK] needle electrode ",
    "answer": "Monopolar | Context:  22- to 30-gauge Teflon-coated needle with an exposed tip requres seperate surface electrode records more abnormal activity ...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 264
  },
  {
    "id": 171,
    "question": "this is a [BLANK] needle electrode ",
    "answer": "Concentric | Context:  Beveled tip: Unidirectional recording 24- to 26-gauge needle (reference) with a bare inner wire Less interference ...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 265
  },
  {
    "id": 172,
    "question": "Monopolar needle advantages (PM&R) Records more {{c1:: positive sharp waves ( more abnormal activity in general) }} and larger [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "MUAP's | Context: record from entire area around needle tip as opposed to just fibers facing the bevel A ...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 266
  },
  {
    "id": 173,
    "question": "Concentric needle advantages less [BLANK]",
    "answer": "interference | Context: the needle serves also as the reference ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 267
  },
  {
    "id": 174,
    "question": " [BLANK]: results from {{c2::denervated}} muscle fibers that are {{c2::reinnervated}} by {{c3::collateral sprouting}} ",
    "answer": "complex repetetive discharge | Context:  from axons of a neighboring motor unit ETIOLOGY ( broad ddx ) Nerve disorders : Anterior horn cell disease, chronic radiculopathy, peripheral neuropathy Muscle disorders : Polymyositis, dermatomyosit...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 268
  },
  {
    "id": 175,
    "question": " {{c1::complex repetetive discharge::EMG wave form}}: results from [BLANK] muscle fibers that are [BLANK] by {{c3::collateral sprouting}} ",
    "answer": "denervated / reinnervated | Context:  from axons of a neighboring motor unit ETIOLOGY ( broad ddx ) Nerve disorders : Anterior horn cell disease, chronic radiculopathy, peripheral neuropathy Muscle disorders : Polymyositis, dermatomyosit...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 268
  },
  {
    "id": 176,
    "question": " {{c1::complex repetetive discharge::EMG wave form}}: results from {{c2::denervated}} muscle fibers that are {{c2::reinnervated}} by [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "collateral sprouting | Context:  from axons of a neighboring motor unit ETIOLOGY ( broad ddx ) Nerve disorders : Anterior horn cell disease, chronic radiculopathy, peripheral neuropathy Muscle disorders : Polymyositis, dermatomyosit...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 268
  },
  {
    "id": 177,
    "question": " [BLANK]: spontaneous discharges originating from the {{c2::motor neuron}} or its {{c2::axon}} prior to its terminal branches results in {{c4::intermittent::timing}} muscle fiber contraction If associated with {{c3::FIBs or PSWs}} , they are considered pathological ",
    "answer": "fasciculation",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 269
  },
  {
    "id": 178,
    "question": " {{c1::fasciculation}}: spontaneous discharges originating from the [BLANK] or its [BLANK] prior to its terminal branches results in {{c4::intermittent::timing}} muscle fiber contraction If associated with {{c3::FIBs or PSWs}} , they are considered pathological ",
    "answer": "motor neuron / axon",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 269
  },
  {
    "id": 179,
    "question": " {{c1::fasciculation}}: spontaneous discharges originating from the {{c2::motor neuron}} or its {{c2::axon}} prior to its terminal branches results in [BLANK] muscle fiber contraction If associated with {{c3::FIBs or PSWs}} , they are considered pathological ",
    "answer": "intermittent",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 269
  },
  {
    "id": 180,
    "question": "[BLANK] EMG finding are associated with {{c1::Anterior horn cell}} diseases (broad category)",
    "answer": "fasciculations | Context: assoc with ant. horn cell disease: Poliomyelitis, spinal muscular atrophy, amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and progressive muscular atrophy ETIOLOGY Nerve disorders : Anterior horn cell disease, tetany,...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 270
  },
  {
    "id": 181,
    "question": "{{c2::fasciculations}} EMG finding are associated with [BLANK] diseases (broad category)",
    "answer": "Anterior horn cell | Context: assoc with ant. horn cell disease: Poliomyelitis, spinal muscular atrophy, amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and progressive muscular atrophy ETIOLOGY Nerve disorders : Anterior horn cell disease, tetany,...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 270
  },
  {
    "id": 182,
    "question": " Radiculopathy (sensory vs motor) most commonly presents as: [BLANK] complaints, [BLANK] complaints, or [BLANK] complaints \"\"in descending order\"\" ",
    "answer": "pure sensory / sensori-motor / pure motor | Context:  as each dermatome is innervated by one spinal nerve root due to the larger size of the sensory fibers, rendering them more prone to injury ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 271
  },
  {
    "id": 183,
    "question": "Radiculopathy A pure sensory injury would demonstrate a [BLANK] EMG . ",
    "answer": "negative | Context:  Sensory NCS would be normal due to sparing of the DRG...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 273
  },
  {
    "id": 184,
    "question": "Unncommon Radiculopathy causes H —[BLANK] I —{{c2::Inflammatory::whole category}} M —{{c3::Metastasis}} A —{{c4::Arachnoiditis}} D —{{c5::Diabetes mellitus}} A —{{c6::Abscess}} M —{{c7::Mass}}",
    "answer": "Herpes zoster | Context: infalmmatory: Tuberculosis (TB), Lyme disease, HIV, syphilis, cryptococcus, and sarcoidosis Arachnoiditis: Myelogram, surgery, steroids, and anesthesia Mass in the spine: Meningioma, neurofibroma, leu...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 275
  },
  {
    "id": 185,
    "question": "Unncommon Radiculopathy causes H —{{c1::Herpes zoster}} I —[BLANK] M —{{c3::Metastasis}} A —{{c4::Arachnoiditis}} D —{{c5::Diabetes mellitus}} A —{{c6::Abscess}} M —{{c7::Mass}}",
    "answer": "Inflammatory | Context: infalmmatory: Tuberculosis (TB), Lyme disease, HIV, syphilis, cryptococcus, and sarcoidosis Arachnoiditis: Myelogram, surgery, steroids, and anesthesia Mass in the spine: Meningioma, neurofibroma, leu...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 275
  },
  {
    "id": 186,
    "question": "Unncommon Radiculopathy causes H —{{c1::Herpes zoster}} I —{{c2::Inflammatory::whole category}} M —[BLANK] A —{{c4::Arachnoiditis}} D —{{c5::Diabetes mellitus}} A —{{c6::Abscess}} M —{{c7::Mass}}",
    "answer": "Metastasis | Context: infalmmatory: Tuberculosis (TB), Lyme disease, HIV, syphilis, cryptococcus, and sarcoidosis Arachnoiditis: Myelogram, surgery, steroids, and anesthesia Mass in the spine: Meningioma, neurofibroma, leu...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 275
  },
  {
    "id": 187,
    "question": "Unncommon Radiculopathy causes H —{{c1::Herpes zoster}} I —{{c2::Inflammatory::whole category}} M —{{c3::Metastasis}} A —[BLANK] D —{{c5::Diabetes mellitus}} A —{{c6::Abscess}} M —{{c7::Mass}}",
    "answer": "Arachnoiditis | Context: infalmmatory: Tuberculosis (TB), Lyme disease, HIV, syphilis, cryptococcus, and sarcoidosis Arachnoiditis: Myelogram, surgery, steroids, and anesthesia Mass in the spine: Meningioma, neurofibroma, leu...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 275
  },
  {
    "id": 188,
    "question": "Unncommon Radiculopathy causes H —{{c1::Herpes zoster}} I —{{c2::Inflammatory::whole category}} M —{{c3::Metastasis}} A —{{c4::Arachnoiditis}} D —[BLANK] A —{{c6::Abscess}} M —{{c7::Mass}}",
    "answer": "Diabetes mellitus | Context: infalmmatory: Tuberculosis (TB), Lyme disease, HIV, syphilis, cryptococcus, and sarcoidosis Arachnoiditis: Myelogram, surgery, steroids, and anesthesia Mass in the spine: Meningioma, neurofibroma, leu...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 275
  },
  {
    "id": 189,
    "question": "Unncommon Radiculopathy causes H —{{c1::Herpes zoster}} I —{{c2::Inflammatory::whole category}} M —{{c3::Metastasis}} A —{{c4::Arachnoiditis}} D —{{c5::Diabetes mellitus}} A —[BLANK] M —{{c7::Mass}}",
    "answer": "Abscess | Context: infalmmatory: Tuberculosis (TB), Lyme disease, HIV, syphilis, cryptococcus, and sarcoidosis Arachnoiditis: Myelogram, surgery, steroids, and anesthesia Mass in the spine: Meningioma, neurofibroma, leu...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 275
  },
  {
    "id": 190,
    "question": "Unncommon Radiculopathy causes H —{{c1::Herpes zoster}} I —{{c2::Inflammatory::whole category}} M —{{c3::Metastasis}} A —{{c4::Arachnoiditis}} D —{{c5::Diabetes mellitus}} A —{{c6::Abscess}} M —[BLANK]",
    "answer": "Mass | Context: infalmmatory: Tuberculosis (TB), Lyme disease, HIV, syphilis, cryptococcus, and sarcoidosis Arachnoiditis: Myelogram, surgery, steroids, and anesthesia Mass in the spine: Meningioma, neurofibroma, leu...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 275
  },
  {
    "id": 191,
    "question": " role of NCS in Radiculopathy is to evaluate [BLANK] to explain the patient’s symptoms ",
    "answer": "superimposed pathology | Context: NCS portion of EDX studies are rarely abnormal in cases of radiculopathies ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 277
  },
  {
    "id": 192,
    "question": "Radiculopathy SNAP: Normal if the lesion is located [BLANK] to the DRG CMAP: Normal or reduced amplitude CMAP Amp: can be normal if the injury is... purely {{c2::demyelinating}} {{c2::incomplete}} or {{c2::reinnervation}} has already occurred (not snesory)",
    "answer": "proximal",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 278
  },
  {
    "id": 193,
    "question": "Radiculopathy SNAP: Normal if the lesion is located {{c1::proximal}} to the DRG CMAP: Normal or reduced amplitude CMAP Amp: can be normal if the injury is... purely [BLANK] [BLANK] or [BLANK] has already occurred (not snesory)",
    "answer": "demyelinating / incomplete / reinnervation",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 278
  },
  {
    "id": 194,
    "question": " H-reflex: Possibly abnormal in an [BLANK] radiculopathy but not pathognomonic ",
    "answer": "S1 | Context: primarily distinguishes L5 from S1 radic...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 279
  },
  {
    "id": 195,
    "question": " F-waves: [BLANK] sensitive / specific for a radiculopathy. ",
    "answer": "Not | Context:  Muscles have more than one root innervation, which can result in a normal latency ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 280
  },
  {
    "id": 196,
    "question": "EMG for Dx r adiculopathy Ideally, [BLANK] muscles ( [BLANK] peripheral muscles + {{c2::paraspinals}} ) should be evaluated ",
    "answer": "6 / 5 | Context:  if one of the six muscles is abnormal, then further muscles should be evaluated. A priority is placed on including weak muscles in the evaluation ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 282
  },
  {
    "id": 197,
    "question": "EMG for Dx r adiculopathy Ideally, {{c1::6}} muscles ( {{c1::5}} peripheral muscles + [BLANK] ) should be evaluated ",
    "answer": "paraspinals | Context:  if one of the six muscles is abnormal, then further muscles should be evaluated. A priority is placed on including weak muscles in the evaluation ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 282
  },
  {
    "id": 198,
    "question": " EMG Radiculopathy Dx Fibs and Sharps may NOT be found if: the lesion is: [BLANK] {{c2::pure sensory}} {{c3::chronic}} incomplete or missed by random sampling ",
    "answer": "demyelinating | Context: recall that fibs and sharps are assoc with axonal loss EMG evaluates muscle fibers; not sensory nerves nl. if reinnervation already occured...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 284
  },
  {
    "id": 199,
    "question": " EMG Radiculopathy Dx Fibs and Sharps may NOT be found if: the lesion is: {{c1::demyelinating}} [BLANK] {{c3::chronic}} incomplete or missed by random sampling ",
    "answer": "pure sensory | Context: recall that fibs and sharps are assoc with axonal loss EMG evaluates muscle fibers; not sensory nerves nl. if reinnervation already occured...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 284
  },
  {
    "id": 200,
    "question": " EMG Radiculopathy Dx Fibs and Sharps may NOT be found if: the lesion is: {{c1::demyelinating}} {{c2::pure sensory}} [BLANK] incomplete or missed by random sampling ",
    "answer": "chronic | Context: recall that fibs and sharps are assoc with axonal loss EMG evaluates muscle fibers; not sensory nerves nl. if reinnervation already occured...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 284
  },
  {
    "id": 201,
    "question": " Somatosensory Evoked Potential study evaluates [BLANK] responses of the nervous system to an {{c2::external stimulus}} . SSEP's represent the function of the {{c3::DCML}} pathway using afferent potentials ",
    "answer": "time-locked | Context:  theoretically evaluate the sensory component of the PNS and CNS . DX dz of CNS (brain, brainstem, spinal cord) as well as of dorsal nerve roots and peripheral nerves Abnormal results present immediat...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 285
  },
  {
    "id": 202,
    "question": " Somatosensory Evoked Potential study evaluates {{c1::time-locked}} responses of the nervous system to an [BLANK] . SSEP's represent the function of the {{c3::DCML}} pathway using afferent potentials ",
    "answer": "external stimulus | Context:  theoretically evaluate the sensory component of the PNS and CNS . DX dz of CNS (brain, brainstem, spinal cord) as well as of dorsal nerve roots and peripheral nerves Abnormal results present immediat...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 285
  },
  {
    "id": 203,
    "question": " Somatosensory Evoked Potential study evaluates {{c1::time-locked}} responses of the nervous system to an {{c2::external stimulus}} . SSEP's represent the function of the [BLANK] pathway using afferent potentials ",
    "answer": "DCML | Context:  theoretically evaluate the sensory component of the PNS and CNS . DX dz of CNS (brain, brainstem, spinal cord) as well as of dorsal nerve roots and peripheral nerves Abnormal results present immediat...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 285
  },
  {
    "id": 204,
    "question": " SSEP's initiated by a repetitive [BLANK] stimulation of a sensory nerve, mixed nerve, or dermatome, and is recorded from the {{c2::spine}} or {{c2::scalp}} ",
    "answer": "submaximal | Context:  theoretically evaluate the sensory component of the PNS and CNS . DX dz of CNS (brain, brainstem, spinal cord) as well as of dorsal nerve roots and peripheral nerves Abnormal results present immediat...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 286
  },
  {
    "id": 205,
    "question": " SSEP's initiated by a repetitive {{c1::submaximal::intensity}} stimulation of a sensory nerve, mixed nerve, or dermatome, and is recorded from the [BLANK] or [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "spine / scalp | Context:  theoretically evaluate the sensory component of the PNS and CNS . DX dz of CNS (brain, brainstem, spinal cord) as well as of dorsal nerve roots and peripheral nerves Abnormal results present immediat...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 286
  },
  {
    "id": 206,
    "question": " Somatosensory evoked potential ( SSEP ) monitors for problems such as (a) [BLANK] , (b) {{c2::CNS lesions (eg. MS) }} , or (c) {{c3::intraoperative monitoring (eg. spinal surgery)}} ",
    "answer": "peripheral nerve injuries | Context:  during spinal cord surgery, loss of tibial nerve potentials with preservation of median nerve potentials can indicate nerve injury at the level of intervention. Anesthesia will affect SSEP potentials...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 287
  },
  {
    "id": 207,
    "question": " Somatosensory evoked potential ( SSEP ) monitors for problems such as (a) {{c1::peripheral nerve injuries}} , (b) {{c2::CNS lesions (eg. MS) }} , or (c) [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "intraoperative monitoring (eg. spinal surgery) | Context:  during spinal cord surgery, loss of tibial nerve potentials with preservation of median nerve potentials can indicate nerve injury at the level of intervention. Anesthesia will affect SSEP potentials...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 287
  },
  {
    "id": 208,
    "question": "MS SSEP's are seen 90% of the time, with the lower limb more likely to be abnormal than the upper limb. most common abnormality is the prolonged [BLANK] . Amplitude reduction or absence can also be seen ",
    "answer": "interpeak latencies",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 288
  },
  {
    "id": 209,
    "question": " SSEP nerves most commonly used for testing are the [BLANK] for the upper limb and the [BLANK] nerve for the lower limb ",
    "answer": "median / tibial",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 289
  },
  {
    "id": 210,
    "question": "SSEP's [BLANK] considered useful for radiculopathies ",
    "answer": "are not | Context:  The long pathway monitored can mask focal lesions between the recording sites, and It monitors sensory pathways and proximal demyelinating injuries ...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 290
  },
  {
    "id": 211,
    "question": " Chronology of Electrodiagnostic Findings Time : [BLANK] days Abnormality : Decreased {{c2::recruitment}} Decreased {{c2::recruitment interval}} Prolonged {{c3::F-wave}} Abnormal {{c3::H-reflex}} ",
    "answer": "0 | Context:  TIME ABNORMALITY 0 Decreased recruitment Decreased recruitment interval Prolonged F wave Abnormal H-reflex (S1 radiculopathy) 4 days Decreased compound motor action potential amplitude (approximately...",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 291
  },
  {
    "id": 212,
    "question": " Chronology of Electrodiagnostic Findings Time : {{c1::0}} days Abnormality : Decreased [BLANK] Decreased [BLANK] Prolonged {{c3::F-wave}} Abnormal {{c3::H-reflex}} ",
    "answer": "recruitment / recruitment interval | Context:  TIME ABNORMALITY 0 Decreased recruitment Decreased recruitment interval Prolonged F wave Abnormal H-reflex (S1 radiculopathy) 4 days Decreased compound motor action potential amplitude (approximately...",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 291
  },
  {
    "id": 213,
    "question": " Chronology of Electrodiagnostic Findings Time : {{c1::0}} days Abnormality : Decreased {{c2::recruitment}} Decreased {{c2::recruitment interval}} Prolonged [BLANK] Abnormal [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "F-wave / H-reflex | Context:  TIME ABNORMALITY 0 Decreased recruitment Decreased recruitment interval Prolonged F wave Abnormal H-reflex (S1 radiculopathy) 4 days Decreased compound motor action potential amplitude (approximately...",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 291
  },
  {
    "id": 214,
    "question": " Chronology of Electrodiagnostic Findings Time: [BLANK] days Abnormality: Decreased {{c2::CMAP amplitude }} ",
    "answer": "4 | Context:  (approximately 50% compared to opposite side) in severe cases TIME ABNORMALITY 0 Decreased recruitment Decreased recruitment interval Prolonged F wave Abnormal H-reflex (S1 radiculopathy) 4 days Decr...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 292
  },
  {
    "id": 215,
    "question": " Chronology of Electrodiagnostic Findings Time: [BLANK] days Abnormality: {{c2::Abnormal spontaneous activity in the paraspinals::EMG finding and location}} ",
    "answer": "7 | Context:  They can be normal if: They become reinnervated The posterior primary rami are spared They can be the only abnormal finding 10%–30% of the time TIME ABNORMALITY 0 Decreased recruitment Decreased recr...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 293
  },
  {
    "id": 216,
    "question": " Chronology of Electrodiagnostic Findings Time: {{c1::7}} days Abnormality: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "Abnormal spontaneous activity in the paraspinals | Context:  They can be normal if: They become reinnervated The posterior primary rami are spared They can be the only abnormal finding 10%–30% of the time TIME ABNORMALITY 0 Decreased recruitment Decreased recr...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 293
  },
  {
    "id": 217,
    "question": " Chronology of Electrodiagnostic Findings Time: [BLANK] days Abnormality: {{c2::Abnormal spontaneous activity in the limbs::EMG finding and location}} ",
    "answer": "14 | Context:  TIME ABNORMALITY 0 Decreased recruitment Decreased recruitment interval Prolonged F wave Abnormal H-reflex (S1 radiculopathy) 4 days Decreased compound motor action potential amplitude (approximately...",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 294
  },
  {
    "id": 218,
    "question": " Chronology of Electrodiagnostic Findings Time: {{c1::14}} days Abnormality: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "Abnormal spontaneous activity in the limbs | Context:  TIME ABNORMALITY 0 Decreased recruitment Decreased recruitment interval Prolonged F wave Abnormal H-reflex (S1 radiculopathy) 4 days Decreased compound motor action potential amplitude (approximately...",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 294
  },
  {
    "id": 219,
    "question": " Chronology of Electrodiagnostic Findings Time: [BLANK] days Abnormality: {{c1::Abnormal activity present in both the paraspinals and limbs::EMG finding and llocation}} ",
    "answer": "21 | Context:  TIME ABNORMALITY 0 Decreased recruitment Decreased recruitment interval Prolonged F wave Abnormal H-reflex (S1 radiculopathy) 4 days Decreased compound motor action potential amplitude (approximately...",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 295
  },
  {
    "id": 220,
    "question": " Chronology of Electrodiagnostic Findings Time: {{c2::21}} days Abnormality: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "Abnormal activity present in both the paraspinals and limbs | Context:  TIME ABNORMALITY 0 Decreased recruitment Decreased recruitment interval Prolonged F wave Abnormal H-reflex (S1 radiculopathy) 4 days Decreased compound motor action potential amplitude (approximately...",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 295
  },
  {
    "id": 221,
    "question": " Chronology of Electrodiagnostic Findings Time: {{c1:: 5–6 weeks::2 #'s }} Abnormality: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "Reinnervation begins / polyphasic | Context:  TIME ABNORMALITY 0 Decreased recruitment Decreased recruitment interval Prolonged F wave Abnormal H-reflex (S1 radiculopathy) 4 days Decreased compound motor action potential amplitude (approximately...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 296
  },
  {
    "id": 222,
    "question": " Chronology of Electrodiagnostic Findings Time: {{c1:: 6 months to 1 year::2 #'s }} Abnormality: {{c2::I ncreased amplitude from reinnervated motor unit }} ",
    "answer": " Reinnervation complete TIME ABNORMALITY 0 Decreased recruitment Decreased recruitment interval Prolonged F wave Abnormal H-reflex (S1 radiculopathy) 4 days Decreased compound motor action potential amplitude (approximately 50% compared to opposite side) in severe cases 1 week Abnormal spontaneous activity occurs first in the paraspinals They can be normal if: They become reinnervated The posterio",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Standard",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 297
  },
  {
    "id": 223,
    "question": "Etiologies Demeylinating Injury [BLANK] causing a transient ischemia or edema with {{c2::paranodal intussusceptions}} Chronic diseases causing degradation of myelin leading to {{c3::peripheral neuropathies}}",
    "answer": "Focal compression | Context: myelin invaginations ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 298
  },
  {
    "id": 224,
    "question": "Etiologies Demeylinating Injury {{c1::Focal compression}} causing a transient ischemia or edema with [BLANK] Chronic diseases causing degradation of myelin leading to {{c3::peripheral neuropathies}}",
    "answer": "paranodal intussusceptions | Context: myelin invaginations ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 298
  },
  {
    "id": 225,
    "question": "Etiologies Demeylinating Injury {{c1::Focal compression}} causing a transient ischemia or edema with {{c2::paranodal intussusceptions}} Chronic diseases causing degradation of myelin leading to [BLANK]",
    "answer": "peripheral neuropathies | Context: myelin invaginations ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 298
  },
  {
    "id": 226,
    "question": " NCS of demeylinating injuries Latency is typicaly [BLANK] and Amplitude is typically [BLANK]",
    "answer": "prolonged / normal | Context:  NCS Latency: Prolonged Conduction velocity: Decreased Temporal dispersion: Increased Amplitude: May decrease secondary to temporal dispersion and phase cancellation Amplitude caveat : may be decrease...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 299
  },
  {
    "id": 227,
    "question": " Radiculopathy In general, CMAP in NCS will be normal * However, in a [BLANK] lesion it may be affected ",
    "answer": "severe radicular | Context: (will be distal to the anterior horn cell) axonal loss can result in Wallerian degeneration focal demeylination would cuase a conduction block only text book answer: in clinical practice it is often a...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 520
  },
  {
    "id": 228,
    "question": "EMG findings are usually negative in peripheral neuropathy, unless there is an [BLANK]",
    "answer": "axonal motor neuropathy | Context: In such cases (usually late stage), affected muscles may demonstrate spontaneous activity EMG testing is helpful, even when negative, as it helps to rule out other disorders, such as a focal neuropath...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 610
  },
  {
    "id": 229,
    "question": "In axonal injury you will see a decrease in CMAP amplitude with stimulation [BLANK] to the lesion latencies/CV will be {{c2::normal*::abnormal/normal}} {{c3::+::+/-}} EMG findings ",
    "answer": "both Distal &amp; Proximal | Context:  latency* : if the fastest fibers are affected, may be abnormal ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 653
  },
  {
    "id": 230,
    "question": "In axonal injury you will see a decrease in CMAP amplitude with stimulation {{c1::both Distal & Proximal::distal or proximal}} to the lesion latencies/CV will be [BLANK] {{c3::+::+/-}} EMG findings ",
    "answer": "normal* | Context:  latency* : if the fastest fibers are affected, may be abnormal ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 653
  },
  {
    "id": 231,
    "question": "In axonal injury you will see a decrease in CMAP amplitude with stimulation {{c1::both Distal & Proximal::distal or proximal}} to the lesion latencies/CV will be {{c2::normal*::abnormal/normal}} [BLANK] EMG findings ",
    "answer": "+ | Context:  latency* : if the fastest fibers are affected, may be abnormal ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 653
  },
  {
    "id": 232,
    "question": "In conduction block you will see a decrease in CMAP amplitude with stimulation [BLANK] to the lesion drop in amp {{c2::20-50::2 # range}}% ",
    "answer": "proximal",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 654
  },
  {
    "id": 233,
    "question": "In conduction block you will see a decrease in CMAP amplitude with stimulation {{c1::proximal::distal or proximal}} to the lesion drop in amp [BLANK]% ",
    "answer": "20-50",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 654
  },
  {
    "id": 234,
    "question": " Pure axonal injury Etiology : (a) focal crush (b) [BLANK] (c) {{c2::transection}} (d) {{c3::peripheral neuropathies}} NCS latency and CV will be {{c1::normal:: abdnormal/ normal }} EMG activity will be {{c1::abdnormal:: abdnormal/ normal }} ",
    "answer": "stretch (traction) | Context:  NCS Amplitude: Decreased CV and latency: Mild slowing of both may occur if the largest and fastest conducting axons are lost *radiculopathy may pres this way ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 655
  },
  {
    "id": 235,
    "question": " Pure axonal injury Etiology : (a) focal crush (b) {{c4::stretch (traction)}} (c) [BLANK] (d) {{c3::peripheral neuropathies}} NCS latency and CV will be {{c1::normal:: abdnormal/ normal }} EMG activity will be {{c1::abdnormal:: abdnormal/ normal }} ",
    "answer": "transection | Context:  NCS Amplitude: Decreased CV and latency: Mild slowing of both may occur if the largest and fastest conducting axons are lost *radiculopathy may pres this way ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 655
  },
  {
    "id": 236,
    "question": " Pure axonal injury Etiology : (a) focal crush (b) {{c4::stretch (traction)}} (c) {{c2::transection}} (d) [BLANK] NCS latency and CV will be {{c1::normal:: abdnormal/ normal }} EMG activity will be {{c1::abdnormal:: abdnormal/ normal }} ",
    "answer": "peripheral neuropathies | Context:  NCS Amplitude: Decreased CV and latency: Mild slowing of both may occur if the largest and fastest conducting axons are lost *radiculopathy may pres this way ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 655
  },
  {
    "id": 237,
    "question": " Pure axonal injury Etiology : (a) focal crush (b) {{c4::stretch (traction)}} (c) {{c2::transection}} (d) {{c3::peripheral neuropathies}} NCS latency and CV will be [BLANK] EMG activity will be [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "normal / abdnormal | Context:  NCS Amplitude: Decreased CV and latency: Mild slowing of both may occur if the largest and fastest conducting axons are lost *radiculopathy may pres this way ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 655
  },
  {
    "id": 238,
    "question": "Abnormal spontaneous activity from muscle fibers includes: [BLANK] [BLANK] {{c2::Complex repetitive discharges}} {{c3::Myotonic discharges}}",
    "answer": "FIBs / PSWs",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 656
  },
  {
    "id": 239,
    "question": "Abnormal spontaneous activity from muscle fibers includes: {{c1::FIBs}} {{c1::PSWs}} [BLANK] {{c3::Myotonic discharges}}",
    "answer": "Complex repetitive discharges",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 656
  },
  {
    "id": 240,
    "question": "Abnormal spontaneous activity from muscle fibers includes: {{c1::FIBs}} {{c1::PSWs}} {{c2::Complex repetitive discharges}} [BLANK]",
    "answer": "Myotonic discharges",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 656
  },
  {
    "id": 241,
    "question": "Abnormal spontaneous activity from a motor neuron/axon includes: [BLANK] {{c2::Myokymic discharges}} {{c3::Neuromyotonic discharges}} {{c4::Cramp discharge}}",
    "answer": "Fasciculation potentials* | Context:  *maybe both (Easy EMG) ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 657
  },
  {
    "id": 242,
    "question": "Abnormal spontaneous activity from a motor neuron/axon includes: {{c1::Fasciculation potentials*}} [BLANK] {{c3::Neuromyotonic discharges}} {{c4::Cramp discharge}}",
    "answer": "Myokymic discharges | Context:  *maybe both (Easy EMG) ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 657
  },
  {
    "id": 243,
    "question": "Abnormal spontaneous activity from a motor neuron/axon includes: {{c1::Fasciculation potentials*}} {{c2::Myokymic discharges}} [BLANK] {{c4::Cramp discharge}}",
    "answer": "Neuromyotonic discharges | Context:  *maybe both (Easy EMG) ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 657
  },
  {
    "id": 244,
    "question": "Abnormal spontaneous activity from a motor neuron/axon includes: {{c1::Fasciculation potentials*}} {{c2::Myokymic discharges}} {{c3::Neuromyotonic discharges}} [BLANK]",
    "answer": "Cramp discharge | Context:  *maybe both (Easy EMG) ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 657
  },
  {
    "id": 245,
    "question": "AIN branches from the median nerve innervate (3 P's): [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK]",
    "answer": "Flexor digitorum <u>profundus</u> (FDP&nbsp;1 and 2) / Flexor <u>pollicis</u> longus (FPL) / <u>Pronator</u> quadratus (PQ)",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 675
  },
  {
    "id": 246,
    "question": "through the carpal tunnel , the median n. innervates 4 muscles, +1 cutaneous [BLANK] {{c2::Opponens pollicis}} {{c3::Abductor pollicis brevis}} {{c4::Flexor pollicis brevis (superficial)}} {{c5::Digital cutaneous branches}}",
    "answer": "Lumbricals (1, 2)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 676
  },
  {
    "id": 247,
    "question": "through the carpal tunnel , the median n. innervates 4 muscles, +1 cutaneous {{c1::Lumbricals (1, 2)}} [BLANK] {{c3::Abductor pollicis brevis}} {{c4::Flexor pollicis brevis (superficial)}} {{c5::Digital cutaneous branches}}",
    "answer": "Opponens pollicis",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 676
  },
  {
    "id": 248,
    "question": "through the carpal tunnel , the median n. innervates 4 muscles, +1 cutaneous {{c1::Lumbricals (1, 2)}} {{c2::Opponens pollicis}} [BLANK] {{c4::Flexor pollicis brevis (superficial)}} {{c5::Digital cutaneous branches}}",
    "answer": "Abductor pollicis brevis",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 676
  },
  {
    "id": 249,
    "question": "through the carpal tunnel , the median n. innervates 4 muscles, +1 cutaneous {{c1::Lumbricals (1, 2)}} {{c2::Opponens pollicis}} {{c3::Abductor pollicis brevis}} [BLANK] {{c5::Digital cutaneous branches}}",
    "answer": "Flexor pollicis brevis (superficial)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 676
  },
  {
    "id": 250,
    "question": "through the carpal tunnel , the median n. innervates 4 muscles, +1 cutaneous {{c1::Lumbricals (1, 2)}} {{c2::Opponens pollicis}} {{c3::Abductor pollicis brevis}} {{c4::Flexor pollicis brevis (superficial)}} [BLANK]",
    "answer": "Digital cutaneous branches",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 676
  },
  {
    "id": 251,
    "question": " Median n. Course : runs medial to the [BLANK] in the distal upper arm continues down the humerus and runs under the {{c2::ligament of Struthers}} at the medial epicondyle the {{c3::antebrachial fascia}} overlies the nerve in the proximal forearm nerve then passes between the {{c4:: two heads of the PT}} muscle and continues down under the {{c5::FDS muscle }} ",
    "answer": "brachial a.",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 677
  },
  {
    "id": 252,
    "question": " Median n. Course : runs medial to the {{c1::brachial a.}} in the distal upper arm continues down the humerus and runs under the [BLANK] at the medial epicondyle the {{c3::antebrachial fascia}} overlies the nerve in the proximal forearm nerve then passes between the {{c4:: two heads of the PT}} muscle and continues down under the {{c5::FDS muscle }} ",
    "answer": "ligament of Struthers",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 677
  },
  {
    "id": 253,
    "question": " Median n. Course : runs medial to the {{c1::brachial a.}} in the distal upper arm continues down the humerus and runs under the {{c2::ligament of Struthers}} at the medial epicondyle the [BLANK] overlies the nerve in the proximal forearm nerve then passes between the {{c4:: two heads of the PT}} muscle and continues down under the {{c5::FDS muscle }} ",
    "answer": "antebrachial fascia",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 677
  },
  {
    "id": 254,
    "question": "[BLANK] : 2 cm bone spur 3 to 6 cm proximal to the medial epicondyle. It is connected to the epicondyle by a ligament in 1% of the population ",
    "answer": "LIGAMENT OF STRUTHER",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 678
  },
  {
    "id": 255,
    "question": " Ligament of Struthers EDX findings : NCS: Abnormal median [BLANK] {{c4::conduction velocity (onset) / or conduction block (amp)::2 NCS paramaters}} at {{c3::above elbow}} site EMG: Abnormal in which median nerve-innervated muscles: {{c2::All (including the PT)}} ",
    "answer": "SNAP&nbsp;and&nbsp;CMAP | Context:  wether SNAP or CMAP is affected depends on the severity of lesion (not type) median nerve does not innervate any upper-arm muscles this is the most proximal innervation tx is rehab or surgery release...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 679
  },
  {
    "id": 256,
    "question": " Ligament of Struthers EDX findings : NCS: Abnormal median {{c1::SNAP and CMAP::2 NCS tests}} [BLANK] at {{c3::above elbow}} site EMG: Abnormal in which median nerve-innervated muscles: {{c2::All (including the PT)}} ",
    "answer": "conduction velocity (onset) / or conduction block (amp) | Context:  wether SNAP or CMAP is affected depends on the severity of lesion (not type) median nerve does not innervate any upper-arm muscles this is the most proximal innervation tx is rehab or surgery release...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 679
  },
  {
    "id": 257,
    "question": " Ligament of Struthers EDX findings : NCS: Abnormal median {{c1::SNAP and CMAP::2 NCS tests}} {{c4::conduction velocity (onset) / or conduction block (amp)::2 NCS paramaters}} at [BLANK] site EMG: Abnormal in which median nerve-innervated muscles: {{c2::All (including the PT)}} ",
    "answer": "above elbow | Context:  wether SNAP or CMAP is affected depends on the severity of lesion (not type) median nerve does not innervate any upper-arm muscles this is the most proximal innervation tx is rehab or surgery release...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 679
  },
  {
    "id": 258,
    "question": " Ligament of Struthers EDX findings : NCS: Abnormal median {{c1::SNAP and CMAP::2 NCS tests}} {{c4::conduction velocity (onset) / or conduction block (amp)::2 NCS paramaters}} at {{c3::above elbow}} site EMG: Abnormal in which median nerve-innervated muscles: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "All (including the&nbsp;PT) | Context:  wether SNAP or CMAP is affected depends on the severity of lesion (not type) median nerve does not innervate any upper-arm muscles this is the most proximal innervation tx is rehab or surgery release...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 679
  },
  {
    "id": 259,
    "question": " bicipital aponeurosis median n. can be injured by entrapment or hematoma compression resulting from an [BLANK] EDX pres: similar to the {{c1::LOS}} ",
    "answer": "ABG / venipuncture",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 680
  },
  {
    "id": 260,
    "question": " bicipital aponeurosis median n. can be injured by entrapment or hematoma compression resulting from an {{c2::ABG / venipuncture::2}} EDX pres: similar to the [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "LOS",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 680
  },
  {
    "id": 261,
    "question": "General Rule of Thumb An entrapment mononeuropathy: is commonly named for the muscle compressing the nerve. That muscle is usually [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "unaffected | Context:  because it receives its innervation before it is pierced by the nerve. However, the nerve can also contribute to the innervations as it courses through the muscle ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 681
  },
  {
    "id": 262,
    "question": "Pronator Teres Syndrome EDX findings: NCS: Abnormal [BLANK] SNAPs Abnormal CMAPs at [BLANK] EMG: Abnormal activity in which median n. muscles: {{c1::All EXCEPT the PT*}}",
    "answer": "median nerve* / above elbow site | Context:  Wrist site will be normal *SNAP may be affected (CMAP o/l > SNAP o/l) Often normal snap with abnl CMAP amp and o/l ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 682
  },
  {
    "id": 263,
    "question": "Pronator Teres Syndrome EDX findings: NCS: Abnormal {{c2::median nerve*}} SNAPs Abnormal CMAPs at {{c2::above elbow site::in conduction block}} EMG: Abnormal activity in which median n. muscles: [BLANK]",
    "answer": "All EXCEPT the&nbsp;PT* | Context:  Wrist site will be normal *SNAP may be affected (CMAP o/l > SNAP o/l) Often normal snap with abnl CMAP amp and o/l ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 682
  },
  {
    "id": 264,
    "question": " Anterior interosseous syndrome Phys-Ex finding pt may demonstrate a positive {{c1:: “ OK ” }} sign or Inability to [BLANK] Sensation is {{c2::spared}} ",
    "answer": "make a fist | Context:  inability to flex the thumb and index DIP joint ( FPL , FDP weakness). Inability to make a fist due to problems incorporating the thumb and index finger AIN is pure motor (save for wrist joint) (A) N...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 683
  },
  {
    "id": 265,
    "question": " Anterior interosseous syndrome Phys-Ex finding pt may demonstrate a positive {{c1:: “ OK ” }} sign or Inability to {{c3::make a fist}} Sensation is [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "spared | Context:  inability to flex the thumb and index DIP joint ( FPL , FDP weakness). Inability to make a fist due to problems incorporating the thumb and index finger AIN is pure motor (save for wrist joint) (A) N...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 683
  },
  {
    "id": 266,
    "question": "[BLANK]% of people with clinical carpal tunnel syndrome (CTS) can have a normal EDX study",
    "answer": "10 | Context: EDX abnormality alone should not establish the diagnosis, clinical syndrome in which nerve damage is coupled with abnormal sensations and pain. It can involve the first, second, third, and 1/2 of the ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 689
  },
  {
    "id": 267,
    "question": "[BLANK] from concomitant DMT2 or cervical radiculopathy increases the risk of CTS ",
    "answer": "Double crush syndrome",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 690
  },
  {
    "id": 268,
    "question": " CTS clinical pres Sensation is abnormal to the lateral 3–1/2 fingers of the hand except at the [BLANK] . Muscle weakness can be noted which muscles: {{c1::“LOAF”}} ",
    "answer": "base of the thumb | Context:  ( L umbricals 1 and 2, O pponens pollicis, A bductor pollicis brevis, and F lexor pollicis brevis ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 691
  },
  {
    "id": 269,
    "question": " CTS clinical pres Sensation is abnormal to the lateral 3–1/2 fingers of the hand except at the {{c2::base of the thumb}} . Muscle weakness can be noted which muscles: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "“LOAF” | Context:  ( L umbricals 1 and 2, O pponens pollicis, A bductor pollicis brevis, and F lexor pollicis brevis ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 691
  },
  {
    "id": 270,
    "question": "CTS E DX findings [BLANK] studies are more sensitive because larger fibers are more affected than the slightly smaller fibers ",
    "answer": "Sensory | Context: Antidromic sensory studies are typically performed and offer the advantage of producing larger amplitudes and are more commonly practiced ...",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 692
  },
  {
    "id": 271,
    "question": " median NCSs demyelinating lesion at the carpal tunnel results in {{c1:: prolonged distal latencies }} of both motor and sensory if demyelination caused conduction block or axonal loss , the distal CMAP and SNAP [BLANK] will be decreased ",
    "answer": "amplitudes",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 693
  },
  {
    "id": 272,
    "question": "CTS EDX study The study of [BLANK] of the median nerve is helpful in distinguishing CTS from {{c2::peripheral neuropathy}} ",
    "answer": "distal segments | Context:  in CTS , the maximal slowing is across the wrist whereas, in peripheral neuropathy, the distal segment is more abnormal ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 694
  },
  {
    "id": 273,
    "question": "CTS EDX study The study of {{c1::distal segments}} of the median nerve is helpful in distinguishing CTS from [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "peripheral neuropathy | Context:  in CTS , the maximal slowing is across the wrist whereas, in peripheral neuropathy, the distal segment is more abnormal ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 694
  },
  {
    "id": 274,
    "question": " If CTS patient has normal \"\"routine\"\" median nerve conduction studies (NCS); further testing is performed using more sensitive NCSs known as [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "comparison studies (ie. median to ulnar) | Context:  \"\"bobby uses radial as ulnar often has pathology\"\" ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 695
  },
  {
    "id": 275,
    "question": " median-versus-ulnar comparison tests a difference of > [BLANK] msec is considered abnormal ",
    "answer": "0.5",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 696
  },
  {
    "id": 276,
    "question": " CTS SEVERITY NCS [BLANK] SNAP: Prolonged latency plus decreased amplitude CMAP: Prolonged latency ",
    "answer": "Moderate",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 697
  },
  {
    "id": 277,
    "question": " CTS SEVERITY NCS [BLANK] SNAP: Prolonged latency CMAP: Normal ",
    "answer": "Mild",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 698
  },
  {
    "id": 278,
    "question": " CTS SEVERITY NCS [BLANK] SNAP: Absent CMAP: Prolonged latency and decr. Amplitude ",
    "answer": "Severe",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 699
  },
  {
    "id": 279,
    "question": " CTS etiology obesity diabetes [BLANK] {{c2::RA tenosynovitis}} {{c3::CHF}} {{c4::renal failure}} {{c5::mass (tumor, hematoma)}} {{c6::pregnancy}} ",
    "answer": "thyroid disease | Context: volume overload or space occupying canal narrowing etc....",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 703
  },
  {
    "id": 280,
    "question": " CTS etiology obesity diabetes {{c1::thyroid disease}} [BLANK] {{c3::CHF}} {{c4::renal failure}} {{c5::mass (tumor, hematoma)}} {{c6::pregnancy}} ",
    "answer": "RA tenosynovitis | Context: volume overload or space occupying canal narrowing etc....",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 703
  },
  {
    "id": 281,
    "question": " CTS etiology obesity diabetes {{c1::thyroid disease}} {{c2::RA tenosynovitis}} [BLANK] {{c4::renal failure}} {{c5::mass (tumor, hematoma)}} {{c6::pregnancy}} ",
    "answer": "CHF | Context: volume overload or space occupying canal narrowing etc....",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 703
  },
  {
    "id": 282,
    "question": " CTS etiology obesity diabetes {{c1::thyroid disease}} {{c2::RA tenosynovitis}} {{c3::CHF}} [BLANK] {{c5::mass (tumor, hematoma)}} {{c6::pregnancy}} ",
    "answer": "renal failure | Context: volume overload or space occupying canal narrowing etc....",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 703
  },
  {
    "id": 283,
    "question": " CTS etiology obesity diabetes {{c1::thyroid disease}} {{c2::RA tenosynovitis}} {{c3::CHF}} {{c4::renal failure}} [BLANK] {{c6::pregnancy}} ",
    "answer": "mass (tumor, hematoma) | Context: volume overload or space occupying canal narrowing etc....",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 703
  },
  {
    "id": 284,
    "question": " CTS etiology obesity diabetes {{c1::thyroid disease}} {{c2::RA tenosynovitis}} {{c3::CHF}} {{c4::renal failure}} {{c5::mass (tumor, hematoma)}} [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "pregnancy | Context: volume overload or space occupying canal narrowing etc....",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 703
  },
  {
    "id": 285,
    "question": "CTS treatments (conserative) [BLANK] {{c2::hand splint}} {{c3::NSAIDs}} {{c4::steroid injection}} {{c5::diuretics}} {{c6::vitamin B6}}",
    "answer": "Ergonomic modification",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 704
  },
  {
    "id": 286,
    "question": "CTS treatments (conserative) {{c1::Ergonomic modification}} [BLANK] {{c3::NSAIDs}} {{c4::steroid injection}} {{c5::diuretics}} {{c6::vitamin B6}}",
    "answer": "hand splint",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 704
  },
  {
    "id": 287,
    "question": "CTS treatments (conserative) {{c1::Ergonomic modification}} {{c2::hand splint}} [BLANK] {{c4::steroid injection}} {{c5::diuretics}} {{c6::vitamin B6}}",
    "answer": "NSAIDs",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 704
  },
  {
    "id": 288,
    "question": "CTS treatments (conserative) {{c1::Ergonomic modification}} {{c2::hand splint}} {{c3::NSAIDs}} [BLANK] {{c5::diuretics}} {{c6::vitamin B6}}",
    "answer": "steroid injection",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 704
  },
  {
    "id": 289,
    "question": "CTS treatments (conserative) {{c1::Ergonomic modification}} {{c2::hand splint}} {{c3::NSAIDs}} {{c4::steroid injection}} [BLANK] {{c6::vitamin B6}}",
    "answer": "diuretics",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 704
  },
  {
    "id": 290,
    "question": "CTS treatments (conserative) {{c1::Ergonomic modification}} {{c2::hand splint}} {{c3::NSAIDs}} {{c4::steroid injection}} {{c5::diuretics}} [BLANK]",
    "answer": "vitamin B6",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 704
  },
  {
    "id": 291,
    "question": " CTS treatment Orthotics: Hand splint neutral to [BLANK] -degree extension ",
    "answer": "30",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 705
  },
  {
    "id": 292,
    "question": " CTS Poor outcome with conservative management may occur with... Symptoms >[BLANK] months in duration Positive Phalen’s test in <[BLANK] seconds any {{c2::mod-severe clinical sx's}} any {{c2::mod-severe EDX findings}} ",
    "answer": "10 / 10 | Context: any mod-severe sx's: Constant paresthesias, Weakness, atrophy any mod-severe EDX findings Marked prolonged latency on NCS Abnormal spontaneous activity on EMG...",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 707
  },
  {
    "id": 293,
    "question": " CTS Poor outcome with conservative management may occur with... Symptoms >{{c1::10 }} months in duration Positive Phalen’s test in <{{c1::10}} seconds any [BLANK] any [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "mod-severe clinical sx's / mod-severe EDX findings | Context: any mod-severe sx's: Constant paresthesias, Weakness, atrophy any mod-severe EDX findings Marked prolonged latency on NCS Abnormal spontaneous activity on EMG...",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 707
  },
  {
    "id": 294,
    "question": " NCS of demeylinating injuries Amplitude typically normal : but may be decreased due to... [BLANK] and [BLANK] or [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "temporal dispersion / phase-cancellation / conduction block | Context:  demeylinating EDx findings ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 726
  },
  {
    "id": 295,
    "question": " in MGA An initial [BLANK] deflection of the median nerve CMAP at {{c2::elbow}} is seen, which is not seen at the {{c2::wrist}}. Only seen with concomitant {{c3::CTS}} ",
    "answer": "positive | Context:  due to the proximal stimulus to ulnar nerve/muscles through the anastomosis reaching the recording electrode via volume conduction before the potential from the median nerve as a result of the median...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 763
  },
  {
    "id": 296,
    "question": " in MGA An initial {{c1::positive}} deflection of the median nerve CMAP at [BLANK] is seen, which is not seen at the [BLANK]. Only seen with concomitant {{c3::CTS}} ",
    "answer": "elbow / wrist | Context:  due to the proximal stimulus to ulnar nerve/muscles through the anastomosis reaching the recording electrode via volume conduction before the potential from the median nerve as a result of the median...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 763
  },
  {
    "id": 297,
    "question": " in MGA An initial {{c1::positive}} deflection of the median nerve CMAP at {{c2::elbow}} is seen, which is not seen at the {{c2::wrist}}. Only seen with concomitant [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "CTS | Context:  due to the proximal stimulus to ulnar nerve/muscles through the anastomosis reaching the recording electrode via volume conduction before the potential from the median nerve as a result of the median...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 763
  },
  {
    "id": 298,
    "question": " In MGA one can see an artificially {{c1:: fast CV::increased/decreased, parameter}} this is 2/2 an unreasonably small [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "latency difference",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 764
  },
  {
    "id": 299,
    "question": "[BLANK] connection of the {{c2::recurrent branch of the::specific part}} median nerve to the {{c2::deep motor branch of the::specific part}} ulnar nerve ",
    "answer": "RICHE-CANNIEU ANASTOMOSIS",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 769
  },
  {
    "id": 300,
    "question": "{{c1::RICHE-CANNIEU ANASTOMOSIS}} connection of the [BLANK] median nerve to the [BLANK] ulnar nerve ",
    "answer": "recurrent branch of the / deep motor branch of the",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 769
  },
  {
    "id": 301,
    "question": " Riche-cannieu While recording over the APB muscle, CMAP is absent with [BLANK] nerve stimulation but present with stimulation of the [BLANK] nerve ",
    "answer": "median / ulnar",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 770
  },
  {
    "id": 302,
    "question": " through Guyon’s canal , Ulnar n . splits into 3 branches 1. [BLANK] 2. [BLANK] 3. [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "Superficial sensory branch / Hypothenar branch / Deep motor branch",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 797
  },
  {
    "id": 303,
    "question": "Ulnar N Hypothenar branch innervated 3 muscles [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK]",
    "answer": "Opponens digiti quinti / Abductor digiti quinti / Flexor digiti quinti",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 798
  },
  {
    "id": 304,
    "question": "Ulnar N. Deep motor branch innervates m. : [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK]",
    "answer": "Flexor pollicis brevis (deep head) / Adductor pollicis / Interossei (Palmar and Dorsal) / Lumbricals (4th &amp; 5th) | Context: Palmaris brevis, not testable ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 799
  },
  {
    "id": 305,
    "question": " The Ulnar n. aka \"\"1-1/2\"\" Nerve 1-1/2 muscle of the forearm [BLANK] [BLANK] 1-1/2 muscles of the thumb {{c2::1 Adductor pollicis}} {{c2::1/2 Flexor pollicis brevis (deep head)}} 1-1/2 muscle class of the palm* {{c3::1 Interosse (all)}} {{c3::1/2 lumbricals (3, 4)}} ",
    "answer": "1 Flexor carpi ulnaris / 1/2 Flexor digitorum profundus (3, 4) | Context:  1-1/2 muscles of the thumb 1 Adductor pollicis 1/2 Flexor pollicis brevis (deep head) 1-1/2 muscle of the forearm 1 Flexor carpi ulnaris 1/2 Flexor digitorum profundus (3, 4) 1-1/2 sensation of the f...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 800
  },
  {
    "id": 306,
    "question": " The Ulnar n. aka \"\"1-1/2\"\" Nerve 1-1/2 muscle of the forearm {{c1::1 Flexor carpi ulnaris}} {{c1::1/2 Flexor digitorum profundus (3, 4)}} 1-1/2 muscles of the thumb [BLANK] [BLANK] 1-1/2 muscle class of the palm* {{c3::1 Interosse (all)}} {{c3::1/2 lumbricals (3, 4)}} ",
    "answer": "1 Adductor pollicis / 1/2 Flexor pollicis brevis (deep head) | Context:  1-1/2 muscles of the thumb 1 Adductor pollicis 1/2 Flexor pollicis brevis (deep head) 1-1/2 muscle of the forearm 1 Flexor carpi ulnaris 1/2 Flexor digitorum profundus (3, 4) 1-1/2 sensation of the f...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 800
  },
  {
    "id": 307,
    "question": " The Ulnar n. aka \"\"1-1/2\"\" Nerve 1-1/2 muscle of the forearm {{c1::1 Flexor carpi ulnaris}} {{c1::1/2 Flexor digitorum profundus (3, 4)}} 1-1/2 muscles of the thumb {{c2::1 Adductor pollicis}} {{c2::1/2 Flexor pollicis brevis (deep head)}} 1-1/2 muscle class of the palm* [BLANK] [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "1 Interosse (all) / 1/2 lumbricals<strong>&nbsp;</strong> (3, 4) | Context:  1-1/2 muscles of the thumb 1 Adductor pollicis 1/2 Flexor pollicis brevis (deep head) 1-1/2 muscle of the forearm 1 Flexor carpi ulnaris 1/2 Flexor digitorum profundus (3, 4) 1-1/2 sensation of the f...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 800
  },
  {
    "id": 308,
    "question": "{{c1:: Dorsal ulnar cutaneous ( DUC ) }} nerve: arising 8 cm proximal to [BLANK]",
    "answer": "Guyon’s canal",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 810
  },
  {
    "id": 309,
    "question": " Dorsal ulnar cutaneous ( DUC ) nerve: normal or abnormal NCS are [BLANK] in a handle-bar neuropathy at the wrist but [BLANK] in more proximal compressions ie. CUTS ",
    "answer": "normal / abnormal | Context:  If severe! the more common picure is Focal nerve slowing w/ nl. SNAPS ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 811
  },
  {
    "id": 310,
    "question": " [BLANK]: fascial band in the medial arm that connects the {{c4::brachialis}} to the {{c4::triceps brachii-medial}} pt demonstrates involvement of {{c2:: all ulnar nerve innervated muscles and sensory }} Phys-ex: Wrist flexion may result in {{c3::radial deviation}} ",
    "answer": "ARCADE OF STRUTHERS | Context:  deviation 2/2 FCU weakness ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 812
  },
  {
    "id": 311,
    "question": " {{c1::ARCADE OF STRUTHERS}}: fascial band in the medial arm that connects the [BLANK] to the [BLANK] pt demonstrates involvement of {{c2:: all ulnar nerve innervated muscles and sensory }} Phys-ex: Wrist flexion may result in {{c3::radial deviation}} ",
    "answer": "brachialis / triceps brachii-medial | Context:  deviation 2/2 FCU weakness ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 812
  },
  {
    "id": 312,
    "question": " {{c1::ARCADE OF STRUTHERS}}: fascial band in the medial arm that connects the {{c4::brachialis}} to the {{c4::triceps brachii-medial}} pt demonstrates involvement of {{c2:: all ulnar nerve innervated muscles and sensory }} Phys-ex: Wrist flexion may result in [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "radial deviation | Context:  deviation 2/2 FCU weakness ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 812
  },
  {
    "id": 313,
    "question": " Arcade of Struthers Syndrome may cause... [BLANK] : unopposed {{c1:: extensor digitorum communis ( EDC ) }} causes partial finger flexion of the 4th and 5th PIP and DIP due to extension of the {{c3::MCP}} joints ",
    "answer": "Ulnar claw hand",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 813
  },
  {
    "id": 314,
    "question": " Arcade of Struthers Syndrome may cause... {{c2::Ulnar claw hand}} : unopposed {{c1:: extensor digitorum communis ( EDC ) }} causes partial finger flexion of the 4th and 5th PIP and DIP due to extension of the [BLANK] joints ",
    "answer": "MCP",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 813
  },
  {
    "id": 315,
    "question": "sign : inability to hold a paper by pure thumb [BLANK] weakness). pt substitutes [BLANK] muscle, causing flexion of the DlP joint ",
    "answer": "adduction (adductor pollicis / FPL",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 815
  },
  {
    "id": 316,
    "question": "[BLANK] sign: Inability to adduct the {{c2::5th digit (palmar interossei::body part/muscle}} weakness)",
    "answer": "Wartenberg’s",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 816
  },
  {
    "id": 317,
    "question": "{{c1::Wartenberg’s}} sign: Inability to adduct the [BLANK] weakness)",
    "answer": "5th digit (palmar interossei",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 816
  },
  {
    "id": 318,
    "question": " [BLANK] a ulnar neuropathy that can occur years after a distal humeral fracture presents same as {{c2::arcade of struthers}} syndrome ",
    "answer": "TARDY ULNAR NERVE PALSY | Context:  nerve can be injured secondary to a trauma that results in bone overgrowth or scar formation Nerve traction can also occur from an increased carrying angle due to a valgus deformity at the elbow with...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 817
  },
  {
    "id": 319,
    "question": " {{c1::TARDY ULNAR NERVE PALSY}} a ulnar neuropathy that can occur years after a distal humeral fracture presents same as [BLANK] syndrome ",
    "answer": "arcade of struthers | Context:  nerve can be injured secondary to a trauma that results in bone overgrowth or scar formation Nerve traction can also occur from an increased carrying angle due to a valgus deformity at the elbow with...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 817
  },
  {
    "id": 320,
    "question": " Cubital tunnel syndrome / Retro Condylar Groove EDx findings.. SNAP: Abnormal [BLANK] findings (if severe) CMAP : abnormal {{c4::above elbow::site}} (in conduction block) CMAP : normal {{c4::wrist and B. elbow sites::site}} (in conduction block) Approximately {{c2::10 - 15::2# range}} msec decrease in {{c2::CV}} or a {{c3::20%}} drop in amplitude ",
    "answer": "sup. sensory (5th digit) &amp; DUC | Context:  conduction block : CMAP amplitude NORMAL at wrist and B. elbow sites ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 818
  },
  {
    "id": 321,
    "question": " Cubital tunnel syndrome / Retro Condylar Groove EDx findings.. SNAP: Abnormal {{c1::sup. sensory (5th digit) & DUC}} findings (if severe) CMAP : abnormal [BLANK] (in conduction block) CMAP : normal [BLANK] (in conduction block) Approximately {{c2::10 - 15::2# range}} msec decrease in {{c2::CV}} or a {{c3::20%}} drop in amplitude ",
    "answer": "above elbow / wrist&nbsp;and&nbsp;B. elbow&nbsp;sites | Context:  conduction block : CMAP amplitude NORMAL at wrist and B. elbow sites ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 818
  },
  {
    "id": 322,
    "question": " Cubital tunnel syndrome / Retro Condylar Groove EDx findings.. SNAP: Abnormal {{c1::sup. sensory (5th digit) & DUC}} findings (if severe) CMAP : abnormal {{c4::above elbow::site}} (in conduction block) CMAP : normal {{c4::wrist and B. elbow sites::site}} (in conduction block) Approximately [BLANK] msec decrease in [BLANK] or a {{c3::20%}} drop in amplitude ",
    "answer": "10 - 15 / CV | Context:  conduction block : CMAP amplitude NORMAL at wrist and B. elbow sites ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 818
  },
  {
    "id": 323,
    "question": " Cubital tunnel syndrome / Retro Condylar Groove EDx findings.. SNAP: Abnormal {{c1::sup. sensory (5th digit) & DUC}} findings (if severe) CMAP : abnormal {{c4::above elbow::site}} (in conduction block) CMAP : normal {{c4::wrist and B. elbow sites::site}} (in conduction block) Approximately {{c2::10 - 15::2# range}} msec decrease in {{c2::CV}} or a [BLANK] drop in amplitude ",
    "answer": "20% | Context:  conduction block : CMAP amplitude NORMAL at wrist and B. elbow sites ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 818
  },
  {
    "id": 324,
    "question": " Cubital tunnel syndrome / Retro Condylar Groove NCS : [BLANK] conduction studies are most useful typically become abnormal 1st 2/2 {{c2::somatotopic}} organization ",
    "answer": "Motor | Context: the opposite of CTS (which is typically sensory 1st) ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 819
  },
  {
    "id": 325,
    "question": " Cubital tunnel syndrome / Retro Condylar Groove NCS : {{c1::Motor::sensory / motor}} conduction studies are most useful typically become abnormal 1st 2/2 [BLANK] organization ",
    "answer": "somatotopic | Context: the opposite of CTS (which is typically sensory 1st) ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 819
  },
  {
    "id": 326,
    "question": " Cubital tunnel syndrome v.s. Retro Condylar Groove entrapment muscles involved include all ulnar n. innervated m’s Save for the [BLANK], which may or may not be involved ",
    "answer": "FCU | Context:  muscle that is peirced may or may not be affected ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 820
  },
  {
    "id": 327,
    "question": " Cubital tunnel syndrome / Retro Condylar Groove EDX findings... EMG: abnormal activity in hand intrinsics [BLANK] forearm muscles ",
    "answer": "&gt; | Context:  Due to nerve fascicle placement in the retrocondylar groove there is a 70% chance of finding abnormalities in the hand intrinsics compared to a 25% chance in the ulnar forearm muscles. Furthermore, t...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 821
  },
  {
    "id": 328,
    "question": " GUYON’S CANAL clinical presentation (1) [BLANK] (2) {{c2::deep palmar motor and hypothenar motor}} (3) {{c3::evrything (proximal canal lesion)}} (4) {{c4::only the sensory fiber to 4th and 5th}} ",
    "answer": "deep palmar motor",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 822
  },
  {
    "id": 329,
    "question": " GUYON’S CANAL clinical presentation (1) {{c1::deep palmar motor}} (2) [BLANK] (3) {{c3::evrything (proximal canal lesion)}} (4) {{c4::only the sensory fiber to 4th and 5th}} ",
    "answer": "deep palmar motor and hypothenar motor",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 822
  },
  {
    "id": 330,
    "question": " GUYON’S CANAL clinical presentation (1) {{c1::deep palmar motor}} (2) {{c2::deep palmar motor and hypothenar motor}} (3) [BLANK] (4) {{c4::only the sensory fiber to 4th and 5th}} ",
    "answer": "evrything (proximal canal lesion)",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 822
  },
  {
    "id": 331,
    "question": " GUYON’S CANAL clinical presentation (1) {{c1::deep palmar motor}} (2) {{c2::deep palmar motor and hypothenar motor}} (3) {{c3::evrything (proximal canal lesion)}} (4) [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "only the sensory fiber to 4th and 5th",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 822
  },
  {
    "id": 332,
    "question": "Guyons Canal EDX findings... SNAP: [BLANK] CMAP: Amplitude Abnormal {{c2::Wrist, B elbow, A elbow (OL/amp)::site}} (in conduction block) CV: {{c4::normal::normal/abnormal}} at the above elbow site EMG: Abnormal activity in {{c3::ulnar innervated hand m's}}",
    "answer": "5th digit is abnormal, but&nbsp;DUC is normal | Context: CV is unique: lesion must be w/ in that SEGMENT ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 823
  },
  {
    "id": 333,
    "question": "Guyons Canal EDX findings... SNAP: {{c1::5th digit is abnormal, but DUC is normal}} CMAP: Amplitude Abnormal [BLANK] (in conduction block) CV: {{c4::normal::normal/abnormal}} at the above elbow site EMG: Abnormal activity in {{c3::ulnar innervated hand m's}}",
    "answer": "Wrist, B elbow, A elbow (OL/amp) | Context: CV is unique: lesion must be w/ in that SEGMENT ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 823
  },
  {
    "id": 334,
    "question": "Guyons Canal EDX findings... SNAP: {{c1::5th digit is abnormal, but DUC is normal}} CMAP: Amplitude Abnormal {{c2::Wrist, B elbow, A elbow (OL/amp)::site}} (in conduction block) CV: [BLANK] at the above elbow site EMG: Abnormal activity in {{c3::ulnar innervated hand m's}}",
    "answer": "normal | Context: CV is unique: lesion must be w/ in that SEGMENT ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 823
  },
  {
    "id": 335,
    "question": "Guyons Canal EDX findings... SNAP: {{c1::5th digit is abnormal, but DUC is normal}} CMAP: Amplitude Abnormal {{c2::Wrist, B elbow, A elbow (OL/amp)::site}} (in conduction block) CV: {{c4::normal::normal/abnormal}} at the above elbow site EMG: Abnormal activity in [BLANK]",
    "answer": "ulnar innervated hand m's | Context: CV is unique: lesion must be w/ in that SEGMENT ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 823
  },
  {
    "id": 336,
    "question": "retrocondylar groove vs CUTS can be localized with the [BLANK] this is important * as the former requires {{c2::nerve transposition}} ",
    "answer": "inching technique",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 824
  },
  {
    "id": 337,
    "question": "retrocondylar groove vs CUTS can be localized with the {{c1::inching technique}} this is important * as the former requires [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "nerve transposition",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 824
  },
  {
    "id": 338,
    "question": "the most common cause of peripheral neuropathy wordlwide is [BLANK]",
    "answer": "leprosy | Context:  may be the most common treatable peripheral nerve disorder worldwide. The major features of leprosy are anesthetic skin lesions, neuropathy, and positive skin smears for Mycobacterium leprae bacilli ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 835
  },
  {
    "id": 339,
    "question": " 4 Median n. FOREARM muscles ( non-AIN m's ) [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "Pronator teres / FCR / Palmaris longus / Flexor digitorum superficialis",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 895
  },
  {
    "id": 340,
    "question": " Axonal Injury [BLANK] and [BLANK] should NOT be affected Unless the {{c1::largest/fastest fibers::2}} are affected ",
    "answer": "O/P <font color=\"\"#fc0006\"\">Latency</font> / CV | Context:  EDx of Axonal injury ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 896
  },
  {
    "id": 341,
    "question": " Axonal Injury {{c2::O/P Latency }} and {{c2::CV}} should NOT be affected Unless the [BLANK] are affected ",
    "answer": "largest/fastest fibers | Context:  EDx of Axonal injury ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 896
  },
  {
    "id": 342,
    "question": " Median Motor study (APB) suspect RCA if CMAP... [BLANK] n. stim at the wrist/elbow: reduced or absent [BLANK] n. stim at the wrist/elbow: present ",
    "answer": "median / ulnar",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 955
  },
  {
    "id": 343,
    "question": " radial nerve cutaneous distribution innervated above the spiral groove - [BLANK] - [BLANK] innervated below the spiral groove - [BLANK] - [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "posterior cutaneous nerve of the arm / inferior lateral cutaneous nerve of the arm / <font color=\"\"#0014ff\"\">posterior cutaneous nerve of forearm</font> / superficial branch",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 964
  },
  {
    "id": 344,
    "question": " Radial N. muscles of the arm Muscles innervated above the spiral groove: [BLANK] [BLANK] Muscles innervated below the spiral groove: [BLANK] [BLANK] +/- [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "Triceps brachii / Anconeus / <font color=\"\"#0014ff\"\">Brachioradialis</font> / ECR-L / ECR-B | Context:  +/- Brachialis (dual: musculocutaneous nerve and components of the radial nerve) ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 965
  },
  {
    "id": 345,
    "question": "Posterior Interosseus Nerve muscles of the forearm Superficial [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] Deep/Snuff box muscles {{c2::Abductor pollicis longus (APL)}} {{c2::Extensor pollicis longus (EPL)}} {{c2::Extensor pollicis brevis (EPB)}} {{c2::Extensor indicis proprius (EIP)}}",
    "answer": "Supinator / Extensor digitorum (communus) / Extensor digiti minimi (EDM) / Extensor carpi ulnaris (ECU)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 966
  },
  {
    "id": 346,
    "question": "Posterior Interosseus Nerve muscles of the forearm Superficial {{c1::Supinator}} {{c1::Extensor digitorum (communus)}} {{c1::Extensor digiti minimi (EDM)}} {{c1::Extensor carpi ulnaris (ECU)}} Deep/Snuff box muscles [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK]",
    "answer": "Abductor pollicis longus (APL) / Extensor pollicis longus (EPL) / Extensor pollicis brevis (EPB) / Extensor indicis proprius (EIP)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 966
  },
  {
    "id": 347,
    "question": "[BLANK] aka radial injury at the axilla can involve the {{c1::posterior cord}} of the brachial plexus (rare) ",
    "answer": "CRUTCH PALSY | Context:  injured posterior cord of the brachial plexus, can affect the radial, axillary, and/or suprascapular nerves, can result in abnormal SNAPs, CMAPs, and EMG findings of the affected nerve ...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 967
  },
  {
    "id": 348,
    "question": "{{c2::CRUTCH PALSY}} aka radial injury at the axilla can involve the [BLANK] of the brachial plexus (rare) ",
    "answer": "posterior cord | Context:  injured posterior cord of the brachial plexus, can affect the radial, axillary, and/or suprascapular nerves, can result in abnormal SNAPs, CMAPs, and EMG findings of the affected nerve ...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 967
  },
  {
    "id": 349,
    "question": "crutch palsy clincial presentation may c/o weakness in [BLANK], Sensation may be decreased over the {{c2::posterior arm, forearm, and hand}}",
    "answer": "<u>all</u> radial n. innervated m.",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 968
  },
  {
    "id": 350,
    "question": "crutch palsy clincial presentation may c/o weakness in {{c1:: all radial n. innervated m.}}, Sensation may be decreased over the [BLANK]",
    "answer": "posterior arm, forearm, and hand",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 968
  },
  {
    "id": 351,
    "question": "EMG Abnormal activity in [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "all radial n. muscles +/- posterior cord muscles | Context:  in demeylination CMAP will be nl at all sites (nl distal to a conduction block) ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 985
  },
  {
    "id": 352,
    "question": "radial n. Injury at the spiral-groove is also known as [BLANK] palsy or [BLANK] palsy ",
    "answer": "Saturday night / honeymooner’s | Context:  wrist drop, NO finger extension. ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 986
  },
  {
    "id": 353,
    "question": " Radial n. injury at spiral-groove clinical presentation weakness of {{c2:: elbow flexion ( BR ) }} , [BLANK] , {{c1:: wrist extension ( ECR -L/B, ECU ) }} , and {{c1:: finger extension ( EDC ) }} There is preservation of {{c1::elbow extension (triceps, anconeus) }} Sensory deficits may occur in the {{c3::dorsal aspect hand and forearm}} ",
    "answer": "supination",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 987
  },
  {
    "id": 354,
    "question": " Radial n. injury at spiral-groove clinical presentation weakness of {{c2:: elbow flexion ( BR ) }} , {{c2::supination}} , {{c1:: wrist extension ( ECR -L/B, ECU ) }} , and {{c1:: finger extension ( EDC ) }} There is preservation of {{c1::elbow extension (triceps, anconeus) }} Sensory deficits may occur in the [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "dorsal aspect hand and forearm",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 987
  },
  {
    "id": 355,
    "question": "Radial n. injury at spiral-groove EDX findings : NCS: CMAP: normal at [BLANK] in conduction block CMAP: abnormal at [BLANK] in wallerian degeneration superficial radial sensory response could be {{c3::normal}} in {{c4::demyelination}} EMG: Abnormal activity in {{c2::all radial n. except the triceps and anconeus::m.}}",
    "answer": "all 3 sites / all 3 sites | Context:  CB: excepts post. arm (not done) ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 988
  },
  {
    "id": 356,
    "question": "Radial n. injury at spiral-groove EDX findings : NCS: CMAP: normal at {{c1::all 3 sites::stim site}} in conduction block CMAP: abnormal at {{c1::all 3 sites::stim site}} in wallerian degeneration superficial radial sensory response could be [BLANK] in {{c4::demyelination}} EMG: Abnormal activity in {{c2::all radial n. except the triceps and anconeus::m.}}",
    "answer": "normal | Context:  CB: excepts post. arm (not done) ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 988
  },
  {
    "id": 357,
    "question": "Radial n. injury at spiral-groove EDX findings : NCS: CMAP: normal at {{c1::all 3 sites::stim site}} in conduction block CMAP: abnormal at {{c1::all 3 sites::stim site}} in wallerian degeneration superficial radial sensory response could be {{c3::normal}} in [BLANK] EMG: Abnormal activity in {{c2::all radial n. except the triceps and anconeus::m.}}",
    "answer": "demyelination | Context:  CB: excepts post. arm (not done) ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 988
  },
  {
    "id": 358,
    "question": "Radial n. injury at spiral-groove EDX findings : NCS: CMAP: normal at {{c1::all 3 sites::stim site}} in conduction block CMAP: abnormal at {{c1::all 3 sites::stim site}} in wallerian degeneration superficial radial sensory response could be {{c3::normal}} in {{c4::demyelination}} EMG: Abnormal activity in [BLANK]",
    "answer": "all radial n. except the triceps and anconeus | Context:  CB: excepts post. arm (not done) ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 988
  },
  {
    "id": 359,
    "question": "[BLANK] radial nerve can be entrapped between the {{c2:: brachialis and BR::2}} c/o {{c4::lateral/dorsal proximal forearm}} pain that worsens with activity, which can mimic {{c3::lateral epicondylitis}} ",
    "answer": "RADIAL TUNNEL SYNDROME",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 990
  },
  {
    "id": 360,
    "question": "{{c1::RADIAL TUNNEL SYNDROME}} radial nerve can be entrapped between the {{c2:: brachialis and BR::2}} c/o [BLANK] pain that worsens with activity, which can mimic {{c3::lateral epicondylitis}} ",
    "answer": "lateral/dorsal proximal forearm",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 990
  },
  {
    "id": 361,
    "question": "{{c1::RADIAL TUNNEL SYNDROME}} radial nerve can be entrapped between the {{c2:: brachialis and BR::2}} c/o {{c4::lateral/dorsal proximal forearm}} pain that worsens with activity, which can mimic [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "lateral epicondylitis",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 990
  },
  {
    "id": 362,
    "question": " Radial Tunnel syndrome NCS will demonstrate [BLANK] EMG will demonstrate [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "typically no findings / typically no findings | Context:  EDX is insensitive Interventions may include rehabilitation, diagnostic injection, or surgical decompression ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 991
  },
  {
    "id": 363,
    "question": " [BLANK]: radial n. injured at the {{c4::Arcade of Frohse}} of the supinator presents with {{c2::painless*::painful/painless}} weakness of all the {{c1::PIN innervated m::same }} they will display weakness with only {{c3::finger/thumb extension::2}} and will show a {{c3::radial (ECU weak. ECR intact)}} deviated wrist ",
    "answer": "posterior interosseous syndrome | Context:  *may have pain 6cm disatal to lat epicondyle, typically no snesory involvement ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 992
  },
  {
    "id": 364,
    "question": " {{c1::posterior interosseous syndrome}}: radial n. injured at the [BLANK] of the supinator presents with {{c2::painless*::painful/painless}} weakness of all the {{c1::PIN innervated m::same }} they will display weakness with only {{c3::finger/thumb extension::2}} and will show a {{c3::radial (ECU weak. ECR intact)}} deviated wrist ",
    "answer": "Arcade of Frohse | Context:  *may have pain 6cm disatal to lat epicondyle, typically no snesory involvement ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 992
  },
  {
    "id": 365,
    "question": " {{c1::posterior interosseous syndrome}}: radial n. injured at the {{c4::Arcade of Frohse}} of the supinator presents with [BLANK] weakness of all the {{c1::PIN innervated m::same }} they will display weakness with only {{c3::finger/thumb extension::2}} and will show a {{c3::radial (ECU weak. ECR intact)}} deviated wrist ",
    "answer": "painless* | Context:  *may have pain 6cm disatal to lat epicondyle, typically no snesory involvement ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 992
  },
  {
    "id": 366,
    "question": " {{c1::posterior interosseous syndrome}}: radial n. injured at the {{c4::Arcade of Frohse}} of the supinator presents with {{c2::painless*::painful/painless}} weakness of all the {{c1::PIN innervated m::same }} they will display weakness with only [BLANK] and will show a [BLANK] deviated wrist ",
    "answer": "finger/thumb extension / radial (ECU weak. ECR intact) | Context:  *may have pain 6cm disatal to lat epicondyle, typically no snesory involvement ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 992
  },
  {
    "id": 367,
    "question": " Posterior interosseous syndrome EDX findings: NCS: superfical radial sensory [BLANK] SNAP. in conduction block [BLANK] radial CMAP when recording over PIN innervated muscles (EIP) EMG: Abnormal in +/- supinator and all PIN muscles. {{c2:: triceps, anconeus, BR, ECR -L, and ECR -B::5 }} are always spared ",
    "answer": "Normal / Abnormal | Context:  i wonder if lateral forearm stim would be nl Amp? (past the supinator) ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 993
  },
  {
    "id": 368,
    "question": " Superficial radial neuropathy: a lso known as [BLANK] or {{c2::cheiralgia paresthetica}} also known informally as wristwatch syndrome or handcuff palsy ",
    "answer": "Wartenberg syndrome",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 994
  },
  {
    "id": 369,
    "question": " Superficial radial neuropathy: a lso known as {{c1::Wartenberg syndrome::eponym}} or [BLANK] also known informally as wristwatch syndrome or handcuff palsy ",
    "answer": "cheiralgia paresthetica",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 994
  },
  {
    "id": 370,
    "question": " Hand-cuff palsy E DX findings : Normal/Abnormal NCS: superfical radial nerve SNAP: [BLANK] radial nerve CMAP: [BLANK] EMG: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "Abnormal / Normal / Normal | Context:  pure sensory syndrome with no muscle involvement. numbness, burning, or tingling on the dorsal radial aspect of the hand. exacerbated with palmar and ulnar wrist flexion or forced pronation ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 995
  },
  {
    "id": 371,
    "question": "Radiculopathy SNAP: Normal if the lesion is located proximal to the DRG CMAP: [BLANK]",
    "answer": "Normal or reduced amplitude | Context: typicaly onset is normal as tends to be axonal...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 996
  },
  {
    "id": 372,
    "question": " musculocutaneous nerve. innervates ARM 3 muscles [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] FOREARM 1 cutaneous sensory [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "Coracobrachialis / Biceps brachii / Brachialis (also radial nerve) / lateral antebrachial cutaneous (LAC)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1013
  },
  {
    "id": 373,
    "question": " MUSCULOCUTANEOUS MONO-NEUROPATHY In General: Injury to the [BLANK] portion of the nerve is more common than to the [BLANK] portion ",
    "answer": "distal / proximal",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1014
  },
  {
    "id": 374,
    "question": " Musculocutaneous mono-neuropathy clinical pres. patient may complain of [BLANK] weakness and abnormal sensation over the [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "elbow flexion / lateral forearm | Context:  supinator and brachio-radialis may hypertrophy ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1032
  },
  {
    "id": 375,
    "question": " Musculocutaneous mono-neuropahty EDX findings : NCS: Abnormal SNAP in the [BLANK] Abnormal CMAP to the {{c2::biceps brachii}} EMG: Abnormal activity in the {{c2::biceps brachii}} ",
    "answer": "LAC",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1033
  },
  {
    "id": 376,
    "question": " Musculocutaneous mono-neuropahty EDX findings : NCS: Abnormal SNAP in the {{c1::LAC}} Abnormal CMAP to the [BLANK] EMG: Abnormal activity in the [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "biceps brachii / biceps brachii",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1033
  },
  {
    "id": 377,
    "question": "As the nerve emerges, it divides into anterior and posterior terminal divisions. ",
    "answer": " quadrilateral space: capsule of the shoulder joint / teres minor above, the surgical neck of the humerus laterally, the long head of the triceps medially, and the teres major below. posterior branch: teres minor, posterior fibers of deltoid, and the upper lateral cutaneous nerve of the arm anterior branch: middle and anterior fibers of the deltoid ",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Standard",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1063
  },
  {
    "id": 378,
    "question": "Axillary n. innervates 3 [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK]",
    "answer": "Teres minor / Deltoid / Upper lateral cutaneous nerve | Context:  Tere Major: lower subscapular nerve (C5, C6) ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1064
  },
  {
    "id": 379,
    "question": " Axillary mono-neuropathy EDX findings : NCS: SNAP [BLANK] CMAP: [BLANK] EMG: Abnormal activity in the {{c2::deltoid and teres minor::2}} muscles ",
    "answer": "not available / Abnormal (not done) | Context: anterior and lateral heads of the deltoid show abnormalities more commonly than the posterior head. Bobby does not check teres minor...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1065
  },
  {
    "id": 380,
    "question": " Axillary mono-neuropathy EDX findings : NCS: SNAP {{c1::not available}} CMAP: {{c1::Abnormal (not done)}} EMG: Abnormal activity in the [BLANK] muscles ",
    "answer": "deltoid and teres minor | Context: anterior and lateral heads of the deltoid show abnormalities more commonly than the posterior head. Bobby does not check teres minor...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1065
  },
  {
    "id": 381,
    "question": " suprascapular nerve. course originate from the C5 and C6 spinal nerve roots and contributes to the [BLANK] which it branches off then passes the {{c2::posterior triangle}} of the neck and runs beneath the {{c2::trapezius}} to the superior margin of the scapula. It runs through the {{c3:: suprascapular notch}}, to innervate the {{c5::supraspinatus}} The nerve then wraps around the {{c4:: spinoglen",
    "answer": "upper trunk",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1073
  },
  {
    "id": 382,
    "question": " suprascapular nerve. course originate from the C5 and C6 spinal nerve roots and contributes to the {{c1::upper trunk::plexus}} which it branches off then passes the [BLANK] of the neck and runs beneath the [BLANK] to the superior margin of the scapula. It runs through the {{c3:: suprascapular notch}}, to innervate the {{c5::supraspinatus}} The nerve then wraps around the {{c4:: spinoglenoid notch",
    "answer": "posterior triangle / trapezius",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1073
  },
  {
    "id": 383,
    "question": " suprascapular nerve. course originate from the C5 and C6 spinal nerve roots and contributes to the {{c1::upper trunk::plexus}} which it branches off then passes the {{c2::posterior triangle}} of the neck and runs beneath the {{c2::trapezius}} to the superior margin of the scapula. It runs through the {{c3:: suprascapular notch}}, to innervate the [BLANK] The nerve then wraps around the {{c4:: spi",
    "answer": "supraspinatus / infraspinatus",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1073
  },
  {
    "id": 384,
    "question": " SUPRASCAPULAR NEUROPATHY This is the only peripheral nerve injury at the [BLANK] level. It is the most commonly involved nerve in {{c2::neuralgic amyotrophy}} ",
    "answer": "trunk | Context:  injured from trauma (forced scapular protraction), traction (from a massive rotator cuff tear), stinger/Erb’s palsy; compression from spinoglenoid ganglions , hematoma, suprascapular or spinoglenoid ...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1074
  },
  {
    "id": 385,
    "question": " SUPRASCAPULAR NEUROPATHY This is the only peripheral nerve injury at the {{c1::trunk}} level. It is the most commonly involved nerve in [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "neuralgic amyotrophy | Context:  injured from trauma (forced scapular protraction), traction (from a massive rotator cuff tear), stinger/Erb’s palsy; compression from spinoglenoid ganglions , hematoma, suprascapular or spinoglenoid ...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1074
  },
  {
    "id": 386,
    "question": "Suprascapular neuropathy clinical pres. proximal injury results in weakness in both [BLANK] and [BLANK] Nerve injury at the spinoglenoid notch will result in weakness [BLANK]",
    "answer": "shoulder abduction (SS) / external rotation (IS) / only in external rotation&nbsp;(IS)",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1075
  },
  {
    "id": 387,
    "question": " Long thoracic n. runs distally along the thoracic wall to innervate the [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "serratus anterior | Context:  ( SALT [ S erratus A nterior L ong T horacic]) ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1076
  },
  {
    "id": 388,
    "question": "2 main types of shoulder winging. EDx findings... Medial winging: EMG findings in [BLANK] Lateral winging: EMG findings in [BLANK]",
    "answer": "serratus anterior / trapezius (&amp;SCM) | Context:  nerve can be injured by traction from a fall, MVA , sports activities, or shoulder bags Scapular Winging: Medial Versus Lateral Scapular Winging MEDIAL SCAPULAR WINGING LATERAL SCAPULAR WINGING Nerve...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1077
  },
  {
    "id": 389,
    "question": "Motor unit [BLANK] is a better measure of pathology",
    "answer": "duration | Context:  Recruitment patterns during maximal voluntary contraction of the deltoid muscle in (A) healthy subject, (B) spinal muscular atrophy , (C) polymyositis. ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1088
  },
  {
    "id": 390,
    "question": "[BLANK] injury may generate spontaneous activity",
    "answer": "BOTH Muscle &amp; Nerve | Context:  \"\"dennervation activity\"\" is a misnomer. classic example is Fib in radiculopathy \"\"if nerve is damaged muscle will eventually be damaged\"\" ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1098
  },
  {
    "id": 391,
    "question": " lateral femoral cutaneous n. pure sensory nerve fibers originate from the [BLANK] and [BLANK] nerve roots from the {{c2::posterior}} division of the lumbar plexus ",
    "answer": "L2 / L3",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1099
  },
  {
    "id": 392,
    "question": " lateral femoral cutaneous n. pure sensory nerve fibers originate from the {{c1::L2}} and {{c1::L3}} nerve roots from the [BLANK] division of the lumbar plexus ",
    "answer": "posterior",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1099
  },
  {
    "id": 393,
    "question": " lateral femoral cutaneous neuropathy aka [BLANK] Etiology 1.) {{c1::compression}} 2.) medical cuases: Diabetes, {{c2::tumor}}, infection, {{c2::weight gain/loss}} 3.) {{c3::Iatrogenic::category}} ",
    "answer": "meralgia paresthetica | Context:  Etiology chronic compression by a repeated low grade trauma: from a protuberant abdomen, pregnancy, or tight clothing Diabetes, tumor, infection, and rapid weight gain or weight loss can also affect ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1100
  },
  {
    "id": 394,
    "question": " lateral femoral cutaneous neuropathy aka {{c4::meralgia paresthetica}} Etiology 1.) [BLANK] 2.) medical cuases: Diabetes, {{c2::tumor}}, infection, {{c2::weight gain/loss}} 3.) {{c3::Iatrogenic::category}} ",
    "answer": "compression | Context:  Etiology chronic compression by a repeated low grade trauma: from a protuberant abdomen, pregnancy, or tight clothing Diabetes, tumor, infection, and rapid weight gain or weight loss can also affect ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1100
  },
  {
    "id": 395,
    "question": " lateral femoral cutaneous neuropathy aka {{c4::meralgia paresthetica}} Etiology 1.) {{c1::compression}} 2.) medical cuases: Diabetes, [BLANK], infection, [BLANK] 3.) {{c3::Iatrogenic::category}} ",
    "answer": "tumor / weight gain/loss | Context:  Etiology chronic compression by a repeated low grade trauma: from a protuberant abdomen, pregnancy, or tight clothing Diabetes, tumor, infection, and rapid weight gain or weight loss can also affect ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1100
  },
  {
    "id": 396,
    "question": " lateral femoral cutaneous neuropathy aka {{c4::meralgia paresthetica}} Etiology 1.) {{c1::compression}} 2.) medical cuases: Diabetes, {{c2::tumor}}, infection, {{c2::weight gain/loss}} 3.) [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "Iatrogenic | Context:  Etiology chronic compression by a repeated low grade trauma: from a protuberant abdomen, pregnancy, or tight clothing Diabetes, tumor, infection, and rapid weight gain or weight loss can also affect ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1100
  },
  {
    "id": 397,
    "question": " lateral femoral cutaneous nerve course pass over the [BLANK] toward the {{c2::anterior iliac spine}} It passes underneath the {{c3::inguinal ligament}} to provide sensation to the lateral thigh ",
    "answer": "iliacus",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1101
  },
  {
    "id": 398,
    "question": " lateral femoral cutaneous nerve course pass over the {{c1::iliacus::m.}} toward the [BLANK] It passes underneath the {{c3::inguinal ligament}} to provide sensation to the lateral thigh ",
    "answer": "anterior iliac spine",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1101
  },
  {
    "id": 399,
    "question": " lateral femoral cutaneous nerve course pass over the {{c1::iliacus::m.}} toward the {{c2::anterior iliac spine}} It passes underneath the [BLANK] to provide sensation to the lateral thigh ",
    "answer": "inguinal ligament",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1101
  },
  {
    "id": 400,
    "question": " lateral femoral cutaneous nerve. clinical pres. patient may report sensory complaints in the lateral thigh, including pain, numbness, burning, or a dull ache, exacerbated by [BLANK] and [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "hip extension/flexion / prolonged sitting | Context:  T reatment : Interventions may include rehabilitation, NSAIDs, Gabapentin, cortisone injections, surgical release. Symptoms may be self-limited In addition, removal of compressive clothing should occ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1102
  },
  {
    "id": 401,
    "question": " lateral femoral cutaneous nerve, EDX findings : NCS SNAP: [BLANK] CMAP: [BLANK] EMG [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "Abnormal lateral femoral cutaneous nerve (not typically done) / not available / not available",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1103
  },
  {
    "id": 402,
    "question": " Femoral n. innervates (motor) [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "Iliacus<b><font color=\"\"#fc2307\"\">*</font></b> (illiopsoas) / Pectineus (1/2) / Sartorius / Quadriceps m. x4",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1104
  },
  {
    "id": 403,
    "question": " Sensory Femoral n. innervates Iliacus (illiopsoas) Pectineus (1/2) Anterior Branch Sartorius [BLANK] [BLANK] Posterior Branch [BLANK] [BLANK] Quadriceps m. x4 ",
    "answer": "intermediate cutaneous nerve of the thigh / medial cutaneous nerve of the thigh / Saphenous nerve / infra-patellar branch of saphenous",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1112
  },
  {
    "id": 404,
    "question": "Femoral Neuropathy, EDX findings: NCS: Abnormal [BLANK] Abnormal [BLANK] EMG: - Abnormal activity in femoral n. innervated m's - if abnl, then study other m's (eg. {{c2::hamstrings, gluts, adductor::1ex.}}) to r/o {{c2::plexus/root::2}} involvement",
    "answer": "saphenous nerve&nbsp;SNAP / rectus femoris CMAP | Context: EX. Involvement of obturator nerve innervated muscles (e.g., adductor longus) and/or lumbar paraspinals could indicate an L3/4 radiculopathy over a femoral neuropathy ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1148
  },
  {
    "id": 405,
    "question": "Femoral Neuropathy, EDX findings: NCS: Abnormal {{c1::saphenous nerve SNAP}} Abnormal {{c1::rectus femoris CMAP}} EMG: - Abnormal activity in femoral n. innervated m's - if abnl, then study other m's (eg. [BLANK]) to r/o [BLANK] involvement",
    "answer": "hamstrings, gluts, adductor / plexus/root | Context: EX. Involvement of obturator nerve innervated muscles (e.g., adductor longus) and/or lumbar paraspinals could indicate an L3/4 radiculopathy over a femoral neuropathy ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1148
  },
  {
    "id": 406,
    "question": "[BLANK] is the most common cause of femoral neuropathy ",
    "answer": "Diabetic amyotrophy | Context:  a nerve disorder which is a complication of diabetes mellitus . It affects the thighs, hips, buttocks and legs, causing pain and muscle wasting . It is also called by several other names, including p...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1149
  },
  {
    "id": 407,
    "question": "[BLANK] is a proximal diabetic neuropathy distinct from other types of distal diabetic peripheral neuropathies it is also known as a {{c2::lumbo-sacral radiculo-plexus::\"\"4-names\"\"}} neuropathy ",
    "answer": "Diabetic amyotrophy | Context:  as it can involve the plexus and nerve roots, as well as peripheral nerves It predominantly affects the lumbosacral plexus ...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1150
  },
  {
    "id": 408,
    "question": "{{c1::Diabetic amyotrophy}} is a proximal diabetic neuropathy distinct from other types of distal diabetic peripheral neuropathies it is also known as a [BLANK] neuropathy ",
    "answer": "lumbo-sacral radiculo-plexus | Context:  as it can involve the plexus and nerve roots, as well as peripheral nerves It predominantly affects the lumbosacral plexus ...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1150
  },
  {
    "id": 409,
    "question": " exact cause of diabetic amyotrophy is unknown believed to result from a multifocal [BLANK] . The nerve is believed to be injured from an abnormality of the vaso-nervorum due to diabetes mellitus. Nerve biopsy shows multifocal nerve fiber loss suggesting {{c2::ischemic}} injury and perivascular infiltrate amyotrophy has been noted to occur after {{c3::marked weight loss::pt characteristic}} ",
    "answer": "immune-mediated microvasculitis",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1151
  },
  {
    "id": 410,
    "question": " exact cause of diabetic amyotrophy is unknown believed to result from a multifocal {{c1::immune-mediated microvasculitis::2 names}} . The nerve is believed to be injured from an abnormality of the vaso-nervorum due to diabetes mellitus. Nerve biopsy shows multifocal nerve fiber loss suggesting [BLANK] injury and perivascular infiltrate amyotrophy has been noted to occur after {{c3::marked weight ",
    "answer": "ischemic",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1151
  },
  {
    "id": 411,
    "question": " exact cause of diabetic amyotrophy is unknown believed to result from a multifocal {{c1::immune-mediated microvasculitis::2 names}} . The nerve is believed to be injured from an abnormality of the vaso-nervorum due to diabetes mellitus. Nerve biopsy shows multifocal nerve fiber loss suggesting {{c2::ischemic}} injury and perivascular infiltrate amyotrophy has been noted to occur after [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "marked weight loss",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1151
  },
  {
    "id": 412,
    "question": "Patients then develops [BLANK] and [BLANK] of the proximal > distal lower extremity musculature ",
    "answer": "weakness / atrophy | Context: typically associated weight loss that precedes symptoms. patient may complain of asymmetric thigh pain, knee extension weakness (quadriceps), and atrophy. Loss of the patellar reflex may also occur...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1154
  },
  {
    "id": 413,
    "question": " diabetic amyotrophy EDX findings : NCS: [BLANK] SNAP saphenous* [BLANK] CMAP rectus EMG (Abnormal activity): femoral innervated muscles (±), {{c2::adductors}} iliopsoas {{c2::paraspinals}} ",
    "answer": "Abnormal / Abnormal | Context:  sounds like a L3/L4 radiculopathy * abnl sensory indicates plexus and not a radic \"\"hamstrings should be normal\"\" Treatment : Diabetic amyotrophy is a self-limited condition, but the recovery process...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1155
  },
  {
    "id": 414,
    "question": " diabetic amyotrophy EDX findings : NCS: {{c1::Abnormal}} SNAP saphenous* {{c1::Abnormal}} CMAP rectus EMG (Abnormal activity): femoral innervated muscles (±), [BLANK] iliopsoas [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "adductors / paraspinals | Context:  sounds like a L3/L4 radiculopathy * abnl sensory indicates plexus and not a radic \"\"hamstrings should be normal\"\" Treatment : Diabetic amyotrophy is a self-limited condition, but the recovery process...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1155
  },
  {
    "id": 415,
    "question": " SAPHENOUS NEUROPATHY Etiology can be entrapped in the [BLANK] (aka [BLANK]) or between the {{c3::sartorius}} and {{c3::gracilis}} iatrogenic trauma, including {{c1::knee arthroscopy/meniscectomy}} or {{c4::catheterization/thrombectomy}} ",
    "answer": "hip adductor canal / Hunter’s canal",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1156
  },
  {
    "id": 416,
    "question": " SAPHENOUS NEUROPATHY Etiology can be entrapped in the {{c2::hip adductor canal}} (aka {{c2::Hunter’s canal}}) or between the [BLANK] and [BLANK] iatrogenic trauma, including {{c1::knee arthroscopy/meniscectomy}} or {{c4::catheterization/thrombectomy}} ",
    "answer": "sartorius / gracilis",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1156
  },
  {
    "id": 417,
    "question": " SAPHENOUS NEUROPATHY Etiology can be entrapped in the {{c2::hip adductor canal}} (aka {{c2::Hunter’s canal}}) or between the {{c3::sartorius}} and {{c3::gracilis}} iatrogenic trauma, including [BLANK] or {{c4::catheterization/thrombectomy}} ",
    "answer": "knee arthroscopy/meniscectomy",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1156
  },
  {
    "id": 418,
    "question": " SAPHENOUS NEUROPATHY Etiology can be entrapped in the {{c2::hip adductor canal}} (aka {{c2::Hunter’s canal}}) or between the {{c3::sartorius}} and {{c3::gracilis}} iatrogenic trauma, including {{c1::knee arthroscopy/meniscectomy}} or [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "catheterization/thrombectomy",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1156
  },
  {
    "id": 419,
    "question": " Saphenous Neuropathy, EDX findings : NCS SNAP: [BLANK] CMAP: [BLANK] EMG femoral nerve innervated muscles: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "Abnormal saphenous nerve / Normal / Normal | Context: Treatment: Interventions may include rehabilitation or surgical procedure ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1157
  },
  {
    "id": 420,
    "question": " Sciatic Nerve, course (tibial & peroneal) L4, L5 roots from the [BLANK], and the 1st, 2nd, and 3rd sacral ventral rami exits the pelvis through the {{c1::greater sciatic foramen}} below the {{c4::piriformis}} muscle between the {{c2::lesser trochanter}} and {{c2::ischial tuberosity}} . (bony landmarks) the nerve is deep to the {{c5::gluteus maximus::pelvis}} m. and {{c5::biceps femoris::thigh}} m",
    "answer": "lumbosacral trunk",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1158
  },
  {
    "id": 421,
    "question": " Sciatic Nerve, course (tibial & peroneal) L4, L5 roots from the {{c7::lumbosacral trunk}}, and the 1st, 2nd, and 3rd sacral ventral rami exits the pelvis through the [BLANK] below the {{c4::piriformis}} muscle between the {{c2::lesser trochanter}} and {{c2::ischial tuberosity}} . (bony landmarks) the nerve is deep to the {{c5::gluteus maximus::pelvis}} m. and {{c5::biceps femoris::thigh}} m. down",
    "answer": "greater sciatic foramen",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1158
  },
  {
    "id": 422,
    "question": " Sciatic Nerve, course (tibial & peroneal) L4, L5 roots from the {{c7::lumbosacral trunk}}, and the 1st, 2nd, and 3rd sacral ventral rami exits the pelvis through the {{c1::greater sciatic foramen}} below the [BLANK] muscle between the {{c2::lesser trochanter}} and {{c2::ischial tuberosity}} . (bony landmarks) the nerve is deep to the {{c5::gluteus maximus::pelvis}} m. and {{c5::biceps femoris::th",
    "answer": "piriformis",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1158
  },
  {
    "id": 423,
    "question": " Sciatic Nerve, course (tibial & peroneal) L4, L5 roots from the {{c7::lumbosacral trunk}}, and the 1st, 2nd, and 3rd sacral ventral rami exits the pelvis through the {{c1::greater sciatic foramen}} below the {{c4::piriformis}} muscle between the [BLANK] and [BLANK] . (bony landmarks) the nerve is deep to the {{c5::gluteus maximus::pelvis}} m. and {{c5::biceps femoris::thigh}} m. down the midline ",
    "answer": "lesser trochanter / ischial tuberosity",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1158
  },
  {
    "id": 424,
    "question": " Sciatic Nerve, course (tibial & peroneal) L4, L5 roots from the {{c7::lumbosacral trunk}}, and the 1st, 2nd, and 3rd sacral ventral rami exits the pelvis through the {{c1::greater sciatic foramen}} below the {{c4::piriformis}} muscle between the {{c2::lesser trochanter}} and {{c2::ischial tuberosity}} . (bony landmarks) the nerve is deep to the [BLANK] m. and [BLANK] m. down the midline of the th",
    "answer": "gluteus maximus / biceps femoris",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1158
  },
  {
    "id": 425,
    "question": " Sciatic Nerve, course (tibial & peroneal) L4, L5 roots from the {{c7::lumbosacral trunk}}, and the 1st, 2nd, and 3rd sacral ventral rami exits the pelvis through the {{c1::greater sciatic foramen}} below the {{c4::piriformis}} muscle between the {{c2::lesser trochanter}} and {{c2::ischial tuberosity}} . (bony landmarks) the nerve is deep to the {{c5::gluteus maximus::pelvis}} m. and {{c5::biceps ",
    "answer": "shaft of the femur",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1158
  },
  {
    "id": 426,
    "question": " Sciatic Nerve, course (tibial & peroneal) L4, L5 roots from the {{c7::lumbosacral trunk}}, and the 1st, 2nd, and 3rd sacral ventral rami exits the pelvis through the {{c1::greater sciatic foramen}} below the {{c4::piriformis}} muscle between the {{c2::lesser trochanter}} and {{c2::ischial tuberosity}} . (bony landmarks) the nerve is deep to the {{c5::gluteus maximus::pelvis}} m. and {{c5::biceps ",
    "answer": "popliteal fossa",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1158
  },
  {
    "id": 427,
    "question": "Sciatic nerve muscle innervation in the thigh peroneal (fibular) division [BLANK] tibial division [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK]",
    "answer": "Short head biceps femoris / Long head biceps femoris / Semitendinosus / Semimembranosus / Adductor magnus (also obturator n.)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1159
  },
  {
    "id": 428,
    "question": " the [BLANK] division makes up the outer two-thirds of the sciatic nerve proper ",
    "answer": "peroneal",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1160
  },
  {
    "id": 429,
    "question": "[BLANK] is an uncommon type of compressive sciatic neuropathy at the pelvic outlet that mainly affects the {{c2::peroneal (fibular)}} portion of the nerve ",
    "answer": "Piriformis syndrome | Context:  Because there is no consensus on diagnosing piriformis syndrome, it is a dx of exclusion estimated incidence is approximately 4% ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1162
  },
  {
    "id": 430,
    "question": "{{c1::Piriformis syndrome}} is an uncommon type of compressive sciatic neuropathy at the pelvic outlet that mainly affects the [BLANK] portion of the nerve ",
    "answer": "peroneal (fibular) | Context:  Because there is no consensus on diagnosing piriformis syndrome, it is a dx of exclusion estimated incidence is approximately 4% ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1162
  },
  {
    "id": 431,
    "question": " Sciatic neuropathy Clinical presentation : primarily presents as weakness of [BLANK] and {{c1::muscles of the peroneal (foot drop) and tibial nerves * (plantar flexion)}} numbness occurs over the {{c2::lateral leg}} and the {{c2::entire foot}} The {{c3::lateral hamstring}} and {{c3::Achilles reflexes}} may be abnormal (physical examination) ",
    "answer": "knee flexion | Context:  Motor = hamstrings + foot drop (peroneal) + plantar flexion (gastroc) pt c/o depends on which portion of the nerve is more involved (can be peroneal alone) Sensory = peroneal + sural ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1163
  },
  {
    "id": 432,
    "question": " Sciatic neuropathy Clinical presentation : primarily presents as weakness of {{c1::knee flexion}} and {{c1::muscles of the peroneal (foot drop) and tibial nerves * (plantar flexion)}} numbness occurs over the [BLANK] and the [BLANK] The {{c3::lateral hamstring}} and {{c3::Achilles reflexes}} may be abnormal (physical examination) ",
    "answer": "lateral leg / entire foot | Context:  Motor = hamstrings + foot drop (peroneal) + plantar flexion (gastroc) pt c/o depends on which portion of the nerve is more involved (can be peroneal alone) Sensory = peroneal + sural ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1163
  },
  {
    "id": 433,
    "question": " Sciatic neuropathy Clinical presentation : primarily presents as weakness of {{c1::knee flexion}} and {{c1::muscles of the peroneal (foot drop) and tibial nerves * (plantar flexion)}} numbness occurs over the {{c2::lateral leg}} and the {{c2::entire foot}} The [BLANK] and [BLANK] may be abnormal (physical examination) ",
    "answer": "lateral hamstring / Achilles reflexes | Context:  Motor = hamstrings + foot drop (peroneal) + plantar flexion (gastroc) pt c/o depends on which portion of the nerve is more involved (can be peroneal alone) Sensory = peroneal + sural ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1163
  },
  {
    "id": 434,
    "question": " Sciatic neuropathy EDX findings : NCS SNAP: Abnormal [BLANK] CMAP: Abnormal [BLANK] EMG Abnormal activity in {{c1:: all sciatic innervated musculature 1.) hamstrings (eg. biceps femoris s/l + semi m/t), 2.) tibial n. (eg. gastroc + tib post), and 3.) c. peroneal n. (tib ant. + fib brevis/long)}} Normal activity in {{c5::gluteus medius (r/o plexopathy)}} and {{c5::lumbar paraspinals (r/o radiculop",
    "answer": "superficial peroneal (fibular) and sural sensory / tibial and comm. peroneal (fibular) motor studies | Context: **even if sciatic is injured in the thigh --> can be specificaly tibial or peroneal ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1164
  },
  {
    "id": 435,
    "question": " Sciatic neuropathy EDX findings : NCS SNAP: Abnormal {{c2:: superficial peroneal (fibular) and sural sensory}} CMAP: Abnormal {{c2::tibial and comm. peroneal (fibular) motor studies}} EMG Abnormal activity in [BLANK] Normal activity in {{c5::gluteus medius (r/o plexopathy)}} and {{c5::lumbar paraspinals (r/o radiculopathy)}} absent or delayed {{c4::H-reflex}} ",
    "answer": "<u>all</u> sciatic innervated musculature&nbsp;</div><div>1.) hamstrings (eg. biceps femoris s/l + semi m/t),&nbsp;</div><div>2.) tibial n. (eg. gastroc + tib post), and&nbsp;</div><div>3.) c. peroneal n. (tib ant. + fib brevis/long) | Context: **even if sciatic is injured in the thigh --> can be specificaly tibial or peroneal ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1164
  },
  {
    "id": 436,
    "question": " Sciatic neuropathy EDX findings : NCS SNAP: Abnormal {{c2:: superficial peroneal (fibular) and sural sensory}} CMAP: Abnormal {{c2::tibial and comm. peroneal (fibular) motor studies}} EMG Abnormal activity in {{c1:: all sciatic innervated musculature 1.) hamstrings (eg. biceps femoris s/l + semi m/t), 2.) tibial n. (eg. gastroc + tib post), and 3.) c. peroneal n. (tib ant. + fib brevis/long)}} No",
    "answer": "gluteus medius (r/o plexopathy) / lumbar paraspinals (r/o radiculopathy) | Context: **even if sciatic is injured in the thigh --> can be specificaly tibial or peroneal ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1164
  },
  {
    "id": 437,
    "question": " Sciatic neuropathy EDX findings : NCS SNAP: Abnormal {{c2:: superficial peroneal (fibular) and sural sensory}} CMAP: Abnormal {{c2::tibial and comm. peroneal (fibular) motor studies}} EMG Abnormal activity in {{c1:: all sciatic innervated musculature 1.) hamstrings (eg. biceps femoris s/l + semi m/t), 2.) tibial n. (eg. gastroc + tib post), and 3.) c. peroneal n. (tib ant. + fib brevis/long)}} No",
    "answer": "H-reflex | Context: **even if sciatic is injured in the thigh --> can be specificaly tibial or peroneal ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1164
  },
  {
    "id": 438,
    "question": "[BLANK] portion of the sciatic nerve is more vulnerable to injury ",
    "answer": "peroneal (fibular) | Context:  more vulnerable than the tibial because the peroneal portion is more fixated at the sciatic notch and at the fibula-neck. stretch It has larger fascicles with less protective epineural tissue and les...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1165
  },
  {
    "id": 439,
    "question": "[BLANK] skin of the distal [BLANK] of the leg, the skin overlying the [BLANK] {{c2::malleolus}}, and the [BLANK] aspect of the {{c2::foot}} and {{c2::little toe}} the {{c3::medial calcaneal}} branch supplies the skin of the {{c3::medial heel}} ",
    "answer": "lateral / third / lateral / lateral",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1188
  },
  {
    "id": 440,
    "question": "{{c1::lateral}} skin of the distal {{c1::third}} of the leg, the skin overlying the {{c1::lateral}} [BLANK], and the {{c1::lateral}} aspect of the [BLANK] and [BLANK] the {{c3::medial calcaneal}} branch supplies the skin of the {{c3::medial heel}} ",
    "answer": "malleolus / foot / little toe",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1188
  },
  {
    "id": 441,
    "question": "{{c1::lateral}} skin of the distal {{c1::third}} of the leg, the skin overlying the {{c1::lateral}} {{c2::malleolus}}, and the {{c1::lateral}} aspect of the {{c2::foot}} and {{c2::little toe}} the [BLANK] branch supplies the skin of the [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "medial calcaneal / medial heel",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1188
  },
  {
    "id": 442,
    "question": "Tibial N. innervates Superficial/proximal [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] Deep/distal {{c2::Tibialis posterior (TP)}} {{c2::Flexor digitorum longus (FDL)}} {{c2::Flexor hallucis longus (FHL)}}",
    "answer": "Popliteus / Plantaris / Gastrocnemius / Soleus",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1189
  },
  {
    "id": 443,
    "question": "Tibial N. innervates Superficial/proximal {{c1::Popliteus}} {{c1::Plantaris}} {{c1::Gastrocnemius}} {{c1::Soleus}} Deep/distal [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK]",
    "answer": "Tibialis posterior (TP) / Flexor digitorum longus (FDL) / Flexor hallucis longus (FHL)",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1189
  },
  {
    "id": 444,
    "question": "Tibial nerve innervates m. (distal to tarsal tunnel) Medial plantar nerve [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] Sensory branch Lateral plantar nerve {{c2::Lumbricals}} {{c2::Interossei}} {{c2::Quadratus plantae}} {{c2::Abductor digiti minimi}} {{c2::Flexor digiti minimi}} {{c2::Adductor hallucis}} Sensory branches Calcaneal nerve Sensory branch",
    "answer": "Abductor hallucis / Flexor hallucis brevis / Flexor digitorum brevis / 1st Lumbrical",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1190
  },
  {
    "id": 445,
    "question": "Tibial nerve innervates m. (distal to tarsal tunnel) Medial plantar nerve {{c1::Abductor hallucis}} {{c1::Flexor hallucis brevis}} {{c1::Flexor digitorum brevis}} {{c1::1st Lumbrical}} Sensory branch Lateral plantar nerve [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] Sensory branches Calcaneal nerve Sensory branch",
    "answer": "Lumbricals / Interossei / Quadratus plantae / Abductor digiti minimi / Flexor digiti minimi / Adductor hallucis",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1190
  },
  {
    "id": 446,
    "question": "[BLANK]: tibial n. injured by compression under the flexor retinaculum in the medial ankle ",
    "answer": "tarsal tunnel sndrome | Context: prety rare (la chupacabra) ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1191
  },
  {
    "id": 447,
    "question": " Tarsal tunnel syndrome Clinical presentation Involves all muscles innervated by the tibial nerve distal to the tarsal tunnel. thus patient may complain of symptoms related to [BLANK] pain, numbness, and paresthesias may involve the medial {{c2::Perimalleolar}} area and entire {{c2::sole}} It is reproduced by {{c3::ankle inversion}} positive Tinel’s sign at the medial ankle may be elicited ",
    "answer": "intrinsic foot weakness | Context: Heel sensation may be spared due to the calcaneal branch departing proximal to the tunnel Foot atrophy / intrinsic weakness difficult to detect clinically ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1192
  },
  {
    "id": 448,
    "question": " Tarsal tunnel syndrome Clinical presentation Involves all muscles innervated by the tibial nerve distal to the tarsal tunnel. thus patient may complain of symptoms related to {{c1::intrinsic foot weakness}} pain, numbness, and paresthesias may involve the medial [BLANK] area and entire [BLANK] It is reproduced by {{c3::ankle inversion}} positive Tinel’s sign at the medial ankle may be elicited ",
    "answer": "Perimalleolar / sole | Context: Heel sensation may be spared due to the calcaneal branch departing proximal to the tunnel Foot atrophy / intrinsic weakness difficult to detect clinically ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1192
  },
  {
    "id": 449,
    "question": " Tarsal tunnel syndrome Clinical presentation Involves all muscles innervated by the tibial nerve distal to the tarsal tunnel. thus patient may complain of symptoms related to {{c1::intrinsic foot weakness}} pain, numbness, and paresthesias may involve the medial {{c2::Perimalleolar}} area and entire {{c2::sole}} It is reproduced by [BLANK] positive Tinel’s sign at the medial ankle may be elicited",
    "answer": "ankle inversion | Context: Heel sensation may be spared due to the calcaneal branch departing proximal to the tunnel Foot atrophy / intrinsic weakness difficult to detect clinically ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1192
  },
  {
    "id": 450,
    "question": " Tarsal tunnel, EDX findings : NCS SNAP: Abnormal [BLANK]. Normal [BLANK] CMAP: Abnormal [BLANK] EMG Abnormal activity in {{c2::all tibial n. foot muscles (entire sole of foot)}} ",
    "answer": "medial and lateral plantar nerve / calcaneal nerve / medial and lateral plantar nerve | Context:  \"\"i imagine sural sensory is normal??\"\" \"\"conduction block: Tibial motor would be abnl at ankle and knee\"\" * ( Mixed Study : not often done, technicaly difficult, often small or absent response) ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1193
  },
  {
    "id": 451,
    "question": " Tarsal tunnel, EDX findings : NCS SNAP: Abnormal {{c1::medial and lateral plantar nerve::2 same}}. Normal {{c1::calcaneal nerve}} CMAP: Abnormal {{c1::medial and lateral plantar nerve::2 same}} EMG Abnormal activity in [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "all tibial n. foot muscles (entire sole of foot) | Context:  \"\"i imagine sural sensory is normal??\"\" \"\"conduction block: Tibial motor would be abnl at ankle and knee\"\" * ( Mixed Study : not often done, technicaly difficult, often small or absent response) ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1193
  },
  {
    "id": 452,
    "question": "contents of the Tarsal tunnel [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK]",
    "answer": "Tibialis Posterior / flexor Digitorum longus / Post. Tib A. / Post. Tib V. / Tibial N. / Flexor Hallucis longus",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1194
  },
  {
    "id": 453,
    "question": " Superficial Peroneal (Fibular) Nerve innervates : (2 motor 2 sensory) [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "Peroneus longus / Peroneus brevis / Medial cutaneous nerve (foot dorsum) / Lateral cutaneous nerve (foot dorsum)",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1213
  },
  {
    "id": 454,
    "question": " Deep Peroneal (Fibular) Nerve innervates : Leg [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] Foot {{c2::Peroneus tertius}} {{c2::Extensor Digitorum Brevis}} {{c2::First dorsal interossei}} {{c2::Dorsal digital cutaneous n. (1st Web-space)::sensory}} ",
    "answer": "Tibialis Anterior / Extensor Digitorum Longus / Extensor Hallucis Longus",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1214
  },
  {
    "id": 455,
    "question": " Deep Peroneal (Fibular) Nerve innervates : Leg {{c1::Tibialis Anterior}} {{c1::Extensor Digitorum Longus}} {{c1::Extensor Hallucis Longus}} Foot [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "Peroneus tertius / Extensor Digitorum Brevis / First dorsal interossei / Dorsal digital cutaneous n. (1st Web-space)",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1214
  },
  {
    "id": 456,
    "question": " Peroneal nerve injury Etiology [BLANK] {{c2::rapid weight loss (slimmer's paralysis)}} {{c3::positioning during surgery}} {{c4::cast application/tight boots (ski-boot palsy)}} {{c5::prolonged squatting position (strawberry pickers’ palsy)}} common {{c6::metabolic disorders (diabetes, etoh use, etc.)}} {{c6::trauma (to the knee or fibula)}} ",
    "answer": "prolonged leg crossing",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1215
  },
  {
    "id": 457,
    "question": " Peroneal nerve injury Etiology {{c1::prolonged leg crossing}} [BLANK] {{c3::positioning during surgery}} {{c4::cast application/tight boots (ski-boot palsy)}} {{c5::prolonged squatting position (strawberry pickers’ palsy)}} common {{c6::metabolic disorders (diabetes, etoh use, etc.)}} {{c6::trauma (to the knee or fibula)}} ",
    "answer": "rapid weight loss (slimmer's paralysis)",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1215
  },
  {
    "id": 458,
    "question": " Peroneal nerve injury Etiology {{c1::prolonged leg crossing}} {{c2::rapid weight loss (slimmer's paralysis)}} [BLANK] {{c4::cast application/tight boots (ski-boot palsy)}} {{c5::prolonged squatting position (strawberry pickers’ palsy)}} common {{c6::metabolic disorders (diabetes, etoh use, etc.)}} {{c6::trauma (to the knee or fibula)}} ",
    "answer": "positioning during surgery",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1215
  },
  {
    "id": 459,
    "question": " Peroneal nerve injury Etiology {{c1::prolonged leg crossing}} {{c2::rapid weight loss (slimmer's paralysis)}} {{c3::positioning during surgery}} [BLANK] {{c5::prolonged squatting position (strawberry pickers’ palsy)}} common {{c6::metabolic disorders (diabetes, etoh use, etc.)}} {{c6::trauma (to the knee or fibula)}} ",
    "answer": "cast application/tight boots (ski-boot palsy)",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1215
  },
  {
    "id": 460,
    "question": " Peroneal nerve injury Etiology {{c1::prolonged leg crossing}} {{c2::rapid weight loss (slimmer's paralysis)}} {{c3::positioning during surgery}} {{c4::cast application/tight boots (ski-boot palsy)}} [BLANK] common {{c6::metabolic disorders (diabetes, etoh use, etc.)}} {{c6::trauma (to the knee or fibula)}} ",
    "answer": "prolonged squatting position (strawberry pickers’ palsy)",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1215
  },
  {
    "id": 461,
    "question": " Peroneal nerve injury Etiology {{c1::prolonged leg crossing}} {{c2::rapid weight loss (slimmer's paralysis)}} {{c3::positioning during surgery}} {{c4::cast application/tight boots (ski-boot palsy)}} {{c5::prolonged squatting position (strawberry pickers’ palsy)}} common [BLANK] [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "metabolic disorders (diabetes, etoh use, etc.) / trauma (to the knee or fibula)",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1215
  },
  {
    "id": 462,
    "question": " Weakness of only the ankle dorsiflexors and {{c1:: ankle evertors}} helps to clinically differentiate a [BLANK] nerve injury from a/an: [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "common peroneal (fibular) / L5 radiculopathy / Lumbar Plexopathy / Sciatic Neuropathy",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1225
  },
  {
    "id": 463,
    "question": " Common peroneal neuropathy EDX findings : NCS SNAP Abnormal [BLANK] Normal [BLANK] CMAP: Abnormal {{c2::above fibular head::conduction block}} Normal at {{c2::ankle and below fibular head::conduction block}} EMG Abnormal activity muscles innervated by the {{c3:: both superficial and deep peroneal nerves::2}} ex. {{c3::Tibialis Anterior, extensor hallucis longus}} ex. {{c3::Peroneus longus/brevis}",
    "answer": "superficial peroneal (fibular) / Sural nerve",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1233
  },
  {
    "id": 464,
    "question": " Common peroneal neuropathy EDX findings : NCS SNAP Abnormal {{c5::superficial peroneal (fibular)}} Normal {{c5::Sural nerve}} CMAP: Abnormal [BLANK] Normal at [BLANK] EMG Abnormal activity muscles innervated by the {{c3:: both superficial and deep peroneal nerves::2}} ex. {{c3::Tibialis Anterior, extensor hallucis longus}} ex. {{c3::Peroneus longus/brevis}} Normal activity in {{c4::biceps femoris",
    "answer": "above fibular head / ankle and below fibular head",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1233
  },
  {
    "id": 465,
    "question": " Common peroneal neuropathy EDX findings : NCS SNAP Abnormal {{c5::superficial peroneal (fibular)}} Normal {{c5::Sural nerve}} CMAP: Abnormal {{c2::above fibular head::conduction block}} Normal at {{c2::ankle and below fibular head::conduction block}} EMG Abnormal activity muscles innervated by the [BLANK] ex. [BLANK] ex. [BLANK] Normal activity in {{c4::biceps femoris-short (sciatic nerve, perone",
    "answer": "both superficial and deep peroneal nerves / Tibialis Anterior, extensor hallucis longus / Peroneus longus/brevis",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1233
  },
  {
    "id": 466,
    "question": " Common peroneal neuropathy EDX findings : NCS SNAP Abnormal {{c5::superficial peroneal (fibular)}} Normal {{c5::Sural nerve}} CMAP: Abnormal {{c2::above fibular head::conduction block}} Normal at {{c2::ankle and below fibular head::conduction block}} EMG Abnormal activity muscles innervated by the {{c3:: both superficial and deep peroneal nerves::2}} ex. {{c3::Tibialis Anterior, extensor hallucis",
    "answer": "biceps femoris-short (sciatic nerve, peroneal (fibular) division \"\"proximal extent\"\") / Gastroc (S1, S2) [r/o sciatic involvement] / Tibialis posterior (L5, S1) [r/o L5 radic]",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1233
  },
  {
    "id": 467,
    "question": "Common peroneal nerve NCS the [BLANK] can be used if the EDB is atrophied ",
    "answer": "TA",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1234
  },
  {
    "id": 468,
    "question": " DEEP PERONEAL (FIBULAR) NEUROPATHY AKA [BLANK] refers to entrapment of the deep peroneal (fibular) nerve under the {{c2::inferior extensor retinaculum}} of the ankle ",
    "answer": "anterior tarsal tunnel syndrome",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1245
  },
  {
    "id": 469,
    "question": " DEEP PERONEAL (FIBULAR) NEUROPATHY AKA {{c1::anterior tarsal tunnel syndrome}} refers to entrapment of the deep peroneal (fibular) nerve under the [BLANK] of the ankle ",
    "answer": "inferior extensor retinaculum",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1245
  },
  {
    "id": 470,
    "question": " anterior tarsal tunnel syndrome clinical presentation may have weakness, and atrophy of the [BLANK] numbness and paresthesias in the [BLANK] Pain may be located over the {{c2::dorsum of the foot}} that is relieved with {{c2::motion}} ",
    "answer": "EDB / 1st / 2nd web space",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1246
  },
  {
    "id": 471,
    "question": " anterior tarsal tunnel syndrome clinical presentation may have weakness, and atrophy of the {{c1::EDB}} numbness and paresthesias in the {{c1::1st / 2nd web space}} Pain may be located over the [BLANK] that is relieved with [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "dorsum of the foot / motion",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1246
  },
  {
    "id": 472,
    "question": " anterior tarsal tunnel syndrome EDX findings: NCS SNAP: Abnormal [BLANK] Normal [BLANK] CMAP: Abnormal {{c2::common peroneal (fibular) Motor ALL sites (Ankle & a/b fib)}} (Conduction Block) EMG Abnormal activity in {{c3::deep peroneal (fibular) innervated muscles below the ankle (ie EDB)}} ",
    "answer": "deep peroneal (fibular) (Abnormal findings to the first web space <font color=\"\"#fc0006\"\">[Never seen this done]</font>) / superficial peroneal",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1247
  },
  {
    "id": 473,
    "question": " anterior tarsal tunnel syndrome EDX findings: NCS SNAP: Abnormal {{c1::deep peroneal (fibular) (Abnormal findings to the first web space [Never seen this done] )}} Normal {{c1::superficial peroneal}} CMAP: Abnormal [BLANK] (Conduction Block) EMG Abnormal activity in {{c3::deep peroneal (fibular) innervated muscles below the ankle (ie EDB)}} ",
    "answer": "common peroneal (fibular) Motor <u>ALL</u> sites (Ankle &amp; a/b fib)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1247
  },
  {
    "id": 474,
    "question": " anterior tarsal tunnel syndrome EDX findings: NCS SNAP: Abnormal {{c1::deep peroneal (fibular) (Abnormal findings to the first web space [Never seen this done] )}} Normal {{c1::superficial peroneal}} CMAP: Abnormal {{c2::common peroneal (fibular) Motor ALL sites (Ankle & a/b fib)}} (Conduction Block) EMG Abnormal activity in [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "deep peroneal (fibular) innervated muscles below the ankle&nbsp;</div><div>(ie EDB)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1247
  },
  {
    "id": 475,
    "question": "SUPERFICIAL PERONEAL (FIBULAR) NEUROPATHY Clinical presentation: c/o of pain, numbness, and/or paresthesias or loss of sensation in [BLANK] and [BLANK] except for the [BLANK] {{c2::Foot eversion}} weakness can also be noted ",
    "answer": "distal anterolateral calf / dorsal foot / 1st webspace",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1248
  },
  {
    "id": 476,
    "question": "SUPERFICIAL PERONEAL (FIBULAR) NEUROPATHY Clinical presentation: c/o of pain, numbness, and/or paresthesias or loss of sensation in {{c1::distal anterolateral calf}} and {{c1::dorsal foot}} except for the {{c1::1st webspace}} [BLANK] weakness can also be noted ",
    "answer": "Foot eversion",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1248
  },
  {
    "id": 477,
    "question": " superficial peroneal neuropathy EDX findings NCS SNAP: Abnormal [BLANK] Normal [BLANK] CMAP: Normal [BLANK] [BLANK] EMG Abnormal activity in {{c2::peroneus longus and/or peroneus brevis}} normal findings in {{c2::deep peroneal (fibular) nerve innervated muscles ie Tib. Ant.}} ",
    "answer": "superficial peroneal (fibular) sensory / sural sensory / common peroneal Motor (from deep fib) / Tibial Motor&nbsp;</div><div>(Superficial peroneal motor, not available)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1249
  },
  {
    "id": 478,
    "question": " superficial peroneal neuropathy EDX findings NCS SNAP: Abnormal {{c1::superficial peroneal (fibular) sensory}} Normal {{c1::sural sensory}} CMAP: Normal {{c1::common peroneal Motor (from deep fib)}} {{c1::Tibial Motor (Superficial peroneal motor, not available)}} EMG Abnormal activity in [BLANK] normal findings in [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "peroneus longus and/or peroneus brevis / deep peroneal (fibular) nerve innervated muscles ie Tib. Ant.",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1249
  },
  {
    "id": 479,
    "question": " [BLANK] nerve: anomalous branch from the [BLANK] nerve that travels {{c2::posterior}} to the {{c2::lateral malleolus}} to innervate some or all of the {{c3::extensor digitorum brevis (EDB)}} ",
    "answer": "accessory peroneal (fibular) / superficial peroneal (fibular)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1250
  },
  {
    "id": 480,
    "question": " {{c1::accessory peroneal (fibular)}} nerve: anomalous branch from the {{c1::superficial peroneal (fibular)}} nerve that travels [BLANK] to the [BLANK] to innervate some or all of the {{c3::extensor digitorum brevis (EDB)}} ",
    "answer": "posterior / lateral malleolus",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1250
  },
  {
    "id": 481,
    "question": " {{c1::accessory peroneal (fibular)}} nerve: anomalous branch from the {{c1::superficial peroneal (fibular)}} nerve that travels {{c2::posterior}} to the {{c2::lateral malleolus}} to innervate some or all of the [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "extensor digitorum brevis (EDB)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1250
  },
  {
    "id": 482,
    "question": " accessory peroneal (fibular) n. can be confirmed by [BLANK]",
    "answer": "stimulating posterior to the lateral malleolus | Context: This will elicit the “missing” CMAP from the EDB. ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1261
  },
  {
    "id": 483,
    "question": " accessory peroneal n. with this anomalous innervation... the EDB can be spared with a [BLANK] nerve injury ",
    "answer": "deep peroneal (aka anterior tarsal tunnel)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1281
  },
  {
    "id": 484,
    "question": " sural n. fibers originate from branches of the [BLANK] and {{c2::common peroneal (fibular)}} nerves ",
    "answer": "tibial",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1282
  },
  {
    "id": 485,
    "question": " sural n. fibers originate from branches of the {{c1::tibial}} and [BLANK] nerves ",
    "answer": "common peroneal (fibular)",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1282
  },
  {
    "id": 486,
    "question": " SURAL NEUROPATHY, Etiology : [BLANK] {{c2::Baker’s/ganglion cyst}} trauma (e.g., laceration) ",
    "answer": "compression from tight socks",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1283
  },
  {
    "id": 487,
    "question": " SURAL NEUROPATHY, Etiology : {{c1::compression from tight socks}} [BLANK] trauma (e.g., laceration) ",
    "answer": "Baker’s/ganglion cyst",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1283
  },
  {
    "id": 488,
    "question": "sural neuropathy, EDX findings : NCS SNAP: [BLANK] CMAP: [BLANK] EMG [BLANK]",
    "answer": "Abnormal&nbsp;sural sensory / not applicable / Not applicable | Context: Decreased or absent sural responses can be seen as a normal finding in elderly patients ( Tavee et al., 2013 ). ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1284
  },
  {
    "id": 489,
    "question": " gluteal n. injury clinical pres superior gluteal neuropathy: presents with weakness of [BLANK] and [BLANK]. {{c2::Trendelenburg gait::phys-ex}} will be seen inferior gluteal neuropathy: presents with weakness of [BLANK]. ",
    "answer": "hip abduction / internal/external rotation / hip extension",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1297
  },
  {
    "id": 490,
    "question": " gluteal n. injury clinical pres superior gluteal neuropathy: presents with weakness of {{c1::hip abduction}} and {{c1::internal/external rotation}}. [BLANK] will be seen inferior gluteal neuropathy: presents with weakness of {{c1::hip extension}}. ",
    "answer": "Trendelenburg gait",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1297
  },
  {
    "id": 491,
    "question": "Obturator n. injury During ambulation, they present with a [BLANK] and [BLANK] gait",
    "answer": "wide-based / circumducting | Context: becuase the hip is externally rotated and abnormally abducted...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1319
  },
  {
    "id": 492,
    "question": " Obturator neuroptathy, E DX findings : NCS SNAP: [BLANK] CMAP: [BLANK] EMG Abnormal activity: {{c2::in the obturator n. innervated m's (eg. adductor’s & gracillus)}} ",
    "answer": "None available / None available",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1320
  },
  {
    "id": 493,
    "question": " Obturator neuroptathy, E DX findings : NCS SNAP: {{c1::None available}} CMAP: {{c1::None available}} EMG Abnormal activity: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "in the obturator n. innervated m's (eg. adductor’s &amp; gracillus)",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1320
  },
  {
    "id": 494,
    "question": " Peripheral Neuropathies categorized based on distribution effected they can be described as [BLANK] or [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "diffuse / multifocal",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1321
  },
  {
    "id": 495,
    "question": "Inherited Peripheral Neuropathies typically categorized as : [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK]",
    "answer": "Hereditary motor and sensory neuropathies (HMSN) / Hereditary sensory and autonomic neuropathies (HSAN) / Hereditary motor neuropathies (HMN) | Context:  based on the presentation s ubclassification is based on inheritance pattern and EDX findings (demyelinating vs. axonal) Specific gene mutation is also relevant ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1322
  },
  {
    "id": 496,
    "question": " [BLANK] aka {{c2::Charcot–Marie–Tooth}} disease is the most commonly inherited peripheral polyneuropathy due to duplication mutation of the {{c3::PMP -22 }} gene, l ocated within the chromosome {{c4::17p11. 2}} ",
    "answer": "HMSN",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1323
  },
  {
    "id": 497,
    "question": " {{c1::HMSN}} aka [BLANK] disease is the most commonly inherited peripheral polyneuropathy due to duplication mutation of the {{c3::PMP -22 }} gene, l ocated within the chromosome {{c4::17p11. 2}} ",
    "answer": "Charcot–Marie–Tooth",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1323
  },
  {
    "id": 498,
    "question": "Acquired Peripheral Neuropathies [BLANK] can manifest as a polyradiculopathy ",
    "answer": "Demyelinating inflammatory neuropathies | Context:  Polyradiculopathy refers to the condition where more than one spinal nerve root is affected ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1325
  },
  {
    "id": 499,
    "question": " EMG/NCS diagnostic criteria for peripheral neuropathy consists of evaluating at least [BLANK]",
    "answer": "three limbs | Context:  Abnormalities of SNAPs , CMAPs , and MUAPs are dependent on the type and timing of the pathology affecting a nerve ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1328
  },
  {
    "id": 500,
    "question": " Peripheral Neuropathy EDX abnormalities can include : Prolonged latencies (o/l) Increased conduction velocities (CV) Reduced or absent amplitudes (uv) Decreased [BLANK] (“missing” waveforms on {{c3::repetitive::same}} stimulations) Increased {{c2::chronodispersion}} (large latency difference between the fastest and slowest waveform on {{c3::repetitive::same}} stimulation \"\"duration\"\") ",
    "answer": "persistence",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1329
  },
  {
    "id": 501,
    "question": " Peripheral Neuropathy EDX abnormalities can include : Prolonged latencies (o/l) Increased conduction velocities (CV) Reduced or absent amplitudes (uv) Decreased {{c1::persistence}} (“missing” waveforms on [BLANK] stimulations) Increased {{c2::chronodispersion}} (large latency difference between the fastest and slowest waveform on [BLANK] stimulation \"\"duration\"\") ",
    "answer": "repetitive / repetitive",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1329
  },
  {
    "id": 502,
    "question": " Peripheral Neuropathy EDX abnormalities can include : Prolonged latencies (o/l) Increased conduction velocities (CV) Reduced or absent amplitudes (uv) Decreased {{c1::persistence}} (“missing” waveforms on {{c3::repetitive::same}} stimulations) Increased [BLANK] (large latency difference between the fastest and slowest waveform on {{c3::repetitive::same}} stimulation \"\"duration\"\") ",
    "answer": "chronodispersion",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1329
  },
  {
    "id": 503,
    "question": "Ddx Foot Drop {{c1::Central: Tumor, cerebrovascular accident (CVA), arteriovenous malformation (AVM), spinal cord injury (SCI)}} {{c2::Radiculopathy: L4–L5::2}} [BLANK] {{c4::Mononeuropathy: peroneal (fibular) portion of the sciatic nerve, common peroneal (fibular), deep peroneal (fibular)::3}} {{c5::Diffuse polyneuropathy: Diabetes}}",
    "answer": "Plexopathy",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1330
  },
  {
    "id": 504,
    "question": "In addition to Charcot–Marie–Tooth disease the PMP-22 gene is also implicated in hereditary neuropathy with [BLANK]. which presents with {{c2::recurrent}} and {{c2::short-term}} episodes of motor and sensory mononeuropathies",
    "answer": "liability to pressure palsy (HNPP) | Context: last from hours to a few weeks typically noted in regions of entrapments or from mild trauma...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1331
  },
  {
    "id": 505,
    "question": "In addition to Charcot–Marie–Tooth disease the PMP-22 gene is also implicated in hereditary neuropathy with {{c1::liability to pressure palsy (HNPP)}}. which presents with [BLANK] and [BLANK] episodes of motor and sensory mononeuropathies",
    "answer": "recurrent / short-term | Context: last from hours to a few weeks typically noted in regions of entrapments or from mild trauma...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1331
  },
  {
    "id": 506,
    "question": " NCS in peripheral neruopathy Conduction Block is more likely to be seen in [BLANK] polyneuropathies ",
    "answer": "acquired | Context: as well as focal slowing and temporal dispersions -see 2nd table ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1332
  },
  {
    "id": 507,
    "question": "peripheral neuropathies classicaly present with stocking-glove pattern Though less common, [BLANK] may demonstrate abnormalities first",
    "answer": "the upper limbs | Context: can occur in... vasculitic neuropathies chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyradiculopathy (CIDP) HNPP toxicity porphyria inflammatory neuropathies diabetes mellitus, etc....",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1333
  },
  {
    "id": 508,
    "question": "nerve [BLANK] roots ",
    "answer": "L5, S1 | Context:  deep fib -> common fib -> peroneal division of the sciatic -> sacral plexus ...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1347
  },
  {
    "id": 509,
    "question": " [BLANK] needle electrode ",
    "answer": "Single-fiber | Context:  This is a needle (reference) consisting of an exposed 25-μm diameter wire (active) it has an active electrode as a side prot pik up and the cannula is the reference Advantages : Looks at individual m...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1348
  },
  {
    "id": 510,
    "question": " EMG Special Studies Small nerve fiber abnormalities and associated [BLANK] dysfunction may not be seen with conventional NCS and can require additional tests ",
    "answer": "autonomic | Context:  These may be considered in patients with systemic symptoms such as: orthostatic blood pressure changes, dry scaly skin, dry eyes, dry mouth, etc sounds like there is a sural n biopsy and mayo send ou...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1349
  },
  {
    "id": 511,
    "question": " [BLANK] Peripheral Neuropathy ddx (broad categories) {{c5::HMSN-II::inherited disorder}} {{c1::Heavy metals: Lead, Gold, Mercury}} {{c2::Cancer drugs: Vincristine, Cis-platinum}} {{c3:: Metabolic derangements: alcohol, B12 d eficiency, folate deficiency }} {{c4::Auto-immune: paraneoplastic syndrome, Sjogren's, Crohn's, Sarcoidosis }} ",
    "answer": "Axonal | Context:  Lyme, HIV, AIDP, +/- amyloid can cause both axonal and demyelination ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1351
  },
  {
    "id": 512,
    "question": " {{c6::Axonal}} Peripheral Neuropathy ddx (broad categories) [BLANK] {{c1::Heavy metals: Lead, Gold, Mercury}} {{c2::Cancer drugs: Vincristine, Cis-platinum}} {{c3:: Metabolic derangements: alcohol, B12 d eficiency, folate deficiency }} {{c4::Auto-immune: paraneoplastic syndrome, Sjogren's, Crohn's, Sarcoidosis }} ",
    "answer": "HMSN-II | Context:  Lyme, HIV, AIDP, +/- amyloid can cause both axonal and demyelination ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1351
  },
  {
    "id": 513,
    "question": " HMSN I: CHARCOT-MARIE-TOOTH Edx Findings NCS SNAP: Abnormal CMAP: Abnormal, CV decreased by [BLANK]% No {{c2::temporal dispersion}} No {{c2::conduction block}} No {{c2::focal slowing (diffuse slowing}} EMG {{c3::Normal}} ",
    "answer": "70 | Context:  CMAP *temporal dispersion and CB are indicative of an aquired neuropathy ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1352
  },
  {
    "id": 514,
    "question": " HMSN I: CHARCOT-MARIE-TOOTH Edx Findings NCS SNAP: Abnormal CMAP: Abnormal, CV decreased by {{c1::70}}% No [BLANK] No [BLANK] No [BLANK] EMG {{c3::Normal}} ",
    "answer": "temporal dispersion / conduction block / focal slowing (diffuse slowing | Context:  CMAP *temporal dispersion and CB are indicative of an aquired neuropathy ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1352
  },
  {
    "id": 515,
    "question": " HMSN I: CHARCOT-MARIE-TOOTH Edx Findings NCS SNAP: Abnormal CMAP: Abnormal, CV decreased by {{c1::70}}% No {{c2::temporal dispersion}} No {{c2::conduction block}} No {{c2::focal slowing (diffuse slowing}} EMG [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "Normal | Context:  CMAP *temporal dispersion and CB are indicative of an aquired neuropathy ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1352
  },
  {
    "id": 516,
    "question": " AIDP (GBS) and CIDP Edx findings NCS SNAP: [BLANK] CMAP: [BLANK] CV / o/p latecny [BLANK]: amplitude NCS CMAP will be positive for {{c1::temporal dispersion}} {{c1::conduction block}} {{c1::focal slowing}} {{c2::F-wave}}: {{c4::Abnormal—first EDX sign}} EMG [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "Abnormal / Abnormal / normal (unless poor prognosis) / typically Normal (unless axonal variant) | Context:  autoimmune response targets Schwann cells (responsible for producing myelin sheath of peripheral nerves) segmental demyelination throughout peripheral nerves SNAP: absent or slowed CMAP: increased di...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1353
  },
  {
    "id": 517,
    "question": " AIDP (GBS) and CIDP Edx findings NCS SNAP: {{c3::Abnormal}} CMAP: {{c3::Abnormal}} CV / o/p latecny {{c3::normal (unless poor prognosis)}}: amplitude NCS CMAP will be positive for [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK] {{c2::F-wave}}: {{c4::Abnormal—first EDX sign}} EMG {{c3::typically Normal (unless axonal variant)}} ",
    "answer": "temporal dispersion / conduction block / focal slowing | Context:  autoimmune response targets Schwann cells (responsible for producing myelin sheath of peripheral nerves) segmental demyelination throughout peripheral nerves SNAP: absent or slowed CMAP: increased di...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1353
  },
  {
    "id": 518,
    "question": " AIDP (GBS) and CIDP Edx findings NCS SNAP: {{c3::Abnormal}} CMAP: {{c3::Abnormal}} CV / o/p latecny {{c3::normal (unless poor prognosis)}}: amplitude NCS CMAP will be positive for {{c1::temporal dispersion}} {{c1::conduction block}} {{c1::focal slowing}} [BLANK]: {{c4::Abnormal—first EDX sign}} EMG {{c3::typically Normal (unless axonal variant)}} ",
    "answer": "F-wave | Context:  autoimmune response targets Schwann cells (responsible for producing myelin sheath of peripheral nerves) segmental demyelination throughout peripheral nerves SNAP: absent or slowed CMAP: increased di...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1353
  },
  {
    "id": 519,
    "question": " AIDP (GBS) and CIDP Edx findings NCS SNAP: {{c3::Abnormal}} CMAP: {{c3::Abnormal}} CV / o/p latecny {{c3::normal (unless poor prognosis)}}: amplitude NCS CMAP will be positive for {{c1::temporal dispersion}} {{c1::conduction block}} {{c1::focal slowing}} {{c2::F-wave}}: [BLANK] EMG {{c3::typically Normal (unless axonal variant)}} ",
    "answer": "Abnormal—first&nbsp;EDX&nbsp;sign | Context:  autoimmune response targets Schwann cells (responsible for producing myelin sheath of peripheral nerves) segmental demyelination throughout peripheral nerves SNAP: absent or slowed CMAP: increased di...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1353
  },
  {
    "id": 520,
    "question": " AIDP (GBS) and CIDP Edx findings Poorer prognosis if : CMAP: Amplitude <[BLANK]% of normal NCV <[BLANK]% of normal {{c3::F-wave: Absent}} EMG : {{c2::Abnormal activity (axonal involvement)}} ",
    "answer": "20 / 40",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1354
  },
  {
    "id": 521,
    "question": " AIDP (GBS) and CIDP Edx findings Poorer prognosis if : CMAP: Amplitude <{{c1::20}}% of normal NCV <{{c1::40}}% of normal {{c3::F-wave: Absent}} EMG : [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "Abnormal activity (axonal involvement)",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1354
  },
  {
    "id": 522,
    "question": " HIV -Related Neuropathies [BLANK] : most common type of neuropathy primarily affects {{c2::sensory}} and {{c2::autonomic}} fibers paresthesias begin in the {{c3::toes}} followed by the {{c3::fingers}} ",
    "answer": "Distal Symmetric Poly-neuropathy",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1355
  },
  {
    "id": 523,
    "question": " HIV -Related Neuropathies {{c1::Distal Symmetric Poly-neuropathy}} : most common type of neuropathy primarily affects [BLANK] and [BLANK] fibers paresthesias begin in the {{c3::toes}} followed by the {{c3::fingers}} ",
    "answer": "sensory / autonomic",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1355
  },
  {
    "id": 524,
    "question": " HIV -Related Neuropathies {{c1::Distal Symmetric Poly-neuropathy}} : most common type of neuropathy primarily affects {{c2::sensory}} and {{c2::autonomic}} fibers paresthesias begin in the [BLANK] followed by the [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "toes / fingers",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1355
  },
  {
    "id": 525,
    "question": " NMJ disorders hinder the production, release, or uptake of ACh a low [BLANK] causes the amplitude of the {{c2::endplate potentials}} to fall below the threshold needed to generate a muscle fiber AP This occurs due to an alteration of quantal response or content ",
    "answer": "safety factor | Context:  safety factor: a measure of how much larger the endplate potential is compared to the threshold potential necessary to trigger an action potential through the activation of voltage gated sodium chann...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1356
  },
  {
    "id": 526,
    "question": " NMJ disorders hinder the production, release, or uptake of ACh a low {{c1::safety factor}} causes the amplitude of the [BLANK] to fall below the threshold needed to generate a muscle fiber AP This occurs due to an alteration of quantal response or content ",
    "answer": "endplate potentials | Context:  safety factor: a measure of how much larger the endplate potential is compared to the threshold potential necessary to trigger an action potential through the activation of voltage gated sodium chann...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1356
  },
  {
    "id": 527,
    "question": " Myasthenia gravis ( MG ): disorder resulting in a decreased quantal response due to an autoimmune response against postsynaptic ACh receptors leads to [BLANK] {{c1:: miniature endplate potential ( MEPP ) }} amplitudes , and [BLANK] frequency (quantal content is normal) ",
    "answer": "reduced / normal | Context:  Postsynaptic membrane changes . MG —Simplification of the postsynaptic membrane. The NMJ demonstrates a reduction in the number of postsynaptic junctional folds. MS —Hypertrophy of postsynaptic membr...",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1357
  },
  {
    "id": 528,
    "question": " MG pathophys disorder of neuromuscular transmission due to an autoimmune response in which polyclonal antibodies are directed against the Muscle Specific Tyrosine Kinase ( MuSK ) of the [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "postsynaptic membrane",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1359
  },
  {
    "id": 529,
    "question": "LEMS pathophys disorder of neuromuscular transmission due to an autoimmune response against the voltage gated [BLANK] channels on the [BLANK] membrane",
    "answer": "P/Q Ca<sup>2+</sup> / presynaptic",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1360
  },
  {
    "id": 530,
    "question": "In MG MSR are [BLANK] In LEMS MSR are [BLANK]",
    "answer": "normal / abnormal | Context:  MG, LEMS, Botulism (also abnormal in botulism) ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1361
  },
  {
    "id": 531,
    "question": " NMJ disorders muscle biopsy MG [BLANK] of the postjunctional membrane with loss of junctional folds and receptors LEMS [BLANK] of neuromuscular junction with d ecreased active zones ",
    "answer": "Simplification / Overdevelopment | Context:  Postsynaptic membrane changes MG —Simplification of the postsynaptic membrane. The NMJ demonstrates a reduction in the number of postsynaptic junctional folds. LEMS/MS —Hypertrophy of postsynaptic me...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1364
  },
  {
    "id": 532,
    "question": " NMJ disorders EDx findings NCS : SNAP : [BLANK] ^ CMAP : {{c2::normal}} & o/p latency and conduction velocity {{c2::variable (MG: normal)}} * amplitude except in {{c2::LEMS}} ",
    "answer": "normal | Context:  ^ SNAP: sensory nerves do not have a NMJ Occasionally, sensory neuropathies can be associated with a paraneoplastic syndrome seen with LEMS CMAP : & meylin is not injured, thus normal speeds * normal...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1366
  },
  {
    "id": 533,
    "question": " NMJ disorders EDx findings NCS : SNAP : {{c1::normal}} ^ CMAP : [BLANK] & o/p latency and conduction velocity {{c2::variable (MG: normal)}} * amplitude except in [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "normal / LEMS | Context:  ^ SNAP: sensory nerves do not have a NMJ Occasionally, sensory neuropathies can be associated with a paraneoplastic syndrome seen with LEMS CMAP : & meylin is not injured, thus normal speeds * normal...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1366
  },
  {
    "id": 534,
    "question": "NMJ d/o Edx If low CMAP amplitude, should be followed by a [BLANK] [BLANK], followed by a single stimulation. Increased amplitudes >{{c2::100}}% compared with premaximum contraction are seen in LEMS",
    "answer": "10 second / maximum voluntary contraction",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1367
  },
  {
    "id": 535,
    "question": "NMJ d/o Edx If low CMAP amplitude, should be followed by a {{c1::10 second::time}} {{c1::maximum voluntary contraction}}, followed by a single stimulation. Increased amplitudes >[BLANK]% compared with premaximum contraction are seen in LEMS",
    "answer": "100",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1367
  },
  {
    "id": 536,
    "question": " NMJ d/o Edx CMAP amplitude will show > [BLANK] % [BLANK] on low rate rep. stim ",
    "answer": "10 / decrement",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1368
  },
  {
    "id": 537,
    "question": "NMJ disorder Edx findings EMG : Can be normal or abnormal In severe cases, abnormal spontaneous activity can be seen [BLANK], [BLANK] MUAPs with [BLANK] recruitment are associated with {{c2::blocking::SFEMG parameter}} MUAPs become {{c3::unstable}}",
    "answer": "Short-duration / low-amplitude / early | Context:  Unstable MUAP . Same MUAP with varying amplitudes and configurations . seen in patients with myasthenia gravis; amplitude variations are from neuromuscular junction blocking. ...",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1369
  },
  {
    "id": 538,
    "question": "NMJ disorder Edx findings EMG : Can be normal or abnormal In severe cases, abnormal spontaneous activity can be seen {{c1::Short-duration}}, {{c1::low-amplitude}} MUAPs with {{c1::early}} recruitment are associated with [BLANK] MUAPs become {{c3::unstable}}",
    "answer": "blocking | Context:  Unstable MUAP . Same MUAP with varying amplitudes and configurations . seen in patients with myasthenia gravis; amplitude variations are from neuromuscular junction blocking. ...",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1369
  },
  {
    "id": 539,
    "question": "NMJ disorder Edx findings EMG : Can be normal or abnormal In severe cases, abnormal spontaneous activity can be seen {{c1::Short-duration}}, {{c1::low-amplitude}} MUAPs with {{c1::early}} recruitment are associated with {{c2::blocking::SFEMG parameter}} MUAPs become [BLANK]",
    "answer": "unstable | Context:  Unstable MUAP . Same MUAP with varying amplitudes and configurations . seen in patients with myasthenia gravis; amplitude variations are from neuromuscular junction blocking. ...",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1369
  },
  {
    "id": 540,
    "question": "Myesthenia Gravis Treatment [BLANK] {{c2::Anticholinesterase drugs: Pyridostigmine}} Corticosteroids Immunosuppressive agents Plasmapheresis IV Immunoglobulin",
    "answer": "Thymectomy | Context: Mestinon (Pyridostigmine) 30 mg q 4 to 6 hours One-third improve spontaneously Thymectomy can be curative? ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1370
  },
  {
    "id": 541,
    "question": "Lambert Eaton Snydrome treatment Treat [BLANK] {{c3::Immunosuppressives: Corticosteroids, steroid-sparing agents, PLEX, IVIG::category}} {{c2::Guanidine}}: Increases ACh quanta 3,4-diaminopyridine",
    "answer": "malignancy",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1371
  },
  {
    "id": 542,
    "question": "Lambert Eaton Snydrome treatment Treat {{c1::malignancy}} {{c3::Immunosuppressives: Corticosteroids, steroid-sparing agents, PLEX, IVIG::category}} [BLANK]: Increases ACh quanta 3,4-diaminopyridine",
    "answer": "Guanidine",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1371
  },
  {
    "id": 543,
    "question": "Botulism treatment [BLANK] in first {{c2::24}} hours Supportive with intubation for respiratory failure Recovery occurs from collateral sprouting",
    "answer": "trivalent&nbsp;ABE&nbsp;antitoxin | Context:  as far as I know same as botox overdoes, add more ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1372
  },
  {
    "id": 544,
    "question": "Botulism treatment {{c1::trivalent ABE antitoxin}} in first [BLANK] hours Supportive with intubation for respiratory failure Recovery occurs from collateral sprouting",
    "answer": "24 | Context:  as far as I know same as botox overdoes, add more ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1372
  },
  {
    "id": 545,
    "question": "[BLANK]: a fixed deformity of the extremities due to {{c2::intrauterine hypomobility}}",
    "answer": "Arthrogryposis | Context:  multiple joint contractures may occur in newborns from myopathies, muscular dystrophies, or oligohydramnios. A hallmark sign of myopathy is the inability to generate a forceful contraction. ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1373
  },
  {
    "id": 546,
    "question": "{{c1::Arthrogryposis}}: a fixed deformity of the extremities due to [BLANK]",
    "answer": "intrauterine hypomobility | Context:  multiple joint contractures may occur in newborns from myopathies, muscular dystrophies, or oligohydramnios. A hallmark sign of myopathy is the inability to generate a forceful contraction. ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1373
  },
  {
    "id": 547,
    "question": " Myopathy Edx Findings NCS SNAP: [BLANK] ^^ CMAP: [BLANK] amplitude ** [BLANK] latencies and conduction velocities && EMG Classic findings: are {{c3::low amplitude}}, {{c3::short duration}}, {{c3::polyphasic}} MUAP's with {{c3::early}} recruitment Resting activity: {{c2::fibs/sharps}}, {{c2::myotonic discharges}}, {{c2::CRD's (depends on the type of disorder)}} ",
    "answer": "Normal / typically normal, (Decreased in significant atrophy/preferential distal m.'s) / Normal | Context:  ^^ SNAP: sensory fibers ar not affected in myopathy ** CMAP: typically normal as active is over a distal muscle (ie. APB) - recal that myopathies tend to affect proximal muscles. && latencies and con...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1374
  },
  {
    "id": 548,
    "question": " Myopathy Edx Findings NCS SNAP: {{c1::Normal}} ^^ CMAP: {{c1::typically normal, (Decreased in significant atrophy/preferential distal m.'s)}} amplitude ** {{c1::Normal}} latencies and conduction velocities && EMG Classic findings: are [BLANK], [BLANK], [BLANK] MUAP's with [BLANK] recruitment Resting activity: {{c2::fibs/sharps}}, {{c2::myotonic discharges}}, {{c2::CRD's (depends on the type of di",
    "answer": "low amplitude / short duration / polyphasic / early | Context:  ^^ SNAP: sensory fibers ar not affected in myopathy ** CMAP: typically normal as active is over a distal muscle (ie. APB) - recal that myopathies tend to affect proximal muscles. && latencies and con...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1374
  },
  {
    "id": 549,
    "question": " Myopathy Edx Findings NCS SNAP: {{c1::Normal}} ^^ CMAP: {{c1::typically normal, (Decreased in significant atrophy/preferential distal m.'s)}} amplitude ** {{c1::Normal}} latencies and conduction velocities && EMG Classic findings: are {{c3::low amplitude}}, {{c3::short duration}}, {{c3::polyphasic}} MUAP's with {{c3::early}} recruitment Resting activity: [BLANK], [BLANK], [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "fibs/sharps / myotonic discharges / CRD's (depends on the type of disorder) | Context:  ^^ SNAP: sensory fibers ar not affected in myopathy ** CMAP: typically normal as active is over a distal muscle (ie. APB) - recal that myopathies tend to affect proximal muscles. && latencies and con...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1374
  },
  {
    "id": 550,
    "question": " Quantitative EMG provides a more detailed measurement of the MUAPs. It is a better indication of waveform [BLANK], which is a sensitive parameter for diagnosing {{c2::myopathies}}. The mean [BLANK] is calculated using {{c3::20::#}} MUAPs and on a screen set with a trigger and delay line. ",
    "answer": "duration / duration | Context: This avoids superimposing MUAPs and falsely creating a polyphasic....",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1375
  },
  {
    "id": 551,
    "question": " Quantitative EMG provides a more detailed measurement of the MUAPs. It is a better indication of waveform {{c1::duration::same}}, which is a sensitive parameter for diagnosing [BLANK]. The mean {{c1::duration::same}} is calculated using {{c3::20::#}} MUAPs and on a screen set with a trigger and delay line. ",
    "answer": "myopathies | Context: This avoids superimposing MUAPs and falsely creating a polyphasic....",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1375
  },
  {
    "id": 552,
    "question": " Quantitative EMG provides a more detailed measurement of the MUAPs. It is a better indication of waveform {{c1::duration::same}}, which is a sensitive parameter for diagnosing {{c2::myopathies}}. The mean {{c1::duration::same}} is calculated using [BLANK] MUAPs and on a screen set with a trigger and delay line. ",
    "answer": "20 | Context: This avoids superimposing MUAPs and falsely creating a polyphasic....",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1375
  },
  {
    "id": 553,
    "question": " Recruitment: Early Onset With Minimal Effort (myopathies) MUAP presentation short-duration, small amplitude possible cause due to [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "loss of muscle fibers",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1376
  },
  {
    "id": 554,
    "question": " Recruitment: Early Onset With Minimal Effort (myopathies) MUAP presentation long-duration, large amplitude possible cause these polyphasic potentials are due to [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "collateral sprouting",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1377
  },
  {
    "id": 555,
    "question": " Recruitment: Early Onset With Minimal Effort (myopathies) MUAP presentation [BLANK] possible cause variable amplitude potentials are due to {{c2::blocking}} of {{c1:: immature NMJs}} , formed at the beginning of {{c1::collateral sprouting}} ",
    "answer": "Unstable | Context:  Unstable MUP in a patient with ALS. There is increased ''jiggle'' of several components of the MUP, and impulse blocking of the last component. Concentric needle EMG recording with trigger delay line...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1378
  },
  {
    "id": 556,
    "question": " Recruitment: Early Onset With Minimal Effort (myopathies) MUAP presentation {{c3::Unstable}} possible cause variable amplitude potentials are due to [BLANK] of {{c1:: immature NMJs}} , formed at the beginning of {{c1::collateral sprouting}} ",
    "answer": "blocking | Context:  Unstable MUP in a patient with ALS. There is increased ''jiggle'' of several components of the MUP, and impulse blocking of the last component. Concentric needle EMG recording with trigger delay line...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1378
  },
  {
    "id": 557,
    "question": " Recruitment: Early Onset With Minimal Effort (myopathies) MUAP presentation {{c3::Unstable}} possible cause variable amplitude potentials are due to {{c2::blocking}} of {{c1:: immature NMJs}} , formed at the beginning of [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "collateral sprouting | Context:  Unstable MUP in a patient with ALS. There is increased ''jiggle'' of several components of the MUP, and impulse blocking of the last component. Concentric needle EMG recording with trigger delay line...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1378
  },
  {
    "id": 558,
    "question": "Myopathies Single-Fiber EMG (may demonstrate): [BLANK] [BLANK] [BLANK]",
    "answer": "increased jitter / increased fiber density (FD) / increased blocking | Context:  Fiber density (FD; Figure 5–126 ) : This represents the number of single fibers belonging to the same motor unit within the recording radius of the electrode. The FD is determined by dividing the num...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1380
  },
  {
    "id": 559,
    "question": " TYPE I FIBER ATROPHY [BLANK] {{c2::Nemaline rod myopathy}} Fiber type disproportion ",
    "answer": "Myotonic Dystrophy",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1381
  },
  {
    "id": 560,
    "question": " TYPE I FIBER ATROPHY {{c1::Myotonic Dystrophy}} [BLANK] Fiber type disproportion ",
    "answer": "Nemaline rod myopathy",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1381
  },
  {
    "id": 561,
    "question": " TYPE II FIBER ATROPHY [BLANK] {{c2::Myasthenia gravis}} Deconditioning ",
    "answer": "Steroid myopathy",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1382
  },
  {
    "id": 562,
    "question": " TYPE II FIBER ATROPHY {{c1::Steroid myopathy}} [BLANK] Deconditioning ",
    "answer": "Myasthenia gravis",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1382
  },
  {
    "id": 563,
    "question": "FSH , facioscapulohumeral inheritance: [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "autosomal dominant | Context: best muscle to test is tibialis anterior...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1383
  },
  {
    "id": 564,
    "question": " Motor Neuron Disease It is important to rule out treatable neuropathies that mimic motor neuron disease ( MND ). An example of this is [BLANK] , which includes conduction block and temporal dispersion, not seen in MND . ",
    "answer": "multifocal motor neuropathy | Context:  What is multifocal motor neuropathy? a progressive muscle disorder characterized by weakness in the hands, with differences from one side of the body to the other It affects men much more than women....",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1388
  },
  {
    "id": 565,
    "question": " Motor Neuron Disease Edx findings NCS SNAP: [BLANK] ** CMAP: [BLANK]: conduction velocities and onselt/distal latencies ^^ [BLANK]: amplitude && F-wave: {{c2::Abnormal latency}}, {{c2::persistence}} with {{c2::chronodispersion}} ",
    "answer": "normal / typicaly normal / reduced | Context:  this sounds very similar to a radiculopathy ** Abnormal can be seen in hereditary spastic paraplegia and spinobulbar muscular atrophy. - since the Anterior horn cell is affected and the DRG is spared...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1389
  },
  {
    "id": 566,
    "question": " Motor Neuron Disease Edx findings NCS SNAP: {{c1::normal}} ** CMAP: {{c1::typicaly normal}}: conduction velocities and onselt/distal latencies ^^ {{c1::reduced}}: amplitude && F-wave: [BLANK], [BLANK] with [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "Abnormal latency / persistence / chronodispersion | Context:  this sounds very similar to a radiculopathy ** Abnormal can be seen in hereditary spastic paraplegia and spinobulbar muscular atrophy. - since the Anterior horn cell is affected and the DRG is spared...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1389
  },
  {
    "id": 567,
    "question": "Motor Neuron Disease Edx findings EMG Study at least [BLANK] limbs Classic Needle Finding: {{c1::Active denervation with reinnervation::in general}} and {{c1::fasciculations::MUAP morphology}} must be found in {{c2::3}} of {{c4::4 (craniobulbar, cervical, thoracic, and lumbosacral)}} body segments At least {{c3::2}} muscles with different innervations should be abnormal",
    "answer": "3 | Context:  Chronic neurogenic changes (decreased MUP recruitment, large amplitude MUAP, rapidly firing potential) denervation potentials (FIB, PSWs, fasciculations) should be evident. Recruitment is decreased. ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1390
  },
  {
    "id": 568,
    "question": "Motor Neuron Disease Edx findings EMG Study at least {{c5::3}} limbs Classic Needle Finding: [BLANK] and [BLANK] must be found in {{c2::3}} of {{c4::4 (craniobulbar, cervical, thoracic, and lumbosacral)}} body segments At least {{c3::2}} muscles with different innervations should be abnormal",
    "answer": "Active denervation with reinnervation / fasciculations | Context:  Chronic neurogenic changes (decreased MUP recruitment, large amplitude MUAP, rapidly firing potential) denervation potentials (FIB, PSWs, fasciculations) should be evident. Recruitment is decreased. ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1390
  },
  {
    "id": 569,
    "question": "Motor Neuron Disease Edx findings EMG Study at least {{c5::3}} limbs Classic Needle Finding: {{c1::Active denervation with reinnervation::in general}} and {{c1::fasciculations::MUAP morphology}} must be found in [BLANK] of {{c4::4 (craniobulbar, cervical, thoracic, and lumbosacral)}} body segments At least {{c3::2}} muscles with different innervations should be abnormal",
    "answer": "3 | Context:  Chronic neurogenic changes (decreased MUP recruitment, large amplitude MUAP, rapidly firing potential) denervation potentials (FIB, PSWs, fasciculations) should be evident. Recruitment is decreased. ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1390
  },
  {
    "id": 570,
    "question": "Motor Neuron Disease Edx findings EMG Study at least {{c5::3}} limbs Classic Needle Finding: {{c1::Active denervation with reinnervation::in general}} and {{c1::fasciculations::MUAP morphology}} must be found in {{c2::3}} of [BLANK] body segments At least {{c3::2}} muscles with different innervations should be abnormal",
    "answer": "4 (craniobulbar, cervical, thoracic, and lumbosacral) | Context:  Chronic neurogenic changes (decreased MUP recruitment, large amplitude MUAP, rapidly firing potential) denervation potentials (FIB, PSWs, fasciculations) should be evident. Recruitment is decreased. ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1390
  },
  {
    "id": 571,
    "question": "Motor Neuron Disease Edx findings EMG Study at least {{c5::3}} limbs Classic Needle Finding: {{c1::Active denervation with reinnervation::in general}} and {{c1::fasciculations::MUAP morphology}} must be found in {{c2::3}} of {{c4::4 (craniobulbar, cervical, thoracic, and lumbosacral)}} body segments At least [BLANK] muscles with different innervations should be abnormal",
    "answer": "2 | Context:  Chronic neurogenic changes (decreased MUP recruitment, large amplitude MUAP, rapidly firing potential) denervation potentials (FIB, PSWs, fasciculations) should be evident. Recruitment is decreased. ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1390
  },
  {
    "id": 572,
    "question": "CNS disorders Edx Findings In CNS disorders, sensory and motor NCSs are normal. On needle EMG, there is no denervation or reinnervation on the weak limb(s); it reveals normal spontaneous activity and normal MUAP morphology. On voluntary contraction, recruitment is [BLANK]",
    "answer": "normal | Context: On voluntary contraction, however, the interference pattern is not complete due to decreased activation (i.e., decreased firing frequency); the number of available MUAPs (i.e., recruitment) remains no...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1393
  },
  {
    "id": 573,
    "question": "SCI edx findings will EMG be abdnormal: [BLANK]",
    "answer": "yes (at the level of the lesion) | Context: In a segmental spinal cord lesion, muscle innervated below the level of lesion will display the typical pattern of CNS lesion (i.e., decreased activation). At the segmental level of the lesion, anteri...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1394
  },
  {
    "id": 574,
    "question": "paraneoplastic neurologic syndromes (PNS) related cancers small cell lung cancer [BLANK] [BLANK]",
    "answer": "lymphoma / myeloma | Context: paraneoplastic neurologic syndromes (PNS) result from immune cross-reactivity between tumor cells and components of the nervous system. Paraneoplastic Syndrome are detected before cancer is diagnosed ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1395
  },
  {
    "id": 575,
    "question": "Paraneoplastic Syndrome can affect the CNS e.g. {{c1::limbic encephalitis (hippocampus and amygdala) }} and paraneoplastic [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "cerebellar degeneration | Context: can affect... the NMJ (e.g., Lambert–Eaton myasthenia syndrome and myasthenia gravis), the peripheral nervous system (e.g., autonomic neuropathy and subacute sensory neuropathy). The diagnosis of PNS ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1396
  },
  {
    "id": 576,
    "question": "In ALS [BLANK], [BLANK], and [BLANK] are spared",
    "answer": "bowel / bladder / sensation | Context: ie a painless foot drop is concerning cranial nerves for EOM should be normal ie 4 and 6, but may have other (non CN) ocular issues however, there are ALS + syndromes that do not fit the typical prese...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1397
  },
  {
    "id": 577,
    "question": " Repetitive nerve stimulation: These are studies in which a [BLANK] [BLANK] stimulation of a motor nerve is performed. A series of CMAPs are recorded and evaluated for pathologic {{c2::amplitude changes}}. ",
    "answer": "repeated / supramaximal | Context:  Repetitive nerve stimulation: normal response ...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1398
  },
  {
    "id": 578,
    "question": " Repetitive nerve stimulation: These are studies in which a {{c1::repeated}} {{c1::supramaximal}} stimulation of a motor nerve is performed. A series of CMAPs are recorded and evaluated for pathologic [BLANK]. ",
    "answer": "amplitude changes | Context:  Repetitive nerve stimulation: normal response ...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1398
  },
  {
    "id": 579,
    "question": " Repetitive Nerve Stimulation ( RNS) SETUP [BLANK] the electrode [BLANK] the limb Stimulate at a supramaximal level Optimize limb temperature (approximately {{c4::30°C}}) Minimize {{c1::electrode gel}} Stop {{c2::anticholinesterase inhibitors}} Muscles should be evaluated in a {{c3::distal to proximal}} progression (if an abnormality is suspected but not demonstrated) ",
    "answer": "Immobilize / Immobilize | Context:  The study is best performed on the clinically weak muscle(s). However, due to the ease of the examination, it is typically started in the hand intrinsics. If no abnormality is noted, then progression...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1399
  },
  {
    "id": 580,
    "question": " Repetitive Nerve Stimulation ( RNS) SETUP {{c5::Immobilize}} the electrode {{c5::Immobilize}} the limb Stimulate at a supramaximal level Optimize limb temperature (approximately [BLANK]) Minimize {{c1::electrode gel}} Stop {{c2::anticholinesterase inhibitors}} Muscles should be evaluated in a {{c3::distal to proximal}} progression (if an abnormality is suspected but not demonstrated) ",
    "answer": "30°C | Context:  The study is best performed on the clinically weak muscle(s). However, due to the ease of the examination, it is typically started in the hand intrinsics. If no abnormality is noted, then progression...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1399
  },
  {
    "id": 581,
    "question": " Repetitive Nerve Stimulation ( RNS) SETUP {{c5::Immobilize}} the electrode {{c5::Immobilize}} the limb Stimulate at a supramaximal level Optimize limb temperature (approximately {{c4::30°C}}) Minimize [BLANK] Stop {{c2::anticholinesterase inhibitors}} Muscles should be evaluated in a {{c3::distal to proximal}} progression (if an abnormality is suspected but not demonstrated) ",
    "answer": "electrode gel | Context:  The study is best performed on the clinically weak muscle(s). However, due to the ease of the examination, it is typically started in the hand intrinsics. If no abnormality is noted, then progression...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1399
  },
  {
    "id": 582,
    "question": " Repetitive Nerve Stimulation ( RNS) SETUP {{c5::Immobilize}} the electrode {{c5::Immobilize}} the limb Stimulate at a supramaximal level Optimize limb temperature (approximately {{c4::30°C}}) Minimize {{c1::electrode gel}} Stop [BLANK] Muscles should be evaluated in a {{c3::distal to proximal}} progression (if an abnormality is suspected but not demonstrated) ",
    "answer": "anticholinesterase inhibitors | Context:  The study is best performed on the clinically weak muscle(s). However, due to the ease of the examination, it is typically started in the hand intrinsics. If no abnormality is noted, then progression...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1399
  },
  {
    "id": 583,
    "question": " Repetitive Nerve Stimulation ( RNS) SETUP {{c5::Immobilize}} the electrode {{c5::Immobilize}} the limb Stimulate at a supramaximal level Optimize limb temperature (approximately {{c4::30°C}}) Minimize {{c1::electrode gel}} Stop {{c2::anticholinesterase inhibitors}} Muscles should be evaluated in a [BLANK] progression (if an abnormality is suspected but not demonstrated) ",
    "answer": "distal to proximal | Context:  The study is best performed on the clinically weak muscle(s). However, due to the ease of the examination, it is typically started in the hand intrinsics. If no abnormality is noted, then progression...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1399
  },
  {
    "id": 584,
    "question": "Low-Rate Repetitive Stimulation: This repetitive stimulation test is performed at a rate of [BLANK] to [BLANK] Hz Each stimulus causes the {{c2::EPP}} amplitude to drop. If the {{c2::safety factor}} is decreased, the potential will fall below the threshold necessary for activation. This results in a decrease of the {{c3::MUAP}} amplitude",
    "answer": "2 / 3",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1401
  },
  {
    "id": 585,
    "question": "Low-Rate Repetitive Stimulation: This repetitive stimulation test is performed at a rate of {{c1::2}} to {{c1::3}} Hz Each stimulus causes the [BLANK] amplitude to drop. If the [BLANK] is decreased, the potential will fall below the threshold necessary for activation. This results in a decrease of the {{c3::MUAP}} amplitude",
    "answer": "EPP / safety factor",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1401
  },
  {
    "id": 586,
    "question": "Low-Rate Repetitive Stimulation: This repetitive stimulation test is performed at a rate of {{c1::2}} to {{c1::3}} Hz Each stimulus causes the {{c2::EPP}} amplitude to drop. If the {{c2::safety factor}} is decreased, the potential will fall below the threshold necessary for activation. This results in a decrease of the [BLANK] amplitude",
    "answer": "MUAP",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1401
  },
  {
    "id": 587,
    "question": "Low-Rate Repetitive Stimulation: An abnormality is considered when a CMAP demonstrates >[BLANK]% amplitude reduction between the {{c2::1st}} and {{c2::4th}} waveforms An increase in waveform can be seen if more stimulations are provided due to mobilization of {{c3::secondary ACh stores}} A typical {{c4::U-shaped}} decrement can be seen in myasthenia gravis",
    "answer": "10",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1402
  },
  {
    "id": 588,
    "question": "Low-Rate Repetitive Stimulation: An abnormality is considered when a CMAP demonstrates >{{c1::10}}% amplitude reduction between the [BLANK] and [BLANK] waveforms An increase in waveform can be seen if more stimulations are provided due to mobilization of {{c3::secondary ACh stores}} A typical {{c4::U-shaped}} decrement can be seen in myasthenia gravis",
    "answer": "1st / 4th",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1402
  },
  {
    "id": 589,
    "question": "Low-Rate Repetitive Stimulation: An abnormality is considered when a CMAP demonstrates >{{c1::10}}% amplitude reduction between the {{c2::1st}} and {{c2::4th}} waveforms An increase in waveform can be seen if more stimulations are provided due to mobilization of [BLANK] A typical {{c4::U-shaped}} decrement can be seen in myasthenia gravis",
    "answer": "secondary&nbsp;ACh&nbsp;stores",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1402
  },
  {
    "id": 590,
    "question": "Low-Rate Repetitive Stimulation: An abnormality is considered when a CMAP demonstrates >{{c1::10}}% amplitude reduction between the {{c2::1st}} and {{c2::4th}} waveforms An increase in waveform can be seen if more stimulations are provided due to mobilization of {{c3::secondary ACh stores}} A typical [BLANK] decrement can be seen in myasthenia gravis",
    "answer": "U-shaped",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1402
  },
  {
    "id": 591,
    "question": "[BLANK] : After a decrement is noted with LRRS, a 30-60 second {{c2::isometric contraction}} or {{c3::tetany-producing}} stimulation (50 Hz) should be performed. demonstrates a repair in the CMAP amplitude with an immediate follow up LRRS because of an improvement in neuromuscular transmission.",
    "answer": "Postactivation Facilitation (PAF)",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1403
  },
  {
    "id": 592,
    "question": "{{c1::Postactivation Facilitation (PAF)}} : After a decrement is noted with LRRS, a 30-60 second [BLANK] or {{c3::tetany-producing}} stimulation (50 Hz) should be performed. demonstrates a repair in the CMAP amplitude with an immediate follow up LRRS because of an improvement in neuromuscular transmission.",
    "answer": "isometric contraction",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1403
  },
  {
    "id": 593,
    "question": "{{c1::Postactivation Facilitation (PAF)}} : After a decrement is noted with LRRS, a 30-60 second {{c2::isometric contraction}} or [BLANK] stimulation (50 Hz) should be performed. demonstrates a repair in the CMAP amplitude with an immediate follow up LRRS because of an improvement in neuromuscular transmission.",
    "answer": "tetany-producing",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1403
  },
  {
    "id": 594,
    "question": "[BLANK] : This response is seen as a CMAP amplitude decreases. It occurs with a {{c2::LRRS::same}} performed every {{c3::minute}} for {{c3::5 minutes}} after an initial 30-60-second isometric contraction This test should be used if a {{c2::decrement}} is not seen with the initial {{c2::LRRS::same}}, but a diagnosis of a NMJ disorder is suspected",
    "answer": "Postactivation Exhaustion (PAE) | Context:  The greatest drop off is between 2 and 4 minutes. ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1404
  },
  {
    "id": 595,
    "question": "{{c1::Postactivation Exhaustion (PAE)}} : This response is seen as a CMAP amplitude decreases. It occurs with a [BLANK] performed every {{c3::minute}} for {{c3::5 minutes}} after an initial 30-60-second isometric contraction This test should be used if a [BLANK] is not seen with the initial [BLANK], but a diagnosis of a NMJ disorder is suspected",
    "answer": "LRRS / decrement / LRRS | Context:  The greatest drop off is between 2 and 4 minutes. ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1404
  },
  {
    "id": 596,
    "question": "{{c1::Postactivation Exhaustion (PAE)}} : This response is seen as a CMAP amplitude decreases. It occurs with a {{c2::LRRS::same}} performed every [BLANK] for [BLANK] after an initial 30-60-second isometric contraction This test should be used if a {{c2::decrement}} is not seen with the initial {{c2::LRRS::same}}, but a diagnosis of a NMJ disorder is suspected",
    "answer": "minute / 5 minutes | Context:  The greatest drop off is between 2 and 4 minutes. ...",
    "category": "EMG Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "source_line": 1404
  },
  {
    "id": 597,
    "question": "High-Rate Repetitive Stimulation: repetitive stimulation test is performed at a rate of [BLANK] to {{c2::50}} Hz. It causes an accumulation of calcium in the cell, which assists {{c3::ACh release}} and repairs the waveforms typically performed if a patient is unable to perform a {{c4::30- to 60-second::time}} {{c4:: maximal isometric contraction}}",
    "answer": "10 | Context:  High-rate repetitive stimulation. (I) Increment with 50 Hz stimulation. (II) Increment with voluntary contraction (50 Hz simulation/train of 50, femoral/rectus femoris, 500% facilitation). ...",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1405
  },
  {
    "id": 598,
    "question": "High-Rate Repetitive Stimulation: repetitive stimulation test is performed at a rate of {{c1::10}} to [BLANK] Hz. It causes an accumulation of calcium in the cell, which assists {{c3::ACh release}} and repairs the waveforms typically performed if a patient is unable to perform a {{c4::30- to 60-second::time}} {{c4:: maximal isometric contraction}}",
    "answer": "50 | Context:  High-rate repetitive stimulation. (I) Increment with 50 Hz stimulation. (II) Increment with voluntary contraction (50 Hz simulation/train of 50, femoral/rectus femoris, 500% facilitation). ...",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1405
  },
  {
    "id": 599,
    "question": "High-Rate Repetitive Stimulation: repetitive stimulation test is performed at a rate of {{c1::10}} to {{c2::50}} Hz. It causes an accumulation of calcium in the cell, which assists [BLANK] and repairs the waveforms typically performed if a patient is unable to perform a {{c4::30- to 60-second::time}} {{c4:: maximal isometric contraction}}",
    "answer": "ACh&nbsp;release | Context:  High-rate repetitive stimulation. (I) Increment with 50 Hz stimulation. (II) Increment with voluntary contraction (50 Hz simulation/train of 50, femoral/rectus femoris, 500% facilitation). ...",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1405
  },
  {
    "id": 600,
    "question": "High-Rate Repetitive Stimulation: repetitive stimulation test is performed at a rate of {{c1::10}} to {{c2::50}} Hz. It causes an accumulation of calcium in the cell, which assists {{c3::ACh release}} and repairs the waveforms typically performed if a patient is unable to perform a [BLANK] [BLANK]",
    "answer": "30- to 60-second / maximal isometric contraction | Context:  High-rate repetitive stimulation. (I) Increment with 50 Hz stimulation. (II) Increment with voluntary contraction (50 Hz simulation/train of 50, femoral/rectus femoris, 500% facilitation). ...",
    "category": "NCS Principles",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1405
  },
  {
    "id": 601,
    "question": "Pseudofacilitation a normal reaction and demonstrates a progressive increase in [BLANK] with HRRS or voluntary muscle contraction",
    "answer": "CMAP&nbsp;amplitude | Context:  however, the duration will decrease. ths the amplitude is the same ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1407
  },
  {
    "id": 602,
    "question": "Pseudofacilitation It represents a decrease in [BLANK] due to increased {{c2::synchronicity}} of muscle fiber contraction",
    "answer": "temporal dispersion | Context:  The waveforms produced maintain a constant area under the curve though the amplitude appears increased because the duration is decreased ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1408
  },
  {
    "id": 603,
    "question": "Pseudofacilitation It represents a decrease in {{c1::temporal dispersion}} due to increased [BLANK] of muscle fiber contraction",
    "answer": "synchronicity | Context:  The waveforms produced maintain a constant area under the curve though the amplitude appears increased because the duration is decreased ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1408
  },
  {
    "id": 604,
    "question": "Single Fiber EMG This is a study that monitors the parameters of single muscle fiber APs. It is useful if [BLANK] is normal (and an abnormal diagnosis is still suspected)",
    "answer": "repetitive stimulation",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1409
  },
  {
    "id": 605,
    "question": "Single Fiber EMG SFEMG is the most sensitive test for [BLANK] but has low specificity Abnormalities can also be associated with {{c2::motor neuron disorders}}, and {{c2::peripheral neuropathies}}",
    "answer": "NMJ&nbsp;disorders",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1410
  },
  {
    "id": 606,
    "question": "Single Fiber EMG SFEMG is the most sensitive test for {{c1::NMJ disorders}} but has low specificity Abnormalities can also be associated with [BLANK], and [BLANK]",
    "answer": "motor neuron disorders / peripheral neuropathies",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1410
  },
  {
    "id": 607,
    "question": "Single Fiber EMG Paramters Fiber density represents the number of [BLANK] belonging to the same [BLANK] within the recording radius of the electrode A FD of {{c2::1.5::decimal}} is normal. Higher than this represents a {{c3::denervation and reinnervation}} process",
    "answer": "single muscle fibers / motor unit | Context:  The FD is determined by dividing the number of single muscle fiber APs at 20 sites by 20. (A) Normal muscle (action potentials from 1 to 2 fibers recorded). (B) Reinnervation (action potentials from ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1411
  },
  {
    "id": 608,
    "question": "Single Fiber EMG Paramters Fiber density represents the number of {{c1::single muscle fibers}} belonging to the same {{c1::motor unit}} within the recording radius of the electrode A FD of [BLANK] is normal. Higher than this represents a {{c3::denervation and reinnervation}} process",
    "answer": "1.5 | Context:  The FD is determined by dividing the number of single muscle fiber APs at 20 sites by 20. (A) Normal muscle (action potentials from 1 to 2 fibers recorded). (B) Reinnervation (action potentials from ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1411
  },
  {
    "id": 609,
    "question": "Single Fiber EMG Paramters Fiber density represents the number of {{c1::single muscle fibers}} belonging to the same {{c1::motor unit}} within the recording radius of the electrode A FD of {{c2::1.5::decimal}} is normal. Higher than this represents a [BLANK] process",
    "answer": "denervation and reinnervation | Context:  The FD is determined by dividing the number of single muscle fiber APs at 20 sites by 20. (A) Normal muscle (action potentials from 1 to 2 fibers recorded). (B) Reinnervation (action potentials from ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1411
  },
  {
    "id": 610,
    "question": "Single Fiber EMG Paramters [BLANK] : caused by a increased delay in the {{c2::inter-potential}} {{c2::discharges}} of two muscle fibers belonging to the same motor unit (normally 10 to 60 μsec) Disorders of neuromuscular transmission affect the safety factor and cause a delay in the time for an EPP to reach threshold for a muscle fiber AP, Reinnervation through collateral sprouting after a nerve i",
    "answer": "Jitter | Context:  Single-fiber EMG recordings. Top : Superimposed view. Bottom : Rastered view. (A) Normal. (B) Increased jitter. (C) Increased jitter with blocking. ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1412
  },
  {
    "id": 611,
    "question": "Single Fiber EMG Paramters {{c1::Jitter}} : caused by a increased delay in the [BLANK] [BLANK] of two muscle fibers belonging to the same motor unit (normally 10 to 60 μsec) Disorders of neuromuscular transmission affect the safety factor and cause a delay in the time for an EPP to reach threshold for a muscle fiber AP, Reinnervation through collateral sprouting after a nerve injury results in poo",
    "answer": "inter-potential / discharges | Context:  Single-fiber EMG recordings. Top : Superimposed view. Bottom : Rastered view. (A) Normal. (B) Increased jitter. (C) Increased jitter with blocking. ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1412
  },
  {
    "id": 612,
    "question": "Single Fiber EMG parameters [BLANK]: This is an abnormality that occurs when a single muscle fiber AP {{c3::fails to appear}} It occurs if the jitter becomes >{{c2::100}} μsec. It typically resolves in approximately 1 to 3 months, after reinnervation is completed. However, the increased jitter may take approximately 6 months to resolve",
    "answer": "Blocking | Context:  Single-fiber EMG recordings. Top : Superimposed view. Bottom : Rastered view. (A) Normal. (B) Increased jitter. (C) Increased jitter with blocking. ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1413
  },
  {
    "id": 613,
    "question": "Single Fiber EMG parameters {{c1::Blocking}}: This is an abnormality that occurs when a single muscle fiber AP [BLANK] It occurs if the jitter becomes >{{c2::100}} μsec. It typically resolves in approximately 1 to 3 months, after reinnervation is completed. However, the increased jitter may take approximately 6 months to resolve",
    "answer": "fails to appear | Context:  Single-fiber EMG recordings. Top : Superimposed view. Bottom : Rastered view. (A) Normal. (B) Increased jitter. (C) Increased jitter with blocking. ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1413
  },
  {
    "id": 614,
    "question": "Single Fiber EMG parameters {{c1::Blocking}}: This is an abnormality that occurs when a single muscle fiber AP {{c3::fails to appear}} It occurs if the jitter becomes >[BLANK] μsec. It typically resolves in approximately 1 to 3 months, after reinnervation is completed. However, the increased jitter may take approximately 6 months to resolve",
    "answer": "100 | Context:  Single-fiber EMG recordings. Top : Superimposed view. Bottom : Rastered view. (A) Normal. (B) Increased jitter. (C) Increased jitter with blocking. ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1413
  },
  {
    "id": 615,
    "question": "Critical Illness Neuropathy Edx Findings NCS SNAP: [BLANK]: amplitude [BLANK]: CV o/p latency CMAP: [BLANK]: amplitude [BLANK]: CV o/p latency EMG {{c2::Fibs/sharps}} seen in {{c2::distal}} muscles recruitment patter: {{c3::neuropathic (decreased with high frequency)}}",
    "answer": "low/unobtainable / mild slowing / low/unobtainable / mild slowing (primarily axonal) | Context: Sensory Motor Axonal Peripheral Poly Neuropathy predominant axonal process, low amplitudes only mild slowing...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1414
  },
  {
    "id": 616,
    "question": "Critical Illness Neuropathy Edx Findings NCS SNAP: {{c1::low/unobtainable}}: amplitude {{c1::mild slowing}}: CV o/p latency CMAP: {{c1::low/unobtainable}}: amplitude {{c1::mild slowing (primarily axonal)}}: CV o/p latency EMG [BLANK] seen in [BLANK] muscles recruitment patter: {{c3::neuropathic (decreased with high frequency)}}",
    "answer": "Fibs/sharps / distal | Context: Sensory Motor Axonal Peripheral Poly Neuropathy predominant axonal process, low amplitudes only mild slowing...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1414
  },
  {
    "id": 617,
    "question": "Critical Illness Neuropathy Edx Findings NCS SNAP: {{c1::low/unobtainable}}: amplitude {{c1::mild slowing}}: CV o/p latency CMAP: {{c1::low/unobtainable}}: amplitude {{c1::mild slowing (primarily axonal)}}: CV o/p latency EMG {{c2::Fibs/sharps}} seen in {{c2::distal}} muscles recruitment patter: [BLANK]",
    "answer": "neuropathic (decreased with high frequency) | Context: Sensory Motor Axonal Peripheral Poly Neuropathy predominant axonal process, low amplitudes only mild slowing...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1414
  },
  {
    "id": 618,
    "question": "Critical Illness Myopathy Edx Findings in general will present exactly the same as [BLANK]",
    "answer": "myopathies | Context: SNAP: normal, snesory fibers not affected CMAP: normal, typically distal muscles are spared EMG: short duration, low amplitude MUAP with early recruitment spontaneous activity is evident...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1415
  },
  {
    "id": 619,
    "question": "[BLANK]: a means of evaluating the unmyelinated, [BLANK] nerve fibers of the PNS",
    "answer": "Sympathetic skin response / sympathetic | Context: For median nerve testing using standard electrodes, E-1 can be placed on the palm and E-2 on the dorsum of the hand. The median nerve is stimulated at the wrist and elbow at the usual locations. Stimu...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1416
  },
  {
    "id": 620,
    "question": "Sinus arrhythmia study : aka [BLANK] study dependent on the normal {{c2::heart rate variations}} that occur with {{c2::respiration}} via parasympathetic activity test consists of measuring the {{c3::R-R ratio}} with an {{c3::EKG}} machine attached to the amplifier of the EMG.",
    "answer": "cardio-vagal innervation | Context: Loss of this sinus arrhythmia represents a denervation process ...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1417
  },
  {
    "id": 621,
    "question": "Sinus arrhythmia study : aka {{c1::cardio-vagal innervation}} study dependent on the normal [BLANK] that occur with [BLANK] via parasympathetic activity test consists of measuring the {{c3::R-R ratio}} with an {{c3::EKG}} machine attached to the amplifier of the EMG.",
    "answer": "heart rate variations / respiration | Context: Loss of this sinus arrhythmia represents a denervation process ...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1417
  },
  {
    "id": 622,
    "question": "Sinus arrhythmia study : aka {{c1::cardio-vagal innervation}} study dependent on the normal {{c2::heart rate variations}} that occur with {{c2::respiration}} via parasympathetic activity test consists of measuring the [BLANK] with an [BLANK] machine attached to the amplifier of the EMG.",
    "answer": "R-R ratio / EKG | Context: Loss of this sinus arrhythmia represents a denervation process ...",
    "category": "Muscle Testing",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1417
  },
  {
    "id": 623,
    "question": "Anal sphincter activity : EMG recording of the external anal sphincter has [BLANK] activity at rest.",
    "answer": "continuous | Context: There is a brief contraction in response to rapid rectal distension, and a preserved or increased activity during a prolonged substantial rectal distension during defecation in healthy adults....",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1419
  },
  {
    "id": 624,
    "question": "Autonomic Nerve Studies [BLANK] Sympathetic Skin Response Sinus Arryhthmia Valsalva Ratio Anal Sphincter Activity",
    "answer": "Norepinephrine synthesis and&nbsp;release | Context: Norepinephrine is the primary neurotransmitter for postganglionic sympathetic adrenergic nerves. It is synthesized inside the nerve axon, stored within vesicles, then released by the nerve when an AP ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1420
  },
  {
    "id": 625,
    "question": "AIDP clinical presentation sx's worst at [BLANK] after onset {{c1::symmetric::symmetric/asymmetric}} ascending paralysis {{c2::absent reflexes}} {{c4::bulbar (bell's plasy)}} and {{c4::respiratory}} muscle may be affected {{c5::autonomic dysfunction}}",
    "answer": "4 weeks | Context:  sensory symptoms are typically mild pain in 66% Autonomic: tachy, brady, Ortho-stasis, urinary retention, and ileus ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1421
  },
  {
    "id": 626,
    "question": "AIDP clinical presentation sx's worst at {{c3::4 weeks::time}} after onset [BLANK] ascending paralysis {{c2::absent reflexes}} {{c4::bulbar (bell's plasy)}} and {{c4::respiratory}} muscle may be affected {{c5::autonomic dysfunction}}",
    "answer": "symmetric | Context:  sensory symptoms are typically mild pain in 66% Autonomic: tachy, brady, Ortho-stasis, urinary retention, and ileus ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1421
  },
  {
    "id": 627,
    "question": "AIDP clinical presentation sx's worst at {{c3::4 weeks::time}} after onset {{c1::symmetric::symmetric/asymmetric}} ascending paralysis [BLANK] {{c4::bulbar (bell's plasy)}} and {{c4::respiratory}} muscle may be affected {{c5::autonomic dysfunction}}",
    "answer": "absent reflexes | Context:  sensory symptoms are typically mild pain in 66% Autonomic: tachy, brady, Ortho-stasis, urinary retention, and ileus ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1421
  },
  {
    "id": 628,
    "question": "AIDP clinical presentation sx's worst at {{c3::4 weeks::time}} after onset {{c1::symmetric::symmetric/asymmetric}} ascending paralysis {{c2::absent reflexes}} [BLANK] and [BLANK] muscle may be affected {{c5::autonomic dysfunction}}",
    "answer": "bulbar (bell's plasy) / respiratory | Context:  sensory symptoms are typically mild pain in 66% Autonomic: tachy, brady, Ortho-stasis, urinary retention, and ileus ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1421
  },
  {
    "id": 629,
    "question": "AIDP clinical presentation sx's worst at {{c3::4 weeks::time}} after onset {{c1::symmetric::symmetric/asymmetric}} ascending paralysis {{c2::absent reflexes}} {{c4::bulbar (bell's plasy)}} and {{c4::respiratory}} muscle may be affected [BLANK]",
    "answer": "autonomic dysfunction | Context:  sensory symptoms are typically mild pain in 66% Autonomic: tachy, brady, Ortho-stasis, urinary retention, and ileus ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1421
  },
  {
    "id": 630,
    "question": "CIDP can present identical to AIDP CIDP should be considered: If the disease progresses for more than [BLANK] or if [BLANK]",
    "answer": "8 weeks / the patient relapses",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1422
  },
  {
    "id": 631,
    "question": "[BLANK]: a chronic inflammatory neuropathy that presents as an {{c1::assymetric::symetric/assymetric}} {{c1::pure motor::sensory/motor/mixed}} disorder",
    "answer": "Multifocal Motor Neuropathy | Context:  anti-GM antibodes may present like ALS but without UMN signs Multifocal motor neuropathy is a progressive muscle disorder characterized by weakness in the hands, with differences from one side of the...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1423
  },
  {
    "id": 632,
    "question": "{{c2::Multifocal Motor Neuropathy}}: a chronic inflammatory neuropathy that presents as an [BLANK] [BLANK] disorder",
    "answer": "assymetric / pure motor | Context:  anti-GM antibodes may present like ALS but without UMN signs Multifocal motor neuropathy is a progressive muscle disorder characterized by weakness in the hands, with differences from one side of the...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1423
  },
  {
    "id": 633,
    "question": " Firing Rate : This is the number of times a [BLANK]. It is expressed in {{c2::Hz}} and is calculated by dividing {{c3::1,000::#}} by the {{c3::interspike interval (II)}}. take care to look at the units and make sure you are using {{c3::msec}} ",
    "answer": "MUAP&nbsp;fires per second | Context: FR = 1,000/II Firing rate: 1,000/13 = approximately 75. ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1424
  },
  {
    "id": 634,
    "question": " Firing Rate : This is the number of times a {{c1:: MUAP fires per second}}. It is expressed in [BLANK] and is calculated by dividing {{c3::1,000::#}} by the {{c3::interspike interval (II)}}. take care to look at the units and make sure you are using {{c3::msec}} ",
    "answer": "Hz | Context: FR = 1,000/II Firing rate: 1,000/13 = approximately 75. ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1424
  },
  {
    "id": 635,
    "question": " Firing Rate : This is the number of times a {{c1:: MUAP fires per second}}. It is expressed in {{c2::Hz}} and is calculated by dividing [BLANK] by the [BLANK]. take care to look at the units and make sure you are using [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "1,000 / interspike interval (II) / msec | Context: FR = 1,000/II Firing rate: 1,000/13 = approximately 75. ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1424
  },
  {
    "id": 636,
    "question": "[BLANK]: this is defined as the {{c1::Firing Rate}} of the {{c1::1st MUAP}} when {{c1::a 2nd MUAP begins to fire}} Values above normal (20 Hz or below) correlate with a {{c2::neuropathic}} process",
    "answer": "Recruitment frequency (RF) | Context: It is initiated by an increase in the force of a contraction. In this example, it is ~12 Hz, the reciprocal of the recruitment interval, which is 85 ms. 8.5 divisions x 10msec = 85 1000 / 85 = 11.8 ...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1425
  },
  {
    "id": 637,
    "question": "{{c3::Recruitment frequency (RF)}}: this is defined as the [BLANK] of the [BLANK] when [BLANK] Values above normal (20 Hz or below) correlate with a {{c2::neuropathic}} process",
    "answer": "Firing Rate / 1st&nbsp;MUAP / a 2nd&nbsp;MUAP&nbsp;begins to fire | Context: It is initiated by an increase in the force of a contraction. In this example, it is ~12 Hz, the reciprocal of the recruitment interval, which is 85 ms. 8.5 divisions x 10msec = 85 1000 / 85 = 11.8 ...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1425
  },
  {
    "id": 638,
    "question": "{{c3::Recruitment frequency (RF)}}: this is defined as the {{c1::Firing Rate}} of the {{c1::1st MUAP}} when {{c1::a 2nd MUAP begins to fire}} Values above normal (20 Hz or below) correlate with a [BLANK] process",
    "answer": "neuropathic | Context: It is initiated by an increase in the force of a contraction. In this example, it is ~12 Hz, the reciprocal of the recruitment interval, which is 85 ms. 8.5 divisions x 10msec = 85 1000 / 85 = 11.8 ...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1425
  },
  {
    "id": 639,
    "question": "[BLANK]: This is the {{c2::interspike interval (in milliseconds)}} between two discharges of the {{c2::(same) 1st MUAP}} when {{c2::a second MUAP begins to fire}}. It is initiated by an increase in the force of a contraction. Normal is considered approximately {{c3::100}} msec",
    "answer": "Recruitment interval (RI) | Context:  In this example, strip B it is 85 ms 8.5 divisions 8.5 x 10msec = 85 msec ...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1426
  },
  {
    "id": 640,
    "question": "{{c1::Recruitment interval (RI)}}: This is the [BLANK] between two discharges of the [BLANK] when [BLANK]. It is initiated by an increase in the force of a contraction. Normal is considered approximately {{c3::100}} msec",
    "answer": "interspike interval (in milliseconds) / (same)&nbsp;1st MUAP / a second&nbsp;MUAP&nbsp;begins to fire | Context:  In this example, strip B it is 85 ms 8.5 divisions 8.5 x 10msec = 85 msec ...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1426
  },
  {
    "id": 641,
    "question": "{{c1::Recruitment interval (RI)}}: This is the {{c2::interspike interval (in milliseconds)}} between two discharges of the {{c2::(same) 1st MUAP}} when {{c2::a second MUAP begins to fire}}. It is initiated by an increase in the force of a contraction. Normal is considered approximately [BLANK] msec",
    "answer": "100 | Context:  In this example, strip B it is 85 ms 8.5 divisions 8.5 x 10msec = 85 msec ...",
    "category": "Plexus Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Intermediate",
    "source_line": 1426
  },
  {
    "id": 642,
    "question": "Decreased RI (Increased RF) : would be consistent with a [BLANK]",
    "answer": "neuropathic process | Context: A loss of motor units restricts additional motor unit activation to increase contractile force. This causes the first motor unit to fire more rapidly until a second motor unit finally joins in. This s...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1427
  },
  {
    "id": 643,
    "question": "Increased RI (Decreased RF) : is consistent with a [BLANK]",
    "answer": "myopathic process | Context: A loss of muscle fibers causes a second motor unit to join in early to help increase contractile force. This occurs before the first motor unit has the opportunity to increase its firing frequency. Th...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1428
  },
  {
    "id": 644,
    "question": " [BLANK]: This has been used to represent recruitment capabilities, especially when a patient demonstrates difficulty in controlling a contractile force. It is calculated by dividing the {{c1::Firing Rate}} of the {{c1::first MUAP}} by the {{c2::number of different MUAPs on the screen}}. The normal RR is considered < {{c3::10}} ",
    "answer": "Recruitment ratio (RR) | Context: ex. A motor unit firing at 10 Hz when two different MUAPs are viewed on the screen demonstrates an RR of 5. 10 Hz/2 different MUAP = 5. In ex B = 6 1000/85 = ~12 12 / (2 different MUAP's) = 6 ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1429
  },
  {
    "id": 645,
    "question": " {{c4::Recruitment ratio (RR)}}: This has been used to represent recruitment capabilities, especially when a patient demonstrates difficulty in controlling a contractile force. It is calculated by dividing the [BLANK] of the [BLANK] by the {{c2::number of different MUAPs on the screen}}. The normal RR is considered < {{c3::10}} ",
    "answer": "Firing Rate / first&nbsp;MUAP | Context: ex. A motor unit firing at 10 Hz when two different MUAPs are viewed on the screen demonstrates an RR of 5. 10 Hz/2 different MUAP = 5. In ex B = 6 1000/85 = ~12 12 / (2 different MUAP's) = 6 ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1429
  },
  {
    "id": 646,
    "question": " {{c4::Recruitment ratio (RR)}}: This has been used to represent recruitment capabilities, especially when a patient demonstrates difficulty in controlling a contractile force. It is calculated by dividing the {{c1::Firing Rate}} of the {{c1::first MUAP}} by the [BLANK]. The normal RR is considered < {{c3::10}} ",
    "answer": "number of different&nbsp;MUAPs&nbsp;on the screen | Context: ex. A motor unit firing at 10 Hz when two different MUAPs are viewed on the screen demonstrates an RR of 5. 10 Hz/2 different MUAP = 5. In ex B = 6 1000/85 = ~12 12 / (2 different MUAP's) = 6 ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1429
  },
  {
    "id": 647,
    "question": " {{c4::Recruitment ratio (RR)}}: This has been used to represent recruitment capabilities, especially when a patient demonstrates difficulty in controlling a contractile force. It is calculated by dividing the {{c1::Firing Rate}} of the {{c1::first MUAP}} by the {{c2::number of different MUAPs on the screen}}. The normal RR is considered < [BLANK] ",
    "answer": "10 | Context: ex. A motor unit firing at 10 Hz when two different MUAPs are viewed on the screen demonstrates an RR of 5. 10 Hz/2 different MUAP = 5. In ex B = 6 1000/85 = ~12 12 / (2 different MUAP's) = 6 ...",
    "category": "General EMG",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1429
  },
  {
    "id": 648,
    "question": " [BLANK] Patterns This is a qualitative or quantitative description of the sequential appearance of MUAPs. It is the electrical activity recorded from a muscle during {{c1::a maximum voluntary contraction}}. It is composed of {{c2::recruitment}} plus {{c2::activation}}. It can be decreased in {{c3::CNS diseases}} and {{c3::poor patient cooperation (pain, hysteria)}}. ",
    "answer": "Interference | Context:  Activation is the ability of a motor unit to fire faster to produce a greater contractile force and is controlled by a central process. if a patient is asked to generate a force and only a few MUAPs ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1430
  },
  {
    "id": 649,
    "question": " {{c4::Interference}} Patterns This is a qualitative or quantitative description of the sequential appearance of MUAPs. It is the electrical activity recorded from a muscle during [BLANK]. It is composed of {{c2::recruitment}} plus {{c2::activation}}. It can be decreased in {{c3::CNS diseases}} and {{c3::poor patient cooperation (pain, hysteria)}}. ",
    "answer": "a maximum voluntary contraction | Context:  Activation is the ability of a motor unit to fire faster to produce a greater contractile force and is controlled by a central process. if a patient is asked to generate a force and only a few MUAPs ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1430
  },
  {
    "id": 650,
    "question": " {{c4::Interference}} Patterns This is a qualitative or quantitative description of the sequential appearance of MUAPs. It is the electrical activity recorded from a muscle during {{c1::a maximum voluntary contraction}}. It is composed of [BLANK] plus [BLANK]. It can be decreased in {{c3::CNS diseases}} and {{c3::poor patient cooperation (pain, hysteria)}}. ",
    "answer": "recruitment / activation | Context:  Activation is the ability of a motor unit to fire faster to produce a greater contractile force and is controlled by a central process. if a patient is asked to generate a force and only a few MUAPs ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1430
  },
  {
    "id": 651,
    "question": " {{c4::Interference}} Patterns This is a qualitative or quantitative description of the sequential appearance of MUAPs. It is the electrical activity recorded from a muscle during {{c1::a maximum voluntary contraction}}. It is composed of {{c2::recruitment}} plus {{c2::activation}}. It can be decreased in [BLANK] and [BLANK]. ",
    "answer": "CNS&nbsp;diseases / poor patient cooperation (pain,&nbsp;hysteria) | Context:  Activation is the ability of a motor unit to fire faster to produce a greater contractile force and is controlled by a central process. if a patient is asked to generate a force and only a few MUAPs ...",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "Cloze",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "source_line": 1430
  }
]